Chris Goosen: Welcome to the
cloud architects podcast, a
podcast about cloud technology
and the people using it.
Nicolas Blank: The cloud
architects podcast is sponsored
by Kemp technologies. Choose
Kemp to optimize your multi
cloud application deployments
and simplify multi cloud
application management. A single
pane of glass for application
delivery, Kemp provides a 360
degree view of your entire
application environment, and
even third party ADCs. Download
Kemp 360 for free today at
kemptechnologies.com
Chris Goosen: Hello and welcome
to another episode of the cloud
architects podcast. Today we are
in New Zealand of all places.
And I must say the weather out
here is significantly better
than the weather in Sydney where
I've just come from. So I took
the time took the opportunity
here to sit down and we're going
to we're going to record and
talk a little bit about teams.
We don't have on a nick today. I
think Nick is in Singapore
somewhere. Not sure what
Warren's doing. But for those of
you who love Warren's energy,
never fear. We have a guest who
runs at that level right here.
So I think we're gonna we're
gonna make up for it today. So
excited to be sitting down with
Paul and Andrew here to talk
about teams. Guys, you want to
do a quick introduction poll
starting with you.
Paul Bloem: Yeah, absolutely. So
my name is Paul Bloem. I have
been a MVP for the last, what is
going for six years now?
Hopefully, seven soon. I look
after a team that has got sort
of collaboration, teams, Skype
for Business, all the pretty
stuff that gets connected to
that, but more importantly,
these days. I'm focused on
adoption on governance,
compliance and that sort of
thing.
Chris Goosen: Very nice.
Andrew Morpeth: All right. My
name is Andrew. I'm also an MVP
been one also for about six
years I do believe. So I'm, I'm
an ex Skype for Business guy, I
suppose we'll still a little bit
of Skype for Business came from
the office communication server
day. So very much engrossed in
the enterprise voice stuff,
transitioning at the moment into
the Microsoft team's world with
enterprise voice glasses on at
the moment, but sort of working
on all the other stuff that
teams brings to the table.
Chris Goosen: And it brings a
lot to the table. Right? I mean,
I think there's been, it's been
the constant theme for for a
couple of years, at least now,
there's been a lot of talk about
teams and teams and teams that
and, you know, obviously, we
just come from ignite a couple
three months ago now, can you
believe it three months. And
there was a lot of announcements
that ignite and I mean, have you
guys seen anything new since
ignite that that kind of sticks
out to you?
Paul Bloem: Yeah, my favorite.
new functionality is really the
SharePoint view that you get
when you're looking at your
folder structure within teams,
being able to look at the date
and timestamps and being able to
change the views and create
perhaps even my own view I
really liked it. It's Yeah,
Andrew Morpeth: it adds a bit of
complication, but I like it as
well. I like that familiar view
that you get from SharePoint and
there, but more buttons to get
used to, I suppose for some
users, but I think it's a
welcome addition.
Chris Goosen: Okay. Well, very
nice. Yeah. I mean, there's I
think just recently I saw the
there was the read receipts have
kind of made its way as well
which is which is kind of fun
because especially when you're
in a in a situation where you
know, islands mode, you don't
always have to do it's gonna be
Andrew Morpeth: it could be seen
as Big Brother ish. It is
configurable by policy but
again, I like it it's good to
know when someone send your
message. And of course, the
expectation should be sit that
the chat is an instant message,
right? It's not It's not the
expectation is not instant
anymore as it wasn't skype. And
sort of training that out of
people is a hard thing because
we still get those messages of
you know, hi, and then they wait
for a response. Hi, back. And
don't just get to the point and
check I'm not used to that
persistent nature that teams
brings that skype never had.
Chris Goosen: Yeah, yeah, that's
a good point. I think, you know,
read receipts or in any form of
communication is always an
interesting one, right? Because
like me personally, on my phone
on iMessage, I don't have
receipts turned on. Yeah. So you
know, you'll guess if I've read
it or not, but then when I use
WhatsApp, because I use WhatsApp
a lot as well. I like, you know,
the fact the fact that folks can
see that I've, you know, read it
or not. And it helps me when I
can, you know, and I guess maybe
it's just the different types of
people that communicate on
iMessage versus on WhatsApp.
Yeah. Yeah, that's
Andrew Morpeth: right. It
depends what you're trying to
avoid, as far as messages, most
of your contact address list.
And
Paul Bloem: when I'm speaking to
users, I'm always talking about
having some form of a social
contract. And that is just the
nature in which we behave
together. Yeah. So if we know
hey, if you've read a message
then and if I want a response,
because that's a social
contract, then please do
respond. Or whether we're
sharing files or whatever it is
we're doing, there's sort of a
social agreement. As to how
we'll be operating in their
team, and I think that's
essential. Otherwise you do get
that. Hey, are you just ignoring
me? And what's going on?
Chris Goosen: Yep, yep. And it's
hard because sometimes you need
to gather your thoughts on
something, right? And I like to
me, I guess etiquette would
dictate that, like, Hey, give me
a second or Hey, I'm looking
into that for you. I'll get back
to you in a second, right? Just
to give someone a response so
that they know you have
acknowledged the message. I find
that that's something that
doesn't exist all that often in
business anymore, right? There's
this I need this from you. Give
it to me
Andrew Morpeth: situation. And
now now thing everyone wants
everything now these days. Yes,
what we're conditioned for, I
suppose. But, yeah, again, that
comes back to that social
contract. Right. And that's why
the adoption piece is so
important. And unfortunately, it
does get lifted out quite a bit.
And I think that's probably
especially true maybe in our
region, because we're a little
bit she'll be right. You know,
the users will figure it out.
Let's spin the budget on
Technology, you know, the
message I've got is that we can
just turn it all on in the
cloud, we don't have service to
deploy as fireless services cost
in that regard. So that should
be transition to watering and
feeding your users and keeping
them up to speed and making sure
they understand the tick,
because it's changing so
quickly, that it's really hard
for anyone to keep up with even
even myself, right. I mean, I
can I struggle to keep up and
I'm dealing with a single
product.
Paul Bloem: Yeah, yeah. I
couldn't agree more. And
unfortunately, organizations are
looking at the technology and
going, we can deploy this at a
much cheaper cost. Let's save
their budget. Yeah. But the real
challenge is that traditionally,
folks haven't measured success
in the way you would think they
would. They'd measure success
based on does the technology
work? Check. It works. Does it
do what it said on the label?
Yes, yes. But what they never
measure is are people using it?
Are they circumventing it? Yeah.
Is it actually being adopted and
used? Are you actually getting
value for money for your
investment? Yep. Or is it just a
white elephant you've just paid
for an off the wall. You've
saved. So we've, you know,
Chris Goosen: we've had some
great conversations on this show
about adoption and the
difference between adoption and
consumption, right? And why it's
really important to measure the
value that comes out of adopting
something as opposed to, well,
you know, we have someone log
into it once every six months,
and so therefore, the license is
justified. So that's, I mean,
it's interesting, and I think
it's a very, it can be a very
deep topic of conversation just
by itself. But what are you guys
seeing as far as team's
adoption, right? Because if you
listen to Microsoft and the
Microsoft message, right,
obviously, there's a lot of
investment going on in teams,
the team's product group are
doing a lot to promote and
market the product. Are you
seeing people adopting?
Andrew Morpeth: Yeah, hundred
percent. I mean, most of the
customers I think we touch have
already deployed teams to some
capacity. So you know, Microsoft
wants seats turned on and that's
what they're pushing, right. But
the most of the customers were
saying they've already turned
the stuff on. They just need
help to do bits. They don't
quite understand it in
enterprise voice is a key one,
because it is still reasonably
technical. So that element we
get pulled into a lot, I guess
the SharePoint aspect of it and
the document management stuff is
a complex problem a lot of
organizations have, they might
have things in Dropbox and
various other storage solutions
or partially or, you know, not
properly deployed SharePoint, I
need help in that regard. Those
would be the two key things do
you think?
Paul Bloem: Well? Yeah,
absolutely. Absolutely. We're
seeing a lot of organizer
because we've got quite a long,
rich history in the Skype for
business world. What we're
seeing is a lot of
organizations, existing
customers, and some new who are
going we're on Skype for
Business want to go to teams.
And the challenge I'm seeing is
I'm going to them and I'm going
well, if you want to go apples
for apples, because that's what
they say to me. Can you show us
compete and so you can't because
Skype is an apple, but teams is
a fruit salad. Yes, there's some
apple in there. Yeah, but
there's a hell of a lot of other
stuff in there, you know. And so
it's often my point of
reference, just trying to bring
them on board and show them the
teams is actually a portal
through which you access many
other things including a slice
of Apple
Chris Goosen: Yep, fair enough.
That's very well said. I think
we might use that future.
Andrew Morpeth: I'm gonna adopt
that too. I've heard it many
times but haven't adopted into
my own vocab yet.
Chris Goosen: Do you think
there's a difference to or in
the way? adoption is happening
in like here in New Zealand or
in the APAC region, for example
versus North American, the rest
of the world?
Paul Bloem: It's a it's a good
question. We don't have the
visibility we have what's
happening elsewhere is through
our, you know, our connection
through the MVP program and that
sort of thing. What what I'm
seeing and I'm sure Andrew,
you're probably on the same
page. A lot of organizations is
kind of two, two parts to it.
There are those who are really
keen to jump in and get it done
and who are happy to see the
limitations or see the
challenges and find ways around
them. Because you've highlighted
them upfront and then there are
others who go I'll just sit back
and hold until you tell me it's
all good. And that's kind of the
two views when they're coming
from sort of a Skype well then
they are including Andrew
specialty enterprise voice
Andrew Morpeth: If I was to take
a guess I think it comes down to
size of organization as to
whether and how much time that
they'll spend on adoption. And
in the New Zealand region, I
guess the the typical business
size is probably under 100
seats, right, we get the odd,
you know, hundred 500 seats,
thousand, you know, four or
5000s getting pretty big, you
know, biggest company in this
entire country is about 35,000
seats run. So I think it
probably comes down to that. So
my expectation would be sort of
North America excetera a lot, a
lot more bigger companies, they
would probably spend a lot more
money on that stuff. They got a
lot more people to address. How
did it get the information
across versus say, 100 seat
organization, it's a lot easier
for the IT department to just do
that they kind of personally
know the users.
Paul Bloem: You know, it's a bit
easier. Yeah. What we're having
to come up with ways to
introduce adoption concepts and
principles in bite sized chunks
getting back to my food analogy,
because no one's got the funding
divvied up the whole bowl,
right? Yep. So we've got to give
them a little spoon feed chunks
as they need to I think
Chris Goosen: that's absolutely
fascinating. I mean, I had not
considered that that the market
size is, you know, the average
company size is going to be
smaller. And so the way that you
when you're in a smaller
business, there is more of a
familiarity of you know, people
know each other people know the
IT people. And so I think you do
deal with training and adoption
slightly differently to, you
know, when your hundred thousand
seat company and the IT guy
doesn't know, you're just a
name, or an email address to
them, right. They don't know
each other. No one knows each
other.
Paul Bloem: Yeah, absolutely.
And then, of course, when you're
looking at the adoption, sort of
the, the portfolio of skills you
need, you know, there's all
these different roles that when
you look at the Microsoft
framework, there's all these
different people you've got in
there. You come down to New
Zealand, and what do you find?
Well, your admin are all things
to all people within that space.
Yeah. And so you know, it is
what it is, and you just got to
go with it.
Chris Goosen: Yeah, fair enough.
And so, with that, I mean, I
guess if we look at the types of
companies around here are you
seeing One of the things we've
seen a lot of over the last six
or seven months, maybe nine
months is tenant to tenant type
migrations, m&a type situations,
right? And we had for a long
time we, that process was pretty
well understood and was pretty
well, we had it down. We knew,
with the workloads that most
companies adopted, we could do
those types of projects pretty
easily with some tool sets and
things like that. But with teams
in the mix, and because of
people adopting teams, it's
inevitable that every tenant now
has some form of team stuff.
Right. And, you know, just
recently, I was working with a
customer where they, you know,
they had kind of sold off a part
of their business divested a
part of their business, and they
had two and a half thousand
teams. And and the new business
was only taking like 500 of
those two and a half thousand
teams. And it became I mean, it
was, it was very interesting.
Yeah, yeah, I got to know the
graph API. That's an I I
probably would have ever wanted
to drop it. That project. But I
mean, it was fun, though, but it
is very complex.
Paul Bloem: Yeah, that the tools
for that sort of tenant tenant
migrations there. Yeah, I guess
I mean, they hardly existing.
Right. They're they're pretty,
pretty juvenile at best. And so
a lot of that comes down to the
skill sets of the resources
using,
Andrew Morpeth: and that can be
a creative challenge. And
Chris Goosen: it definitely, you
know, I think that the point
there, or at least to me, is
it's arguable whether the
investment in because let's be
honest, you can do anything. If
you put your mind to it. We have
PowerShell we have automation
things at the end, we can
eventually we can get there,
right? Oh, you want to migrate
conversation history? Well,
there's no real API for that,
but we could probably get it
done. I know Lee Ford. MVP out
of the UK has a fantastic script
and does some stuff. And you
know, I used his stuff a lot in
the past or at least on that
project. I owe you a beer there
Lee we'll see each other at
summit. I'm buying the first
round.
Andrew Morpeth: About a second
Yeah.
Chris Goosen: But you've got to
get to a point at some point
where you go, well, the resource
costs associated with coming up
with these include g bomb Grant
Solutions isn't worth the reward
of Yeah, getting the stuff.
Absolutely.
Paul Bloem: You've got to, and
we had a discussion about that
earlier today. Sometimes you've
got the sort of idea of
perfection on a plan of where
you got to go. And then there's
the budget. Yep. So you got to
kind of draw a line in the sand
and go, look, we can give you
that perfect outcome that you
want, but it's gonna cost you a
hell of a lot of money. So what
are you comfortable with paying?
Yeah, how much can we deliver
for that? And you've got to set
that expectation right from the
beginning. And it gives you a
bit of leeway to deliver
accordingly.
Chris Goosen: Yeah. And I think
that's, that's the important
part. That's our job as
technologists, right, is to be
upfront with our customers and
actually advise them to that,
right. I think Unfortunately,
there's this sort of sense
lately of people just becoming
button clickers, right, instead
of actually being advisors or
consultants to to the customers
because you know, it's so much
cheaper to do it. Project 100%
remote that it is yeah, to go
and stand there talking to your
customer. But when you're
actually spending the time with
them, you can actually then have
types these types of
conversations and actually
deliver significant more value
than just Next. Next Next thing
through that
Andrew Morpeth: person is so
important. Yeah, video
conferencing to a degree. Yeah.
You need to get to know people
and have candid conversations.
And yeah, at least initially,
you need to have those in
person, I still think there's
still merit in that.
Paul Bloem: We're still old
school that way within our team.
Any project that we kick off, we
always insist on you know,
initially at very least getting
them eye to eye contact. Our
body language, customer's body
language, you basically install
confidence, and you help them to
appreciate that, hey, these guys
know what they're doing and
they're here to help me. And of
course between Andrew and I were
always waiting for that first
project in Fiji but it hasn't
happened
Andrew Morpeth: yet, or any
other island nation.
Chris Goosen: So tell me about
and I think you might be the
best Andrew might be the most
positive sort of work. So the
islands mode trap is something
that I've, we've seen a lot of
Andrew Morpeth: Yep. Yeah, I've
heard that term I coined I
haven't quite used it myself,
but it's certainly a problem.
You know, Microsoft obviously
want adoption of teams. And for
them islands makes sense because
it means by default, generally
speaking, if you're a three,
five, you know, one of those
plans you get, it's going to
just be turned on unless the
admins have done something to
circumvent that, right. You just
get it. So if someone starts
using it, since an IM chat, I
should call up to someone or
some sort of message, it will
get to the other participant and
they can kind of join and it's
there. The problem I find with
it is it causes interrupt issues
because in Ireland's as the name
suggests, both Skype for
Business if you're using that as
very separate teams and they run
independently of each other. And
with Ireland's being the
default. You really need your
customers to understand that
they need to drive adoption away
from Skype entities. teams and
make sure everyone's aware of
it. Because things that can
happen. For example, as I seen
Paul a chat message, right? He
doesn't know what teams is he's
never used it because his
company hasn't announced that it
exists. It's just turned on. And
he's found it. I found it. And
I've sent him a chat message.
Yes, he'll get an email
notification, say someone's
trying to get you in teams. But
he's never heard of his Oh, was
this team's thing throws it in
this junk email, right. So
creates a poor experience for
the users that who are using it.
And the ones because of the ones
that aren't interested in kind
of self learning it. So that's
where the problem is. So what
you really want in my view, is
you want to make a call up
front, you want to decide what
platform you're going to use,
and sit that mode accordingly.
For one by doing that, it
ensures that the interrupt
works. We get a lot of customers
saying it doesn't work. And it's
not that it doesn't work. It's
that probably you're in islands
mode, or probably you don't
quite understand what the modes
actually mean. So in the very
basic sense of it, there's a
Skype only mode which centrally,
your teams is disabled, and you
only use Skype. And then at the
other end of the scale, there's
a team's only mode where you
don't use Skype anymore. And you
you fully transition to teams.
There's modes in the middle that
let you transition features
across, for example, there's a
Skype with teams meeting mode,
right. And those modes
essentially will allow you to
present to the user what they
should be using and what client
and if you have half your user
base on Skype, and half on
teams, it guarantees the
interrupt based on the modes
that each of your users are on.
So if I'm in Skype, and I send a
chat message to someone who is
in teams, I don't need to know
that they're in teams. By
setting those policies correctly
for each user. Microsoft will
make sure that that happens,
right. And and largely this
works. This works well. And it
works for even for Skype hybrid
server deployments. So yes, I
think it probably is a trap.
That's probably not the best
default. I understand why
Microsoft have done it. But
it's, you know, it's up to you
IT admins out there, too. Get
across it and make sure you
deploy the mode that suits you
and understand what it means.
Chris Goosen: Yeah, I think so.
But really bottom line here is
it can be really confusing to
the end user when when email
messages flying around. And
yeah, you know, and I saw this,
you know, internally, we we
weren't on as much for a long
time. And, you know, I was on
teams only because I was one of
the tests guinea pigs, right.
But then like, my manager, for
example, would not be and so I'm
trying to, I am aiming from
teams, two teams, but you know,
his presence is away because
he's not even looking at the
team's client. He's using Skype
for everything. So I ended up
having two contacts for him one
that has the Skype icon next to
it. One that doesn't it. Like
for me, that's confusing. Can
you imagine for like an end user
who has no idea what's going on
here? It's
Paul Bloem: a shame because the
technology we're talking about
is designed to connect people.
Yes. Forget it. We're in a
situation where we're
disconnecting. Yes, yeah.
Chris Goosen: Yeah. So I think
really important to spend the
time here thinking about not
only like, how will you want
What the best user experience is
going to be for your situation.
But also, make sure the timeline
is understood because it can be
very easy trap to fall into
forgive the pun, to, okay, we're
going to enable this, it's going
to coexist. So we don't need to
worry about accelerating the
deployment, because, hey, it's
going to work right. You know,
it's kind of like a, like a
hybrid deployment. You know,
there are a lot of folks in the
exchange water use hybrid as a
long term coexistence mode,
right, which is, which is fine
and in, it certainly works for
that. But you don't want to be
doing that with this. You kind
of want to use it to make sure
that you're transitioning
correctly, but get the
transaction done as quickly as
you can. Yeah,
Paul Bloem: it's got to be a
driver.
Andrew Morpeth: Yeah,
absolutely. Yeah. Once customers
understand what it means it's
actually a reasonably easy
decision to take to the business
and say, Look, we need to make
this decision, what's it going
to be? And then what I mean, the
easiest thing to do and if
people had people have done that
out the out front, right, or if
Microsoft had made Skype only
the default because everyone was
on Skype or You know, something
like that. And then he forced
the admins to make the decision,
it probably would have created a
bitter experience, because
people would have had to go and
turn things on and really
understand what it meant. And I
personally don't like the
default. But
Paul Bloem: yeah, I'll back you
up on that. I totally agree. I
don't like the idea of having
dual apps with overlapping
features. It confuses people.
But as soon as you change those
modes to something else, you're
taking something away and if you
ever want to annoy users take
something away so it leaves you
in a in a nasty place which I
guess is a good thing for us
since it's how we make our bread
Andrew Morpeth: well one thing I
find amusing is that that is
completely the opposite in the
personal world, like people run
around with WhatsApp iMessage
everything on their phones they
got no problem switching between
them for you know different
chats but when it comes to
enterprise Yep, it kind of has
to be run by the business that
you work for otherwise they
disinterested in it for what are
Chris Goosen: we also we're at a
point now where things are so
like the always on on by default
is Such a thing now, right? Like
if you I think the the team's
app is now being deployed with,
with Office. Yeah. So to kind of
get away from it, and you know,
I, my wife, I often use my
wife's company organization as a
great kind of example of a lot
of things because they, you
know, they use the whole gamut
of technologies. They use
Google, they use WebEx stuff.
And I know the other day, I was
looking at a laptop for
something, I was helping you out
with something. And I was like,
Hey, you have teams, and she was
like, oh, let's just got
installed the other day. I don't
know what that's for. Yeah,
exactly. So it's kind of just,
uh, you know, you, you just, I
mean, it's a great example of
actually being able to, you
know, communicate to your users
when changes coming. But also,
there's so much overlap between
so many different things and
different vendors are doing same
things. And you know, why on
earth the WebEx folks called
their product teams as well.
It's just beyond me like it
just,
Andrew Morpeth: you know, mix it
up some more.
Chris Goosen: But let's not
scratch open that wound right
now. So, okay, so let's, let's
talk a little bit about, I
guess, direct routing and the
voice side of things.
Andrew Morpeth: Okay. So for
those that don't know direct
routing is essentially a bring
your own SIP trunk to Microsoft
Teams. It's a it's an over the
internet encrypt encrypted SIP
trunk between your session
border controller or SBC to the
Microsoft Teams edge. There's
various ways you can deploy it.
So you can use a supported or
certified SBC. So there's the
likes of ribbon audiocodes. And
there's a few other ones Oracle
and I'm trying to rattle them
off off the top of my head hear
this, but the other way you can
do that is it's opened the doors
for telcos to start offering the
service as well. So they're
building out their SBC platforms
to support direct routing and
then offering SIP trunks
directly to teams on your behalf
right at little to no more
additional costs as what we're
seeing in the market here. So
you know, it might be $1 $2 more
for a SIP trunk as opposed to
Something delivered on premise
that you'd have to hook up to
your own SBC. They take away the
headache. And that makes sense
for a lot of customers who are
trying to get everything off
Prem, move everything to cloud.
They've already got a telco
relationship, that telco offers
the service. They just turn it
on, migrate the numbers across,
and you're done. There's still
some merit. I think in having an
SBC. I like it. When customers
choose the SBC option selfishly
probably because it gives me a
inbetween vantage point to see
where things are going wrong if
they're going wrong. It also
lets me do things like
manipulate numbers and and, you
know, do some diverting and
different things like that
that's not quite there in the
team's Admin Center at the
moment or available as a
feature, right. So the SBC gives
you some additional capability
that you wouldn't have if you go
for a run of the mill hosted
solution. So those are the two
options we have in our market
and there's obviously the
Microsoft calling plans, but
they're only in sort of 11 1213
countries off the top of my
head. Were you just buying the
minutes directly of Microsoft.
Chris Goosen: Yeah. How what
would you say would be the
percentage of folks who
organizations who already have
an SBC that that they just
essentially using what they have
versus new purchases? Yeah,
Andrew Morpeth: a lot of our
customers because we've been
just hitting the sand with Skype
for Business for so long so many
years. You know, all the
customers we deal with a pretty
well I'd say 95% of our Skype
customers are enterprise voice
enabled which means they have
SBCs a lot of those SBCs have
always been Microsoft Certified
so therefore they can be
firmware upgraded to support the
team's journey. So yeah, most of
our customers who have Scott
definitely will have an SBC if
they don't, you know, you can
buy one you can go for the
hosted service. These are all
supported virtualized now. So
you know, you can get pick one
up for a few hundred bucks. It's
a reasonably cheap entry point.
Yeah. If you want to host it. We
have
Paul Bloem: we have a split with
several organizations and
there's a number I'm working
with at the moment who are
trying to be resilient
geographically to, you know,
disasters and that sort of
thing. But a lot of them have
components that don't
traditionally work with sort of
a hosted or cloud based SBC so
that they might have some
elevator phones, they might have
some Nish contact center that
doesn't talk to teams. And so
we'll use the session border
controller as a voice gateway or
router, right, that allows you
to intercept and interoperate
these different platforms. fair
to say those are massively more
complex in terms of deployment,
and looking after and so on. And
that I guess it's fair to say
that's our Kung Fu, we may get
some good margin of that. We
know that space very well. And
those who have gone down that
path have made their choice
knowingly because of
constraints, functions,
features, that sort of thing
that's not available in the
Skype or even team's world.
Andrew Morpeth: Yeah, that's
right. But the key the key
things we use SBCs for if we
have access to them ourselves,
number one, and ELA and
allocated numbers. There's no
reason way to handle that in
teams right now. So in the SBC,
I can I can see that teams
doesn't know what that number
is. And then I can basically do
a reroute and maybe rewrite that
as the reception queue or
something like that and send the
number elsewhere. It's probably
one of the key things that we
use it for. And also just
general number manipulations,
which, as far as I can tell,
I've seen, I've seen some stuff
surface in the PowerShell.
Properties, but I don't believe
they're accessible to be seen
just yet. But there are some
translation capabilities that I
think are going to be surfaced
in teams soon. So that will
negate some of us. But that's
probably the key thing that we
enjoy having an SBC for, on top
of bit, the trace, the
traceability being able to see
what what is Microsoft saying,
what are the telco say? Yep. And
where should I focus my efforts
to find the problem versus don't
have an SBC I need to look in
the Microsoft portal, try and
gather as much information I can
from the logging, which is not
as detailed as traces and go
from there. And then Maybe I've
got to engage the telco because
its their problem so, it takes a
little bit longer yes on an SBC
trace, we can figure out exactly
what's going on straightaway.
Yeah,
Chris Goosen: I can see how that
would be beneficial and how
potentially having some third
party doing the sort of cloud
SBC situation would would cause
a situation of people pointing
fingers at each other, right?
Yeah. But then but then you also
have a few you know, if you
really want to keep it very
simple and you potentially a
smaller organization, you could
just buy the minutes if you're
in a supportive market, you
could just buy the minutes from
Microsoft and distribute it all.
Then you have the one throat to
choke as they say, Well, yeah,
it's all Microsoft Microsoft
thing that exact Okay,
Andrew Morpeth: so there's
plenty options. It just comes
down to your your preference,
okay, we just normally talk it
through with the customer.
totally up to them. We don't we
don't push any particular way of
doing it down their throat. It's
Yeah, we
Paul Bloem: don't we don't have
a preferred service or anything
like it will be. We basically go
pros and cons. What's the
customer's current relationships
with with whoever they're
dealing with, and then we try
and work with them to find some
short yet
Chris Goosen: And how about I
mean, are you seeing a lot of
customers replacing their
traditional PBX systems with
with teams? And do you think
teams is ready for that? Is it
really?
Andrew Morpeth: It's a hard one
to answer. It's not quite there.
Really. It's at the tipping
point, I think so where it will
suit a customer as well. You've
got simple requirements. Okay.
So we're we're mostly seeing
people take the plunge to
enterprise voice and teams, is
professional services type
industries, because they don't
have super complex requirements.
This generally people like us,
lawyers, accountants, those
sorts of people who are making
and receiving calls directly to
them. And they might have a
receptionist or to receptionist
or something like that simple
call flow coming in, distributes
calls, that that works pretty
well. But there's still
limitations even in that right.
The call queues are getting
pretty good. Some of the
features of the call queues
getting better than Skype, some
aren't quite as mature. The
biggest ones that we come up
against that a well worth noting
is, by default from a queue, you
can't fold out to a PSTN number,
you know, it's quite a common
requirement, maybe an uncle tick
or something you need to go
directly out. So, workaround,
you need a dummy user account
that's fully licensed, you know,
so you kind of have to create
your own creative ways of doing
things. Another one that we that
impacts us, I think it's more of
an APAC issue. Not a global
issue from other people I've
talked to is that there's
significant call queue delay. So
when you answer a call queue
call, you can I've seen up to
eight seconds before you get
audio right. Wow, that's a
pretty disjointed experience for
the agent trying to answer calls
right, where they're going to
sit there and wait for the the
audio to kick in. So that's
problematic. And we've we've had
to for some customers who don't
think that's acceptable, and I
don't think that's acceptable
personally, some customers live
with it. But for customers that
don't want to live with it,
we've had to use again, dummy
user accounts using the core
group capability of a user
endpoint tops it out, right? So
we create a core group in the
user config and distribute calls
that way. Again, another
creative way of doing things to
work around some immaturities in
the product. So, you know, if,
if you're going to move
enterprise voice to teams, my
general messages, you've got to
be willing to deal with some
rough edges. I wouldn't call it
bleeding edge anymore, but it's
kind of just come out of the
bleeding edge. And it's for the
early majority, certainly who
are willing and able and
prepared to be kind of flexible
and you know, working around how
they might have expected it to
work versus the realities of it.
So you really need to make sure
you understand how enterprise
voice works and compare feature
for feature for you know, what
you've got and what you've come
from and determine what you're
prepared to give up them to get
to teams at this enterprise
voice for at this early stage.
Yeah, but enterprise voice is
not what Microsoft's really
pushing as a it's really the
collaboration So that stuff's
gonna mature, they're moving it
from the Skype online world it's
getting there. It's, it's, I've
always said probably by the end
of this year, we'll probably be
at the point where Man, these
features are actually probably
better than Skype. Now a lot of
them are already kind of better.
I like the auto attendance
better the text to speech,
there's a lot of stuff that's
better is just some stuff that's
just not quite there
Paul Bloem: It needs a bit of
time to mature. So a lot of
businesses are not quite ready
to take the plant. They want to
see it prove itself and you who
can blame them? Yeah. But for
me, the real shining star in the
team space when you're coming
from a Skype for business
background is the meeting space.
I absolutely love the meeting
space. It's one of my favorite
things to talk about it being
able to see and there's some
really cool things coming that
just can't wait to get my hands
on and just having a look at
Skype versus a team's meeting.
It kind of feels a little 80s.
Yeah.
Andrew Morpeth: I mean, yeah,
hasn't changed much past what it
was a messenger you know, it's
all that same sort of format, it
looks nice bit nicer. But it's
sort of that messenger. It's
very old school instant message.
And I say, teams is definitely
the new thing and the way
forward and just jumping back to
modes, right? This is where you
can use Mosier advantage if
you're a Skype customer and
you're an enterprise voice in
teams isn't ready for you've
checked it out, you can still
enable your users as Skype for
Business with teams
collaboration and meetings. So
that lights up meetings and
teams and you've got the
collaboration stuff, which Skype
arguably doesn't work that
either doesn't do and meetings,
probably not as good. You can
light that up in teams, but
still ensure that the enterprise
voice features are still in
teams. And so sorry. Yeah, yeah.
Chris Goosen: Yeah, that's
actually a good point. Um, I you
know, I think we're seeing rapid
development on this though,
right? It's not like Microsoft
were promising or making
promises a year ago that they
still making today
Andrew Morpeth: or we're still
delivering stuff. Yeah. Which
which, but Skype didn't really
change too much over the last. I
mean between 2013 and 20. 15
versions? I mean, yeah, there
were a few sort of small
additions, but it hasn't
fundamentally changed for quite
a long time. Whereas teams is
new and exciting. And it's
certainly the way forward and
and it's, I think meeting the
needs of the modern kind of
information work a much better
than Skype does or ever will.
Because, you know, Skype's, I
guess, at the start of at sunset
and a lot of ways, right, it's
still a valid product, we still
recommend it where it makes
sense. And the great thing about
choosing Scott is that you have
a way to get to teams, it's you
can have, you can still deploy
Skype and have some users on
teams, you can have some of your
users using teams made, you
know, you've got the best of
both worlds if you go that way.
And yeah, still completely valid
solution, completely valid
solution, but it is it's kind of
where the PBX was 15 years ago
when Skype and these UC platform
started coming out. PB x's are
still around, but they're sort
of kind of the almost did now.
Right. Scott's gonna be around
for 510 years, I'd say, you
know, before it disappears.
Paul Bloem: Yeah, no, I
absolutely agree. It's been
incredible. I come from a PBX
background, he used to work for
Siemens, and the the mentality
there was delivering services in
a way that they could address
what they perceive as problems,
like, you know, pick up groups
and hunt groups and all this
sort of thing. And I always say
that, you know, with Skype, and
also with teams, the notion is
different. I always argue with,
you know, when I'm doing
training sessions with users
always tell them that when, when
I'm trying to reach you, who
knows best how to get hold of
you, me, or you, will you do you
know, whether you're on the run
or whether you're at home or
whether you're in a hotel, so I
shouldn't change my behavior of
reaching you, you control how
that's delivered. And that's
fundamentally how it's changed
the way people communicate. It's
been brilliant. But the scary
bit is it's developing so fast,
and that's scary, but it's also
very exciting. And very often,
and we might have to take a time
check right now because this
might be invalid by the time I
get to the end of the sentence,
current state of features is
evolving so fast that sometimes
I'm busy showing somebody
something and then I find that
it's changed.
Chris Goosen: Well, we will run
into that problem every now and
then right away. The best is
when you're in the Admin Center
trying to do a demo of something
that the customer has asked,
then you can't find where it is.
You're like, I saw this was here
just yesterday. And they're
like, yeah, sure, it was. Yeah.
And this is because the UI moves
something just a little bit
around. So that's it. I mean,
it's it's a problem. Right. But
I guess it's part of the
challenge we have is just going
to stay on top of that. And so I
mean, we, we talked about, I
guess, teams being a fairly, you
know, fruit salad versus just an
apple. Right. But, I mean, I
guess one of the questions that
a lot of folks probably
listening to this or watching
this have is how is their
skillset relevant in the new
teams world, right, because I
think, to me right now, there's
no such thing as a team's SME
because teams is made up of so
many different pieces, hit the
fruit salad That it depends on
your background and where you
come from.
Paul Bloem: Absolutely. It's,
it's at this early stage, there
are not a lot of people on the
planet who have got a handle
across, even 80% of the
underlying bits of technology.
And, and we're finding that you
know, So traditionally coming
from a voice background and
having lots of Skype for
Business, and now transitioning
into the governance and
compliance areas and all the
adoption stuff. When you look at
that whole spectrum, you do need
different skill sets across so
you there is you're dead, right?
There is no such thing as one
person who knows it all. And and
we're finding that, you know,
we've got some SharePoint guys
in the team, and I'm relying
heavily on them, and they're
teaching me things all the time.
Yep. And just getting a feel for
how they, you know, put things
in place around governance,
compliance, and, you know,
around all that sort of control,
but I'm learning lots, but what
I'm finding is there's a lot
more consulting than actual
pushing nerd knobs and buttons.
Chris Goosen: Yes, yeah,
Andrew Morpeth: yeah, it's Very
true. Yeah. I mean, I somewhat
missed the Skype days where you
could be intimately familiar
with a single platform and just
know everything about it.
Because now in this world, you
cannot know everything about the
entire stack. And teams is just
a window into multiple micro
services in teams, I'd say to
sis admins, you've already got a
whole ton of skills already that
you might not know you have.
Because teams is leveraging
stuff you already know. It's
just a window into that that
stuff, right? So yes, it is a
collaboration focused product
and there's stuff to learn in
that regard. But a lot of the
underlying technologies you
probably familiar with
Chris Goosen: it so my Sorry,
it's almost like it the the
different areas or components of
it also make for different
deployments. Right. So for
example, when you have a voice
deployment, your voice
requirements, I guess, fairly
binary in terms of customers are
going to know they have these
phone numbers that need to be
answered in this way or handled
in this way. But when it comes
to the compliance and the
governance stuff. That stuff's
gonna be so varied based on
industry and location. And very
often, customers don't actually
have. They don't understand the
requirements that they have
Andrew Morpeth: muted a lot of
customers exactly in small I
couldn't afford to put that
stuff in. But now they get it.
Yep. So they can deploy it, but
they know nothing about it,
really.
Chris Goosen: And if they don't
make the right, you know, it's
almost like making the right
governance decisions up front.
You know, if we take our minds
back to, you know, 8 10 years
ago, when the Yammer was, you
know, first busting up on the
scene may even have been longer
than that. I don't want to go
back that far. But, you know, I
have battle scars from but but
it was one of those things
where, like, if you didn't, in
the very beginning, put in some
really solid governance. It
became such a mess. Yeah. And
and then fixing it retroactively
afterwards was really hard. And
teams is kind of like that, too.
I think like if you just enable
it and just walk away. You're
going to come back in a week and
it's going
Paul Bloem: to be absolutely so
so take your Yammer problem.
Yeah. And I'll see your Yeah,
Yammer problem with my
SharePoint issue. Yeah. 10
exactly, which was just to add
on, and she'll be right, what
happened? Yep. And then we'll
throw in some Skype for Business
and a few other bits and pieces.
And guess what? We have the most
complicated combination of
things we've ever seen. Yeah.
And so what could possibly go
wrong?
Chris Goosen: Yeah, exactly. And
people, people almost like
because we talked about, and I
said this already one time.
Today, we talk about change
management and adoption a lot on
this on the show. And we talk
about governance and compliance
and all of these things. And a
lot of people think that these
are just buzzwords that we're
throwing out and because they
sound cool, well, this this very
good reason why these things
come up over and over and over
again is because, you know, I'm
sure you guys also see customers
who have not made the right
decisions up front or have kind
of gone down the wrong path just
a little bit and then you come
in and now you're, you're trying
to backtrack just a tad to to
help them out. And so that's it,
you know, the message is
consistent because these things
are really important.
Paul Bloem: Yeah, I tell stories
to the highlight you So we keep
the innocent innocent by not
naming any names. And I always
tell them a story. So depending
on the the organization, and I
use some scary story, I heard a
story last week from a customer
who said, We don't like to, you
know, talking about shadow IT,
we don't like to force our users
down any particular path. There
are creative bunch, and we don't
want to limit that. And of
course, at the same time,
they're they're an organization
who's creating new things. And
if those things were to leak,
yeah, well, that'd be the end of
them. Yep. So once I'm married
those two things together and
said so. So I've got some some
pictures we took the other
night, Andrew, I'll share them
with you. They're my Dropbox and
I accidentally share the entire
Dropbox directory. I also have
some very sensitive information
in there right now and knowing
we have shared with you, and I
can't even tell
Chris Goosen: you access.
Exactly.
Paul Bloem: Yeah. So there's all
this kind of stuff. So I usually
just find an angle for the
customer in question, and then
I'll tell them a story leading
down a path. Yeah. And usually
at the end of it, they've got
these massive eyeballs staring
at me and like I've just scare
the hell out. Do it.
Andrew Morpeth: Yeah. And you
don't have to necessarily go
bananas on it, but you've got to
at least sit down and have the
conversations with the business
and just go, you know, at least
make an informed decision. Yeah.
And goes because fires you can
afford to or want to or you
know, but at least have a bit of
a think about it before you just
didn't roll on
Paul Bloem: know the risks.
Right? Yeah.
Chris Goosen: Yep. I absolutely.
I think that's a very, very good
advice. And it's the kind of, I
guess, top off or come to a
close here, guys, it's been
awesome talking to you. Thank
you for taking the time and
showing me around Auckland in
the great weather and whatnot.
And before we go, I guess we you
know, we always kind of like to
plug give you the opportunity to
plug yourself so each of you
studying the book, how do you
want to be found Do you even
want to be found?
Paul Bloem: Hidden not hiding? I
try to make a bit of noise on
LinkedIn and it's just
PaulBorm_NZ. That's where I'm at
and of course my blog as
yucsorted.com. That's where I
am. Yeah, fair enough.
Andrew Morpeth: Yeah, almost.
active on the Twitter community.
My handle is @AndrewMorpeth.
That might be a bit difficult to
spell. So find me at ucgeek.co
That's my blog. So check me out
there and the links to Twitter
and various other channels that
I post information on there as
well.
Chris Goosen: Cool. I'll put all
that in the show notes too. So
folks can just click through and
and I guess the next thing when
next time we'll be seeing each
other is that summit coming up
in full year? Bring it on month
or so just to sort of a month so
I
Paul Bloem: know now it's it's
been recorded first round to be
a second. That'd be
Andrew Morpeth: Yeah, fair
enough. We know he's not
offering anything
Chris Goosen: we may or may not
be a Joey's at some point.
During summer we will be. Well,
guys, thank you again for your
time. Really appreciate it.
Yeah. So it's the sit down here
and I'm sure we'll be chatting
again. Thank you. Cool.
Warren du Toit: Everyone. Before
you go, we just wanted to say
thank you for listening. We
really enjoyed putting this
podcast together for you every
two weeks. Please visit us at
thearchitects.cloud.
Alternatively, drop us a tweet.
We'd love to hear what you have
to say @thecloudarch