Chris Goosen: Welcome to the
cloud architects podcast, a
podcast about cloud technology
and the people using it.
Nicolas Blank: The cloud
architects podcast is sponsored
by Kemp technologies. Choose
Kemp to optimize your multi
cloud application deployments
and simplify multi cloud
application management. A single
pane of glass for application
delivery Kemp provides a 360
degree view of your entire
application environment, and
even third party ADCs. Download
Kemp 360 for free today at
kemptechnologies.com.
Warren du Toit: Hello, everyone,
and welcome to another episode
of the cloud architects. We have
to really cool guests with us
today from ignite
Rick Claus: cloud architects.
Warren du Toit: Yeah, yeah,
cloud architects. Patch and
switch, welcome to the show.
Joey Snow: Thanks for having us
Warren du Toit: The Living
Legends.
Joey Snow: Sure.
Nicolas Blank: Or legendary at
least if you prefer
Joey Snow: dairy probably
Nicolas Blank: dairy, dairy. Is
this an allergy show?
Joey Snow: allergy free zone?
Warren du Toit: allergy free
lactose free.
Nicolas Blank: Safe Zone and too
I had
Rick Claus: my almond milk latte
earlier today. I'm all set.
Joey Snow: Oh, nice. Nice.
Warren du Toit: That's
fantastic. And how's your week
been?
Joey Snow: It's been busy but
it's been fantastic. getting a
chance to see everyone see the
community the MVPs the our
customers I still have meetings
left to do Really? Wow. I've
dinner tonight with corporate
partners that I managed so yeah,
it's it's it's been busy.
Rick Claus: It's been kind of
crazy having a maintain your day
job plus also all the key
aspects Oh, yeah, the event
itself, like joy. I also have
some, some meetings besides it
recording podcast with folks
like you, with the customers and
also an evening meeting as well
too. So,
Nicolas Blank: but we aren't
under oppression that you just
your full time job is to be on
camera.
Rick Claus: You'd be surprised.
Joey Snow: nobody really wants
to see that actually a couple
times here. Alright, that's
enough.
Warren du Toit: So then what
technically is your job titles?
But what is it? What do they
call you?
Rick Claus: So I'm actually
called a cloud advocate lead. So
I built a team of seven people
that are smarter than me, that
go off and create amazing
contents that is in demand by
our customers and by our
partners, and by the community
online that cover a variety of
topics. And my particular team
is focused on the operations
side of Azure, for the IT pro
audience and for the architects
audience, for architecture,
primarily VMs but then also
talking a bit about Kubernetes
and containers and future
looking and then also a bit in
the identity space. Security
space as well. But then we also
handle the modernization of on
premises as well. A lot of our
customers, the majority of the
customers that are out there are
still very much having an on
premises focus. And we're trying
to get them modernize, they can
start to take advantage of some
of the goodness that is inside
of the Azure world.
Joey Snow: I'm a Senior Program
Manager in the identity team. So
I work in the Azure Active
Directory team. And what I do is
I have inside of the engineering
team, we have a customer and
partner experience team, which
is designed basically to help us
get feedback back to our
engineering team faster, and
help our customers get deployed
and to be successful. customers
and partners as well. So I
manage a group of partners that
help our customers get our
product deployed, get managed
services built around them, help
get them secure. All around
identity in Azure Active
Directory.
Nicolas Blank: We love your
world. We ready. We had. Yeah,
we had Elisabeth Olsen on early
on the show. Yeah, and second
year in a row
Joey Snow: and one of those
absolutely nothing. I can add to
this podcast.
Nicolas Blank: Except that Rick
promise does that by you
exceptionally good looks you'd
balance everything out.
Rick Claus: Absolutely. Yeah. At
least his face for radio.
Joey Snow: Yeah, I do I
completely have a face for radio
100%
Warren du Toit: Yeah, your team.
Your team is the cloud. The
cloud advocate teams are
incredible.
Nicolas Blank: Yeah, we spent
some time with him on the road
and they're amazing.
Warren du Toit: Yeah, thank you.
Yeah. Last year and in in Hong
Kong. We got to mess around with
it was good fun.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Rick Claus: Yeah. So biggest fun
this so this year we've expanded
kicking off starting tomorrow,
which is Saturday when we're
recording this. I'm flying to
Paris and we're kicking off at
night the tour 30 plus stops
around the world this time
double the number stops almost.
And my team will be at least one
or two of my team will be at
every single city stuff to be a
luxury of coverage. So we have a
consistently high level of
content and also high level of
engagement. So, if you look up,
Microsoft Ignite the tour,
you'll see the cities they're
free event you can go off and
subscribe to go off to and show
up in your local city. It's
mostly international tour.
There's only I think three or
four cities in the US. Primarily
international for China. Yes,
there's definitely more in
China, Tokyo, Japan. And I'll be
in Beijing in December. I want
to never been to Beijing before.
Yeah, I'll be fine.
Nicolas Blank: Yeah, I'm on my
way to Shanghai right after this
is the first time ever to
Shanghai as well. Awesome.
Really, really? Looking forward
to that?
Rick Claus: Yeah. Yeah, very
cool stuff.
Nicolas Blank: So let's talk
about a topic just for a little
bit. Oh, we know
Rick Claus: we have topics.
Joey Snow: I thought I was just
just here to chit chat,
Warren du Toit: because it's
ties in nicely to the
announcements that last week. So
if we have to look, one of the
big announcements inside of
Agile was Arc. Yep. And that's
multi cloud on prem. The whole
thing. What do you guys thoughts
on that?
Nicolas Blank: Let's just define
Arc quickly for people who don't
know what that is. And go and
go.
Rick Claus: See it. This is kind
of a test to see how the message
was received by someone other
than Microsoft for that it was
given. So I am curious.
Warren du Toit: So it. So arc is
the ability to manage devices
and servers and vdis and
containers and Kubernetes data.
So workloads that aren't
necessarily inside of Azure. So
they can be in AWS, they can be
on premises, and they can also
help you move and manage those
workloads as well. And the
biggest thing about Arc is that
it's free. When you think about
what Amazon is charging Amazon,
which I think they're charging
somewhere in the region of like
$8,000 a month per Kubernetes
cluster, whatever the case may
be, is, where's free,
Nicolas Blank: Joey I know that
I just saw a bit of a little bit
Rick Claus: It worked.
The messaging works.
So it's, it's a, it's an
architecture that allows you to,
if you think about it in the in
the Agile world internally in
engineering, and I think we
talked about this publicly to I
should probably figure that out
for I say it. We talked about
resource providers, right. So
the different resource providers
to be able to spot up resources
inside of Azure as an example.
we're extending that to also not
have resource providers that can
work in different locations.
Because in case you didn't know,
other clouds are pretty
protective about their stuff.
And they don't expose any API's
that expose anything the outside
world, they want you to use
their management of monitoring
tools, yeah, or for you to buy a
third party service to go in and
to do those different management
and stuff. So we're basically
now able to go in and to start
to bubble up stuff. You know,
the first level of things that
gonna be going on are going to
require some level of them and
have an install. Yeah, there's
other areas. So you have to put
some stuff on the Kubernetes
hosts to be able to go off the
nodes and the Management nodes,
you have to be able to go in and
put in a hybrid resource
provider for on premises
machines, but then they appear
as resources inside of Azure.
And then once they're inside of
Azure as a resource, then all
the goodness that is inside of
Azure can take place. And you
can have log analytics take
place, you can have security
recommendations take place, you
can have monitoring alerts and
performance alerts take place
record and
Warren du Toit: upgrade
Kubernetes even straight from
the panel.
Rick Claus: Yep. So so the the
capabilities are being laid out,
and they'll be continuing to
evolve as they go. But it was a
pretty substantial viewpoint
that we gave this earlier in the
week with the initial keynote. I
think it was Gabe Gable gave one
minority source a Monroe or
Malloy. It's been Ryan, I think
it is. I should know this
because I said hello on the
first day he joined Microsoft.
Back in the day from Colorado,
he did a phenomenal demo about
how arc is gonna be going off
and working.
Joey Snow: I think one of my
favorite components of arc and
again, it's not a single thing,
right? Yeah. It's a set of it's
a set of tech Everything you
have that allow things is the
ability to do Policy and
Governance. So basically, it
allows you to leverage some of
the configuration security
configuration and governance of
the server is very, I mean,
everybody probably knows Group
Policy. There are people in this
world that have on their resume.
I'm a group policy expert. And
they know how to do that. You
can think of some of the
components of arc and managing
and these policies is kind of
like a group policy. This is the
next 20 years. Yeah, so for the
past 20 years, we've been doing
group policy on premises, right?
So you can think of this and,
and, and mostly on the server
side, as that's, that's how
you're going to manage those
configurations. And you can take
some of the the practices that
we already have, when you spin
up Azure VMs and some of those
things and and apply those same
policies in a very consistent
manner to resources regardless
of where those resources live.
Yeah, and is really just kind of
this next step. As we move
toward we talked multi cloud and
multi cloud can exist on
premises as well.
Nicolas Blank: What about my on
premises VMware estate?
Rick Claus: Initially, we're
looking at doing it from a VM
inside of the host
configuration, right? We're not
looking at the individual lower
level fabrics at this point in
time. It's a natural extension.
Again, I don't want to say any
for looking statements, they
don't have the details to be
able to pry out of me, which is
good. But if I look at it, I
just see a VM as a VM as a VM. I
don't care where it is.
redeliver don't at this time,
have any kind of inter lower
level knowledge of what's
happening down below. Until you
start going into things like our
migration tools. Our migration
tools do have the ability to go
in to take a look at the
underlaying v cloud platform,
Warren du Toit: which has also
been completely redone, updated
data and yeah, this
Rick Claus: week, don't ask me
questions that one there as I
haven't read that one yet.
There's a Book of news in case
you're wondering
Nicolas Blank: about that. Yeah.
Rick Claus: The Book of news is
available for download from the
news.microsoft.com website that
lists off. And you were saying
the Table of Contents how many
page Long's remember,
Joey Snow: I think I want to say
it was 14 or 15 pages, just the
Table of Contents? Yes,
Rick Claus: it was insane. And
then it has the details of all
the different functions and
features that we announced this
or rather, the solutions that
we've announced, we no longer do
the functions and features thing
anymore.
Nicolas Blank: But How exciting
is that I have a virtual
machine, which could be on just
about anything could be VMware,
it could be on open stack, it
could be on whatever. And I can
see it in portal and I can
report an instrument on it.
Rick Claus: To me, that's going
to be invaluable. I mean, the
customers that I've seen, I
talked with as well, as I
mentioned, a lot of people than
in the space that I work in with
modernization are very much in a
now I'm starting to look at the
cloud. I mean, in your
consultancies, working much more
cloud forward, you're dealing
with a lot of customers that are
very much cutting edge and
wanting to be there. Now we're
starting to see that happen.
first level of the curve has
gone and coming and they're
there and they buy into it. Now
we've got this big massive wave
coming behind them that are now
starting to be able to come
forward and want to want to know
what to do. So yeah, the the
ability to include them and have
them visible inside the inside
the portal, as you mentioned,
the able to put policy against
them and our back against them
and stuff like that. The ability
to install the hybrid agent on
the different machines, it's
going to be very powerful. And
as you mentioned, the very
beginning of all this, it's not
just VMs yet VMs is obviously
where 80% of our customers are
going to be right now for what
they're comfortable with working
with net new development or or
modernization of existing
workloads that are being
reimagined off of VMs into
something more compact, are
going to be looking at
containers to reduce is the
current winner in that space.
And then also potentially re
architect and looking at even
avoiding Kubernetes and going
straight to a microservices
architecture and said all that's
coming down the road, but more
and more people are looking at
how can I get immediate value
now? using something like arc
Using the hybrid RP and other
things like that, to put all the
stuff inside of one, one spot,
it sounds marketing, but, you
know, one pane of glass, the
ideas all in one spot.
Nicolas Blank: It's like the
show's done, we can leave. Okay,
Joey Snow: great talking, ever
done.
Warren du Toit: Now we can go
back to what we were originally
talking about.
Joey Snow: But But listen, you
know, when we talk about the
cloud, it was interesting I had
a conversation with Aaron
chapel. And and it's, it's kind
of the the it comes in waves,
right? And you look it's like,
okay, we're going to do this
thing on prem, then you move to
the cloud, and then you're
expanding out beyond clouds. And
then there may come a time where
you eventually have to come back
down again. Yes, right. But you
need to still be able to treat
those those resources if that as
if they are a true cloud,
scalable resources and all the
things that they were working on
and Azure and the announcements
that they made around that the
arc stuff this, this ignite,
that's exactly what they're
doing. So it's it's not so much
wear anymore. And it's just
using that methodology.
Rick Claus: Yeah, I think there
was a tweet that Jeff Woolsey
put out, which was hilarious.
This week. He's like, our hybrid
strategy is a true and full
planned out. Complete strategy,
multi cloud on premises
exclusively cloud exclusively on
premises. Then also multi cloud
as well
Warren du Toit: as the
intelligent edge net
Rick Claus: and intelligent edge
as well. Yeah. And he's like,
it's not a checkbox. It's right.
It's not like oh, other cloud
vendor. Yeah, we do hybrid
check. Yes, they can get past
the RFC or something like that.
We actually have a full
documented way of how we can go
off and do this sort of stuff.
Joey Snow: It's important to
know that the reality is, is
hybrids going to exist for a
very long time. Oh, yeah. And
it's something that we take very
seriously inside of inside of
active directory, Azure Active
Directory, and making sure that
we have the the ability to
provide the security, to provide
the governance and to provide
the compliance is absolutely
key, no matter where you are. So
we spent a lot of time here at
Ignite, complementing a lot of
that hybrid messaging that was
occurring, not just on the
platform side, but also on the
identity side, right? We start
looking at how can you secure
and manage those identities that
Warren du Toit: you see that's,
that's why security has moved.
So, again, so like one of my
sessions now that I'm doing in
a, in a couple minutes is on
is firewalls inside of Azure,
right network virtual
appliances, and how people still
need them because of certain
things. But Id, the firewalls
not the protection mechanism
anymore, not the person, right?
So identity, yes. So so the
identity is the way you secure
your resources. It's not the
fact that your SQL Servers out
on the internet now it's got
nothing to do with that anymore.
So we're moving in that way. I
didn't The most important thing
they
Joey Snow: the way I talk about
this is that before we kind of
had all of these things together
inside we had, we have the user
of the identity you had the
platform of the devices, the
server, the application, you
have the data. And and and
really Group Policy and some of
the things that we had inside of
remedy did a little of this and
a little about the kind of cross
all of them with Azure Active
Directory, we had to split that
out. And we have Look, it's an
if that's what it is. It's
purely an identity provider. And
it's the one that we want
everybody to use. And it does
one thing, which is identity and
imagine that it protects it. You
want to connect your apps to the
identity have that single
identity that is protected
because it is that Alex Simon's
likes to call it the control
plane, we've done a lot of
controlling talking around the
outside of here, it but that's
it, it's that single place. It's
that one place and you know that
that identity is is trusted and
and then more importantly, That
the session that the identity
has actually initiated is also
trusted, insecure. Yeah. So you
know, it's first make sure you
turn on MFA because password
suck. And until we can get rid
of that and we're in we really
are in the process of doing it.
I think we've crossed the chasm
now, in terms of over a million
identities are managed
passwordless so far.
Nicolas Blank: And we some of
those we've been running
passwordless for months. Yep,
Joey Snow: absolutely. So a lot
of investments a lot of talk
around password list that is
real. these are these are things
you can do today. And and
eventually it's our it's our
goal in our mission to get rid
of passwords all together, and
then in the future, change the
way identity is. So yeah, it's
it's super cool and exciting.
That I think my favorite part
about this is that just like the
the arc things, this all can be
done now and it can all be done
across no matter where you are.
Yeah. And if you're if you're on
prem, you're in Azure. You're in
other clouds.
Warren du Toit: And it's, it's
not hard either. No, it No it's,
you know, to me like to turn MFA
on or to take your password away
is really not hard you like take
out a box and it's gone.
Nicolas Blank: or to even bring
your own identity and federate
through Google, but still manage
your object and Azure AD b2b
again. So there's so much
goodness in there and then
policy and control them. And I
still only have one direction. I
think that's wonderful.
Joey Snow: Yeah, we're
leveraging conditional access
and the things that we can do
through conditional access
policies is really kind of the
game changer. Yeah. I kind of
look at turning on MFA is it's
kind of three major things when
you turn on MFA for everything
for everyone, which is really a
bad experience. As somebody who
was on the early side, when we
did it at Microsoft, it's like
oh my gosh, yeah. And and and
I've actually had customers that
that have gone through this
route and I was just I was I was
just over in Ireland. I was
speaking with a customer and and
they're really struggling
because they did this the first
time and it was not a good
experiences. Their CIO is really
hesitant to go do it again. But
now we actually through
conditional access, and that's,
that's stage two, right? Yeah.
Being able to do conditional
access and make those, you know,
rules around when do you based
on your location, your risk
those those types of things. And
then that third step is taking
it out of the hands of it to
making, making the termination
of if the user is risky, or the
session is risky. And that's all
that's all around identity
protection. And that's by
leveraging the trillions and
trillions and trillions of
signals that we get every single
day. We a lot of people
donorship we authenticate 45
billion authentications in a
month.
Warren du Toit: Tenant to tenant
migration, right? Yep. Tenant to
tenant migration is hard.
Joey Snow: Yes. Yes.
Warren du Toit: And I blame you
Joey Snow: know, we know and
this is this is this is very
work this is work that we're
doing. Yeah,
it's work that we continue to do
I and I don't want to make any
like like I'm gonna stay away
from for for statements but this
is the type of feedback but it's
also the feedback the
information that we need.
Warren du Toit: Yeah no show and
it's why the inevitably
accompanies going to be bought
or sold. Always always
Joey Snow: gonna have look m&a
and some of our biggest. But
there's also it's also
opportunity. Yeah, right. We
look at it as something that we
have to address, because that's
what our customers are doing
this. And I want to be clear, we
don't do anything inside of
Azure Active Directory unless
there's a customer need to do
it. Yeah. We no longer sit in a
room on whiteboards and come up
with shiny disco ball things
thinking, well, if we could only
get our customers to adopt this,
yeah, it doesn't even get to the
next stage until there's a
customer story. Every time we
build a new feature inside of
the service It is tempted inside
of a private preview first
before it goes out into a
broader public preview. All the
feedback comes in all the
changes and modifications. And
there are times that something
will sit in that public preview
for a considerable amount of
time, because maybe we didn't
get it exactly right in the
first time. Us, it's up to us to
make that modification based on
what our customers needs not not
how we look at that. And then,
you know, we'll obviously put it
into GA. And that is something
that's why I am in the space.
That's why I'm in the team. We
are that customer obsessed. I've
80 engineers here that have been
just absolutely inundated in the
booth, in addition to doing
sessions on the developer side
is is there's a lot of stuff
happening there in terms of, as
Rick mentioned, with application
modernization and monetization
platform to modernize the
identity piece as well. Yeah.
And you have to move start
moving things up. And so it's
just really important for folks
to understand it. There's a lot
of hard things. We're also
trying to make life easier
because identity is at its core
can be a very challenging thing
to do. Oh, yes. It used to be,
you know, five years and, and
and the slide deck that you paid
a million dollars for that had
15 Chevron's at the top and you
can't do a single thing until
you tick off all those 15
pieces. Now you can't do that
anymore with you've got to
protect that thing. First turn
on him. If you do nothing else,
turn on MFA. Yeah, via
conditional access and get that
identity protected. And then we
can start moving down the path
of doing things like
provisioning and de provisioning
and which we can already do. You
can actually we have inbound
provisioning through workday.
We're working on other platforms
as well and integration there to
do inbound provisioning. You can
do outbound provisioning with a
whole ton of applications of
1.3. We might be at 1.4 million
applications that have
integration with Azure Active
Directory today.
Nicolas Blank: How many again so
that number
Joey Snow: is we're probably
close to 1.4. I don't We were
1.3. That number is two months
old.
Nicolas Blank: Those are
discrete applications.
Joey Snow: Those are
applications that currently have
integration with Azure Active
Directory. Yep. Yep. But that,
but that does not show
Warren du Toit: PowerShell  is
one of them. And so all the
other applications that use
PowerShell in the back to make
those commands counts as one.
Nicolas Blank: Rick what did you
do last summer.
Joey Snow: And then and then the
other thing too
Rick Claus: Painted my house,
worked on my Jeep.
Joey Snow: We made a lot of
announcements here at Ignite,
and recently around partnerships
that we have with things like
five Yes, where now we can
expose applications behind those
five appliances. But here's the
cool thing. You can set the
policy on the individual
application. You're not just
doing it Oh, everything that
hits the applied. So that
changes how you can modernize
your applications as well.
Right? Yeah, we do. So So we've
been spending a lot of time on
that because we as you mentioned
It's not the thing anymore, not
the firewall, we have to start
going, how do we get these apps?
And 1.3 1.4 million apps is
awesome. But we have to make
sure that we hit the ones
everybody is using. And that's
exactly what we've done. Yeah.
So the top application providers
that that, that need
authentication, we have those
partnerships with them, and they
can do the things that we want
them to do. And it's all
standards based. So we're not
going out and creating some new
wild wacky way to connect
things. Yeah, right. We
provision through scam. Right?
We do we do password list
through Fido2. To we contribute
to the standards, I did an
interview with Pamela Dingle,
whose entire job she's a
director in product marketing.
She works for Alex Simon's in
our org, and all she does is
standards. And it's it's
incredible. The amount of effort
and time and contributions that
we're making to these standards
to ensure that we can do this,
not just now and doing it the
right way, but doing it
Warren du Toit: the right way.
We were talking to Julia (Foran)
the other day.
I've got this thing about ICS
standards. Yeah, a calendar
invite follows those standards,
because they're all different
man.
Joey Snow: If you want to have
if you want to have real fun
with standards Go Go read the
CSP standard. Really? Yeah.
What's hardcore? Oh, it's a hot
mess.
Nicolas Blank: it's a hot mess
Joey Snow: it's a hot mess. It's
all we're doing things that was
never meant is it?
Warren du Toit: Is it is that
comma?
Rick Claus: Is the quote of the
show right there. It's a hot
mess.
Joey Snow: That's what Pamela
told me anyway. Yeah, it's it.
Look at DNS it's always DNS.
Yeah we always blame DNS.
Nicolas Blank: or networking
Rick Claus: I have a question
for you. Actually. Yeah. If you
don't mind me, please. I mean,
the show timeline. No, I like
well, it's my turn to talk about
the, the the, the question the
the one of the topics we're
talking about today is obviously
going to be multi cloud
management, sort of Do you have
customers asking for this? Is it
only that first level of
introductory people that are
going that path? Or is everyone
asking for this? Because Is it a
checkbox exercise? So or is it a
real actual ask? That's
happened.
Warren du Toit: So to be honest
with you, I think is a real
risk. Because you'll see that a
particular client will never put
together just an Azure framework
for their company. They want it
to be a cloud framework. So they
want to make sure that these
policies cover everything moving
forward, because it's a big
change for them. So they've now
gone and set down policies who
can do this, you can do that
that can be spun up that can't
wait, it can be accessed the
portal from and that all gets
documented. But there's no point
in doing it just for Azure.
You'll see some of the banks in
South Africa, for instance, have
done AWS first course right and
now they're putting that AWS
document to blueprints and
obviously with something like
lights coming out as well,
which, you know, manages those
blueprints across all those all
those different tenants. Yes, I
would say having a single place
to manage all those things is
very important, because some of
them already have them. I mean,
you'll see Cape Town, for
instance, has a very large, AWS
huge, huge country.
Nicolas Blank: In particular
sectors like like retail. Yeah,
retail loves Amazon,
Warren du Toit: because for some
reason you got these diehard
Linux dudes who haven't seen the
light, and they're like, if
you're a Linux person, then you
have to go AWS and be faithful,
which is like, the wrong way
around. I mean, we know this. I
mean, I'm a Linux boy. And, you
know, Microsoft is number one
open source contributor on the
planet, but no, no, you're
betraying the you betraying the
shell betraying the Shell, it's
a hot mess.
Joey Snow: Gonna be trading
between betraying the shell and
hot mess are now the themes of
this particular episode of the
podcast.
Warren du Toit: So to answer
your question is I think it's I
think it's,
Nicolas Blank: I'll give you my
spin on this as well and then
I'll, I'll maybe ask you to
comment on it. So my biggest ask
for customers going multicloud
is that they're trying to avoid
vendor lock in. So I'll put a
little bit here put a little bit
day while use the commercial
angle is, as you know, well that
I'm going to tell Microsoft
there, I'm going to do a
percentage of my workload on
another cloud, no matter how
well or how badly it does it
because I'm trying to avoid
commercial lock and I want to
commercial angle. The biggest
pain for me on that is
management overhead. And having
a there's there's no single pane
on anything. There's multiple
places of ordered. There's
multiple management and
infrastructures, having to spend
a lot of money with third
parties to get those logs into
central location which tends to
be on premises, right? And not
scale.
Rick Claus: Yep. So I agree with
that. At the same time. What I
find is interesting is some
customers that are jumping into
this conversation without
thoroughly thinking it out is I
forget who mentioned it was on
online, they were talking about
how, if you look at doing
adopting a multi cloud
environments, you're not going
to get the full depth and
breadth of the power of that
particular platform vendor.
Yeah, because you have to leave
only so much so deep. And that
applies to all three of the
clouds. Yeah, that's out there.
That's what I find the the
concept of arc very interesting,
because it doesn't matter to us
where those resources happen to
be will give you the insights.
So we're kind of like your, I'm
not going to call it a seven
device, but we're kind of like
that inside of the Azure space.
Because we bring stuff back into
duty now analytics on it, but
you can leave your Kubernetes
running over an AWS if you want
to. You can have your your
elastic compute or go off and do
Nvidia AI type stuff in Google
if you want to do but you can
also do it here too. And that's
true for as I mentioned that all
three vendors, obviously, we
will make it the best experience
possible inside of our own
clouds for all the different
services that you have. Same
thing with AWS, same thing with
Google. It's just the strategy
at all three players are doing,
we're the first one to go out
and actually try to say, Okay,
well, the reality is customers
are looking for this, we're
asking for this. So let's go off
and give you an awesome
experience here inside of Azure,
but then also give you the
insights from other places.
Joey Snow: But it's the same
thing from a security
perspective. And I hear this all
the time when I talk about Azure
Active Directory, which then
tends to lead down the
discussion of things like ATP
and some of the other the other
security technologies that we
have, because we're kind of all
together because that's how
we're sold right as part of BMS,
right. But yes, there are multi
vendors out there that the one
advantage that I see inside
ourselves is the sheer volume of
of information and signals that
we have, where we're getting
them from our ability to take
action on those signals. And
then even more importantly, how
inside all of our products, we
all can share that signals data,
right? And we
Warren du Toit: can all take the
same time as the new Microsoft,
right? So if you have to look
from sort of when such a took
over, and that everything
started getting open sourced,
and there was more
collaboration, and they weren't
these big walls anymore. You can
see that Microsoft now is
probably the number one
integrator of other products
into their product, if you look
at it holistically, there are
API's to do so many things there
are I mean, if you look at the
graph framework, yeah, you can
literally do whatever you want,
and get any data out of it. And
then you can present it in a in
any way you want it to be and
you can do it securely. And
there's like none of that you
have to stick with us anymore.
What just choose it mix and
match one
Joey Snow: of the biggest
workloads that we authenticate
to is Google. Yeah.
I mean, that's we share that we
share that all the time. I'd say
it was probably in Alex's
presentation earlier this week.
Yeah. And so yeah, 100% I
understand.
Nicolas Blank: what's the
circumstance? They?
Joey Snow: Well, they're
authenticating to Google
applications.
Nicolas Blank: Yeah, I was gonna
say is it inbound from Google?
Or is it oubound to Google?
Joey Snow: So it's, it's an
Azure Active Directory identity
is being used to access a Google
Google Docs or whatever happens
to be because remember, and and,
and identity is that's a little
bit tricky in terms of you
really don't want to have
identities living in multiple
places you don't because that
means there's more crappy
passwords locating and that's
another thing that somebody has
to manage. His identity is the
one thing that You have to, you
have to make sure that you've
got it and it's secured. And
it's, it's protected. And you
can manage it and you can cover
and against it was only one of
them. Yeah. Well, that ideally,
yes,
Warren du Toit: I do is anything
I can take away from ignite is
how I can fix that problem that
I'm having.
Joey Snow: But listen, we were
very clear about our intention
moving forward. We want to take
identity out of the hands of
companies and businesses and
everybody else and bring it back
to the individual. That's,
that's our future vision, right
where the person can control
that identity and then give the
ability for me to us that it's
explained then take it back. But
that's, that's, that's where we
have to go. That's where we have
to go. And And particularly,
just look, how many of us really
don't think our data is out
there. Huh? Come on. You were
talking on the way to the
airport here. They were PII on
your phone than there is on
throughout your house. In any
documentation? Yeah, we carry
these things around with us.
Right We connect 10 secure Wi Fi
is and all the other bad
behavior that we have
Rick Claus: Bluetooth beacons.
And as you're walking through a
mall, yeah, I don't know where
you are in the mall and what
you're doing just by having a
Bluetooth stack on.
Joey Snow: So I understand the
concern around vendor lock in.
But at the same time, there are
benefits to leveraging services
from a vendor that can have that
communication and share that
data across and making that data
exposed to you so that you can
take action or even better. Let
the AI do it. Yeah. I don't want
to have to manage session risk.
That's ridiculous to me. I don't
know what the best rule is for
when when a session is risky. Or
when it user
Rick Claus: What do you mean, I
can't log in here in Orlando and
in Seattle,
Joey Snow: within an hour each
other time possible travel
scenario, or, hey, maybe I
didn't know that my username and
password ended up in some breach
and I've not changed it and I'm
a global admin. Yeah, you think
you might want to know about
that and even better Just next
time go who's the right one? No,
that's me because I've got a
second factor off. Yes. And now,
Joey, let's reset your password.
Or in this case, you know, just
MFA me because I'm pastoralists.
Yeah, yeah.
Nicolas Blank: Oh, I'm just in
time you so you don't need to be
a high risk person with global
admin that gets targeted.
Joey Snow: Well, and that's
that's really the key piece is
that you shouldn't be running
global admin anyone? Yep. You
should only elevate when
necessary and and even even more
importantly, we shouldn't be
requiring you to be global admin
to do a lot of the things that
you have, which is why we're
doing a lot of investment, a lot
of work where I was about to
ask, because you know,
Nicolas Blank: there's a bunch
of stuff in teams that you can't
do with Justin time. Other
products. Yep, not quite there
yet. But all of the second teams
is a very complicated beats
fine, but then the guidance that
you see is I need this Roland
teams and I need that rollin
teams and unless you and even if
you just in time them and this
you then decided to Temporarily
grant someone Global Admins
stuff still doesn't work. Right.
So our back is not as
transparent as ubiquitous as we
wanted yet. But what I'm hearing
from you is like,
Joey Snow: Yeah, well, we've
been doing that we made
significant investments in that.
We've made investments in that,
that we've talked about here
with with some new reader roles
that we've that we've announced
here. So we have to continue.
The best way that I can explain
this is that we don't ship
product anymore. I we don't ship
a new version of active
directory where we haven't done
that in in years and years and
years. Yeah, we are a service.
We enhance the service
consistently. We have to go
faster. We have to do it faster,
because we have to get to our
customers need it. Yeah. And
that's a difficult thing for IT
professionals to kind of get
their heads around because
either we're not fast enough or
we're too bloody fast. But
that's where that that push and
pull. We made changes because we
understood that we had to
provide this path Way to do
hybrid identity?
Warren du Toit: And where do you
draw the line of stability as
well? Right? Well, and how
Joey Snow: do we make it easier
for people to actually go
password lists? And those are
things that we heard from our
customers. They're like, Look,
this is soo bone who I worked
for, says, when we did password
list Initially, it was like a
moonshot. And our customers are
like, Yo, what are you guys
doing? We're not like this.
Yeah, we're like this, we need
you to help us get there in this
manner. And we listened and we
made those adjustments. So I
hundred percent hear you around
that in our back and those kinds
of things. Just as a few years
ago, you had to be global admin
to do everything. And that's not
good behavior. We have to change
that behavior internally to and
we work on that. It's not just,
hey, our customers are our
Microsoft to Microsoft is our
customer to and we have to make
Rick Claus: that the best part
is, as you mentioned, we don't
ship product anymore. Its
services. I can't even not not
from the men's side of the
design side as you brought up
there. But even just From a user
side, opening up one of my apps
be outlook Word, PowerPoint,
Excel flow tooling or Microsoft
Teams like that. I always get a
little surprised in the morning
and says, Oh, you've been
updated the latest version.
Okay, great. What changed? What
can I find? as an end user?
That's a geek and a tech person.
I love to go off and find all
the new stuff that's possibly
there. People go off and find
it. Yeah. Yeah. Although all
about stage not those are all
the different people. Yeah. And
so you want to have that all
over the place. But yeah, no,
teams of all. software products
evolve, the stuff inside of
Azure evolves, there's no longer
gas' anymore. makes it hard for
us to be able to talk about
announcements because you know,
well that's been out for a while
but it just went ga but really,
everyone's been using it for the
last six months. So really is a
big hype anymore. Not so much
so, so it's it's kind of fun to
see where that where that's
going to continue to evolve and
how it changes us as
technologists.
Nicolas Blank: We are coming up
to the The top of the hour so,
Rick Claus: and you've got a
session to deliver somewhere
Joey Snow: in 20 minutes.
Nicolas Blank: So let us ask
you, how would the like that?
How would the two of you like to
be found on socials or dude? No,
no, let's not assume everybody
knows who everybody is. So, let
us show you how they would like
to be found. And then also ask
you one of the ones you would
like to plug.
Joey Snow: Yeah, sure. Y'all go
ahead
Rick Claus: and start so well.
From a social and fun and
community perspective. You can
find us both online together
because no one knows who is who
and what is what and switch and
patch and patch and switch at
sign patches, which is where we
normally happen to be on the
social community and the fun
side.
Joey Snow: We do a podcast every
other Friday on Twitch, it's
twitch.tv/patchandswitch. And
then from a personal
perspective, you can find me on
Twitter I'm at @Joeysnow
Rick Claus: snow and I'm at sign
RicksterCDN and I managed a team
of folks that follow the
hashtag, #AZops for our bat sign
l in case you have a question a
out operations stuff inside
of Azure or on premises, or
with identity or with teams o
with other things like that. S
oot us a message with the has
tag and one of us will be able
to get you. We almost follo
the sun around the Earth right
ow.
Joey Snow: And turn on MFA.
Rick Claus: It's a great demo to
turn that on. By the way, you
know what it is?, Check.
Nicolas Blank: Guys, thank you
so much.
Rick Claus: An awesome show.
Thank you very much, see you
around
Warren du Toit: Everyone. Before
you go, we just wanted to say
thank you for listening. We
really enjoy putting this
podcast together for you every
two weeks, please visit us at
the architects cloud.
Alternatively, drop us a tweet.
We'd love to hear what you have
to say @TheCloudArch.