Chris Goosen: Welcome to the
cloud architects podcast, a
podcast about cloud technology
and the people using it.
Nicolas Blank: The cloud
architects podcast is sponsored
by Kemp technologies. Choose
Kemp to optimize your multi
cloud application deployments
and simplify multi cloud
application management. A single
pane of glass for application
delivery, Kemp provides a 360
degree view of your entire
application environment, and
even third party ADCs. Download
Kemp 360 for free today at
Kemptechnologies.com
Warren du Toit: Hello, everyone,
and welcome to another episode
of the cloud architects podcast
yet I feel the same as you. It's
been a while. It has definitely
been a while. It's been a crazy
year. And I think that this is
like gonna be the first of many
Corona episodes where we talk
about things that have been
happening in sort of how we've
been forced to change the way we
work. And so I'd like to
introduce my co hosts yet again.
It's good to see you guys.
Nicolas Blank: Hey, Nick.
Chris Goosen: Hey, Chris here.
Warren du Toit: And today, we
have an amazing guest. And we'll
introduce him shortly. I think
Nick wants to pick on me a
little bit.
Nicolas Blank: I do. I do. And I
want to pick on Warren and Chris
both because both of them have
had some changes lately. And we
want to talk about some of those
changes because they do have
context for today's show. And
I'm going to add a little bit of
a mystery by saying that they
have both a joint true of the
world's large Just security
vendors. And so why don't we
start with you, Warren, why
don't you tell us what have you
been doing lately?
Warren du Toit: Yeah. So you
know, it's strange when you say
security vendor, right? Because
that's, that's a new thing. I
mean, who ever thought that
Microsoft would be a security
vendor. So yeah, I started
working for Microsoft this
month. It was was a bit tough
because I had to give up my MVP
status, but it's okay. I don't
have a trophy anymore. I'm more
have a blue badge. I mean, it's
somewhere here and I could
probably show you but yeah, I
have cloud solutions architect.
I guess. The really cool thing
is that I get to use the
internal Microsoft tenant now
for Azure. Ah, okay.But anyway..
Nicolas Blank: for all your
hosting requirements. @WarrenDT
on Twitter.
Warren du Toit: Don't go
breaking some new NDAs But
still, I think I think it's a
beautiful thing. It's a
wonderful company to work for.
And as Fran was saying a little
bit earlier while we were
entering Satya as done amazing
things, man. He really, really
has incredible company to work
for and like parental pandemic
leave. Can you believe? So? I
get if I wanted to, I mean,
provided the workload isn't too
hectic I can do. I can teach my
child, I can take Lee even teach
my child which is which is
pretty read. So I think that's
that's that's the that's a cool
thing. And yeah, like I say,
it's it's amazing to be actually
sort of in a as an MVP, you sort
of delve into it. And you push
to sort of create this second
career. So with an MVP, many
Yeah, you're you really work
hard to maintain the two and now
I'm lucky enough to be like
okay, well the two have merged
So not only do I get to promote
Microsoft technology, and use
Microsoft technology, it's my
job. So it's good.
Chris Goosen: Yeah, well done.
That's awesome, man.
Congratulations for that. You
know, so yeah. Yeah, I have
actually in its it's been
probably the biggest change for
me in my entire career right for
the first time ever. And I've
been thinking about this a lot
this this week in particular,
because for the first time ever,
I'm not working for a very large
Microsoft gold partner. Right.
And so that's been very
interesting. And so I made a
move a bit of a career change, I
guess, if you will, earlier in
the year. So right after we
recorded the last episode, which
was in New Zealand, I joined a
company called Kudelski
Security. And so I'm gonna be
heading up the Microsoft
practice, Microsoft Security
practice at Kudelski. And we're
super excited because, you know,
you mentioned before, you know,
Microsoft being one of the
world's largest security
vendors, right. And that's, it's
so true. That's the messaging
that we're using. And it's
exciting to kind of be on the
forefront of that. So still
working very much in the office
365 space for now in the
Microsoft 365 space, but very
much focusing and looking at
everything through a security
focused lens now, as opposed to
the productivity focused lens
from before. And I guess that's
part of why I think this episode
kind of came together because
I've been immersed in working
with some really, really smart
people. And one of those people
is joining us on the call today.
And I was super excited because
my head started spinning day
one, start, you know, trying to
pick up the vernacular and
trying to pick up all the new
concepts in this new cyber
security world. And so we
thought it'd be really good idea
to bring Francisco Donoso onto
the show, to talk a little bit
about that world and break it
down a little bit so that we can
kind of do a, you know,
cybersecurity for IT pros, if
you will. And so with that, I
want to introduce our guest
today, Francisco or Fran,
welcome to the show.
Francisco Donoso: Thank you very
much for having me, Chris
Warren. Nick, it's a pleasure to
be here.
Chris Goosen: Yeah. Do you want
to just do a quick introduction
and sort of tell folks about
yourself and what you do? And
have done? Yeah.
Francisco Donoso: Yeah,
absolutely. So, as Chris
mentioned, we both work together
at a company called Kudelski
Security. And it's been a real
pleasure, the last few months
getting a chance to work closely
with Chris, we've been working
very closely for the last few
months. And that's been great.
as Chris mentioned, you know,
I've been in cybersecurity for
almost the entirety of my
professional career. I sort of
fell into it. In the very
beginning, I got a job at a
company like koski years ago,
doing like security monitoring
for a bunch of different
companies. And I fell in love
with it. I fell in love with
cyber security, even though that
wasn't a consideration, you
know, when I was in school, but
through my career, sorry, guys,
I've had an opportunity to
actually kind of travel all over
the world and work with so The
world's largest companies. I've
spent a lot of time in the
Middle East. After some big
breaches of some of the world's
most valuable companies, I got a
chance to help organizations,
but you know, across healthcare
or all sorts of different
places, kind of recover after
some large breaches. And it's,
it's been a passion of mine,
helping organizations understand
how things are changing with the
cloud, if you will. One of my
favorite things about
cybersecurity in general is how
quickly we have to adapt to new
technology. I think all of us
are probably familiar with that
stuff as new technology comes
out. It's been a blast because I
get to learn how to use it from,
like, administrative perspective
and then have to think through
how do we potentially secure
this stuff? Kubernetes and cloud
environments and office 365,
Chris Goosen: Okay, I was gonna
say you said the K word
Nicolas Blank: Somebody, at
least it wasn't me.
Francisco Donoso: And, and
through my career, you know,
I've had the opportunity to work
in places like Kudelski building
security practice to help our
customers. But I've also been
security engineer at a company
that's now owned by Twilio, that
process more traffic per day
than Twitter. And I had to learn
a lot about how people were
managing infrastructure at
scale, and how that changed my
perspective or my role as a
security person. And then I've
also worked for a startup where
I built all the Kubernetes
stuff, because we didn't have
anything we needed to deploy
code. Kubernetes seemed like a
cool project. And then I had to
figure out how to secure it. So
I've kind of been all over the
place and I've enjoyed every
Warren du Toit: It's not that
easy to build Kubernetes from
second of it.
scratch.
Francisco Donoso: No specially
when you've never used it
before. So it was a it was a
really it was a really fun
experience, though. And that's
really what I love about the
industry that we're at
technology in general, just like
you just get thrown in, and you
have to figure it out.
Warren du Toit: How much how
much and this this is this, this
equation, when I heard you're
gonna have you on the show, I
was thinking to myself, the
first question I'm going to ask
is a Mr. Robot question. It's
gonna be like, how much like Mr.
Robot is being in security? I
mean, cuz when you look at it,
he, I mean, all of those
commands and things that he ran
and obviously they did a lot of
research into Mr. Robot and what
sort of rootkits were being run
and Kali, Linux and all that
kind of stuff. And like, do you
use Kali Linux?
Francisco Donoso: It really
depends. The answer is yes, it
depends on vironment, right,
yeah. Mr. Robot has done the
best job that I've seen thus
far. It really kind of
explaining what cyber security
looks like from an attackers
perspective. And just recently,
actually, I have the opposite.
You need to join a company that
was built by teams who used to
build offensive stuff for
people. So I've had a lot of
opportunity to work with some of
the world's best hackers. It was
it was mind blowing, because
they would be able to go find a
zero day a zero day exploit in
technology used across the world
in like two days, which I didn't
know was possible at the time.
But I think the biggest thing
that that all of those shows
kind of miss is just how much
failure there is before that,
like, success. And what has to
keep you going when you're in
that side of the house, which is
the attacker side is you have to
be okay with the failure but
really love the adrenaline of
the success. Because it's like
99% failure and banging your
head against something that you
just don't understand. To get to
the point where you're like, Oh
my god, I did it. I exploited
this thing. And that's amazing.
Okay. Let me go back to pounding
my head against the wall to
figure out how to how to do the
next thing. So I think that
that's really what's missing
Warren du Toit: the emotion. I
remember how you did it so that
you could protect yourself
against it.
Yeah, yeah.
Chris Goosen: That's
fascinating, right. I think. I
think part of that is, you know,
these conversations, these types
of conversations and the fact
that we've all thought about and
understood the need to be more
security focused, especially in
the last 10, eight to 10 years,
right with, everything's moving
into the public domain, if you
will, as far as like the cloud
and stuff is not as publicly
accessible. You can't just wrap
your arms around your data
center anymore and go Okay,
well, we'll just put a firewall
and now stuffs protected, right?
I remember, man, this would have
been probably, I'm thinking
probably around 2005, maybe
2004. I was at a teched event,
Microsoft tech event. It was in
Joburg. So it was the early one
did them in, in Sun City. And
there was a guy gentleman by the
name of Steve Riley, who used to
work for Microsoft trustworthy
computing group, and went on to
AWS and I'm not sure where he is
now riverbed, I think at one
point too And at that time, he
was talking about the concept of
perimeter boundary, less data
centers, right. And I still
remember the talk was called
something like, you know, it's
10am. Do you know what your data
is? And people just lost their
mind, because this guy was like,
it's the time is coming, where
you're not going to have a
perimeter, you're going to have
to shift stuff, somewhere,
wherever anyone can access it.
And you need to rethink what
that means to you and your
organization. And Fast Forward
15 years, you know, I mean,
we've been going down this route
for a while now. But Fast
Forward 15 years, it has never
been more true. So welcome to
the cloud. Yeah, welcome to the
cloud, right. So So we've all
kind of Being This is something
that's been on our, I guess, in
our minds for a little while,
but I think when you start
really digging into it, man,
it's a whole new world. Right.
And so I guess Fran, one of the
things I wanted to kind of, I
guess, asked you or ask you to
unpack for us to break out is
the concept of the vernacular
and the concepts that kind of
float around in cyberspace,
right, because you hear people
talk about blue team and red
team and white hat and black
hat. It sounds like people just
love colors in the security
world. But there's some river
they have very specific
meanings, though, right, those
terms and those phrases.
Francisco Donoso: Yeah, yeah,
absolutely. But before I do
that, I'm sorry, I just kind of
mentioned something that you
reminded me of that talk where
you said, Hey, you know,
boundary lis networks and data
centers are a real thing. The
first time I had an experience
like that, that had to kind of
shift. My entire mindset was
when I was working at a company
that got purchased by Twilio.
And we were processing so much
data that when we started
looking at firewall vendors for
protecting our data center, he
would have literally cost
hundreds of millions of dollars
to buy hardware powerful enough
to secure our environment from
like a traditional network
segmentation perspective. So we
had to shift and say, Okay,
well, now we're managing
firewalls at every single
server. And it was just such an
interesting shift that I think
most organizations are now
having to think about, right? I
don't know how many
organizations are so large that
they literally can't buy enough
hardware to, like process the
security traffic from a firewall
perspective, but that was a that
was a really interesting change
in kind of mindset for me. But
yeah, just like you mentioned,
you know, there's a lot of
terms. And I think that this is
something that's been specially
pervasive in cybersecurity, and
I'm not sure exactly why it's so
bad in this specific section,
but we have a lot of terms like
blue team, right, which
essentially is really just
defensive guys. Right? So it
actually a lot of the terms that
you hear in cyber security come
from, like old military
backgrounds, because some of the
very first, people who started
thinking about cyber security
came from the like, national
security or defense space. So
the word red team as an example,
which is intended to denote
someone who's like trying to
attack you in terms of a
cybersecurity exercise they're
trying to break into your
environment. In order to help
you see what could happen came
from the, from the military
world, there would be a red team
who would work on a training
exercise with a team by I don't
know breaking into some compound
and seeing how far they get. So
the red team in cybersecurity is
essentially the same thing. Hey,
can we break into your
organization? How far can we
get? How realistic can we be?
And the blue team is sort of the
opposite of that right that
their defensive team was sitting
there trying See if they can
find those bad guys, or in the
real military,
Warren du Toit: Do they work
well together?
Francisco Donoso: Yeah, that's
really. Yeah.
Warren du Toit: Because I mean,
like the one does the one and
the one does the other, but
they're essentially trying to
achieve the same results.
They're trying to find a way to
prevent the person from getting
in, right? Because obviously,
you're not talking in context of
a blackhead. Now, you're not
talking about hackers trying to
do evil. You're talking about
two teams trying to achieve the
same goal.
Francisco Donoso: Yeah, I think
what you're seeing now is more
and more of the answer is yes.
Previously not so much enough.
I've had the opportunity now to
be on both sides of the coin,
and I love them both. Prior to
joining klc security, I spent
some time at a company that was
trying to build an automated red
team, and that was some of the
most fun I've ever had in my
career. That's where I had to
learn Kubernetes To figure out
how to have a security
environment where we literally
had zero and it's like we
literally had millions of
dollars of zero days that we
developed, and I had to figure
out how to secure that using
some magic. But what I, what
I've seen is that a lot of red
teams from like your traditional
cyber security vendors, they
really just feel like they're
there to beat up the blue team,
right? It just feels like sort
of a bully coming in and say,
Look at how bad you are, you
suck. You didn't find any of
this. And that was a lot of
pervasiveness around cyber
security for a while. But now, a
lot of that attitude has luckily
shifted right where, Look, guys,
the only reason we hired you to
be a red team is to help our
blue team get better. So you
need to work together to do that
and accomplish that. And there's
some firms out there. In fact,
Walmart has some of the best Red
and Blue Team guys that I've
ever met in my entire career.
Both of their teams are
fantastic. The reason they've
succeeded so much, is because
they have this partnership where
they're just constantly
sparring. The Red Team figures
out a really novel way to go
after some part of the Walmart
environment. And then the blue
team does eventually catch them.
But it's all about, okay, well,
that's really cool. How did you
get here? And then what could I
do to potentially detect you in
this new novel way that you came
up with, literally just to break
into this environment, and just
constantly having that
collaboration, because it needs
to be a collaboration. And
what's what's really interesting
in that environment is, you
know, a red team engagement,
depending on how sophisticated
it is, could be a year long,
right? And for the first six
months of that, the blue team
may not even see anything that
the red team has done. It's all
maybe reconnaissance and
staging, to make sure that when
they break in, they have a way
to control what they've broken
into. But a lot of the value out
of that comes What did you spend
six months doing? What did you
do? Oh, you register it A domain
that looks just like mine, how
could I potentially identify
that to see if in the future,
someone else's staging something
similarly? Or, hey, I responded
in a way that actually gave you
more access. So this is
something that we saw at that
company A while ago where a blue
team when they're in an
environment where there's
potentially real breach, right,
because the goal of a red team
should be the blue team should
never be in a position where
they're like, Oh, that's just
the red team, we'll deal with it
later. They need to react as if
it is a real attacker,
constantly. And often what
happens is, for blue teams who
haven't had that experience,
they react in a way that's
actually extremely advantageous
to an attacker. An example would
be, we've had cases where a blue
team person would log into a
machine that we had compromised
using their privileged domain
account, which means Hey, now
we've got your credentials.
We've got your privileged domain
account. Thank you very much
blue team, you've made our job
significantly easier. So a lot
of it is just helping the blue
team understand how they should
react calmly, in a kind of
structured way and think about
how they're going to react to an
attacker, because reacting
correctly, could be disastrous,
right? It could give the bad
guys exactly what they need. And
we see that a lot here at klc
security and other firms where
blue teams who don't have that
experience, React poorly, and
cause unfortunately more harm
than good when they're reacting.
So I think that the most
important part of a red team
really is not just how do you
break into this environment?
That's always useful information
as a defender, but how did I as
a defender make missteps that
made it worse, and how do I
train my team to prevent that
stuff in the future?
Chris Goosen: That's
fascinating. I you know, you
were talking about the sparring
and I remember It was early last
year, I did a security training
course. And I was we were on
like a campus where we would,
you know, we there the whole day
type of thing. And then we would
have lunch, and snack breaks and
whatnot in the cafeteria on this
training campus. And the
lunchtime conversations were
worth almost more than the
course was because I mean, it
was a fantastic course. But the
lifestyle conversations were
great, because the very
backgrounds of the people that
were on this course, was
fascinating, right? We had
these, like really hardcore risk
and compliance folks. And then
we had like, you know, kind of
consultant type people like us.
And then we had really hardcore,
like red or blue team, offensive
and defensive folks, right. And
so these guys would be talking
about someone like the and many
of them represented some pretty
large and very well known
organizations. And so you hear
about the ways they try and get
in and it's not even only from a
from a you know, breaking
through network layer type
stuff, but like even just
physical security penetration
testing, right, like trying to
sneak in as a pregnant lady, or
you know, get through security,
physical security controls,
because you're pregnant, you
can't fit in, you know that all
of these like wildly crazy
concepts. So you just go people
do that and what yeah, we run
these types of operations all
the time, like, get really,
really good looking girl to come
in and try and walk back, you
know, all that type of stuff.
And it's amazing how they, you
know, they would target people
like target a particular
security guard, physical
security guard, because, you
know, maybe he has a wandering
eye. So you bring in an
attractive young lady to try and
do you know what I mean, like,
the social engineering aspect of
this is the sound of
Warren du Toit: what's what's
the end goal, right? I mean, I
think this is also quite
important, because, you know,
like, if we weren't humans, and
we didn't have freewill and they
weren't. I don't want to
swear... Pierre, I'm saving you
here, pal. And I'd like you get
really bad people. Okay, then
once certain things for certain
things, but I mean like to go
and hire someone that is going
to do that takes a lot of
planning a lot of motivation, a
lot of money to orchestrate
these sorts of social
engineering attacks and things
like that. What is the end goal?
Is it to go haha I got in or is
it more of a like, okay, we're
actually going to steal stuff.
And it's actually corporate
corporate corporate espionage
and all these conspiracy
theorists throughout the world.
were absolutely right. And
you're thinking,
Nicolas Blank: I can answer that
very quickly. For me, based on
the last three, four weeks, I
think the last four weeks we've
had three post breach requests
and my last One was from a bank,
which I will not name, who on
the basis of an email, which
came from a domain name, which
was one letter away from the
production domain. Right,
however, had all the rights spam
records in place, so SPF and
DKIM all checked out, it should
a request to accounts payable.
With and you can see how much
how long this breach has been
been in place. I'll tell you in
a second and send a request
accounts payable to say please
will you pay this amount? The
person from accounts payable
said Hang on, this looks fishy.
Should I respond to this? And
five minutes later, an email
came back from the attacking
domain saying yes, this is
correct. Go ahead and pay. And
what's even worse is that the
attacker had crafted a PDF
document With three signatures,
which they had literally
photoshopped on top of a PDF, so
at first glance, it looks
correct. But the second glance
you can see was manufactured in
the lost $400,000 on a Friday
morning.
Chris Goosen: So yeah, yeah. The
the goal, I guess is is trying
to secure all the aspects,
right, all the elements and is
this fascinating? So there's a
podcast that I listened to quite
a lot called the Darknet
diaries. And if you haven't
checked it out, well worth
listening to. One of the
episodes talks about I can't
remember the exact firm name but
a couple of guys who were hired
to do some physical penetration
testing by a government entity.
I think it was up in Iowa.
Actually, it wasn't it
definitely was a Dallas, Iowa. I
remember because I was like
downtown, and they essentially
got caught but knowingly got
caught they tripped in alarm at
a courthouse. They had managed
to get into after some recon and
whatnot. And so they waited for
the cops. And as they normally
would, you know, when the cops
come and rescue, you give them
a, you know, a document that
says we were hired to do this,
here's the signatures of other
people. But that didn't, there
was some kind of, I guess, chain
of command issue in that
process. And these guys ended up
getting arrested and prosecuted
for doing this. And it was a
pretty big, big, big deal. But
fascinating story, if you listen
to not only the things that
they've that they do, to be able
to try these things. So you
know, I guess the point I'm
making is very interesting. It's
a it's a very interesting
concept, right? The whole kind
of blue red team thing.
Nicolas Blank: Chris.
Chris Goosen: Yeah.
Nicolas Blank: I want to
challenge you on that because we
talking about companies like
Walmart writ large enough to
have written blue team, right.
And obviously, the guarding
against and this is where things
get super interesting because
companies of that size will
suffer things like nation state
attack and companies or or
should we say attackers with
literally unlimited budgets. But
what I'm finding in in customers
both large and small lately
who've been breached is that
these are not companies with
blue and red team. These are
just companies who have some
really, really basic things that
they haven't bothered doing from
a security point of view. Like
they are still susceptible to
things like password sprays,
attacks, and they're going to
cloud like office 365 that they
haven't disabled legacy awesome,
then they're surprised because
there's an attack and that's the
last right guys. Well, I'd love
for you guys now who are in the
dedicated security space to to
pass some commentary on that
way.
The.. in my mind, and I don't
mean this as a scare mongering
thing at all. Hear me, right? I
think most of the world who
doesn't have any kind of
security consciousness is so
stunning the exposed that we
actually beyond what Microsoft
says in terms of assuming breach
of trust exposed?
Chris Goosen: That's I mean,
that's a that's a great point.
And I think that's, that's part
of the reason why I think it's
important to have these types of
conversations, right? Because I
think there shouldn't be a, like
a silo between the Information
Technology Group and the
information security group
anymore like this has to become,
they have to be able to work
together a lot more than what's
what's fascinating about the
middle. No, in this is true,
right? Because what's
fascinating about the space, and
Fran has some really good data
on this as well is that
historically, the security teams
and the infosec guys go and buy
the security products separately
from the people who are buying
productivity product team,
right. And so what Microsoft is
coming in and done as well with
bundling everything together.
When the productivity team buys
em 365, they're now getting all
of the security products, right?
And so what I had seen
previously with working with
large customers is that you go
through this massive migration
program, and you're, you know,
halfway through it, and then all
of a sudden, the security guys
are like, hang on, what is this
conditional access thing you
guys are wanting to it? And why
would we involve when we told,
like, pump the brakes? Because
then they're like, well, we
don't want to use a Microsoft
Security product, or we weren't
involved in that decision. So
now we need to go and understand
what the product can do and go
through the whole due diligence
process. So there's Microsoft
that kind of tipping the space
upside down, if you will, in a
sense, because you kind of have
to, they're forcing those teams
to to work together, I think,
and I think that's where this
thing becomes really, really
fascinating. But to your point
about being exposed. One of the
things that I think is important
to mention is that especially in
the Microsoft ecosystem, those
basic security controls roles
exist, folks are just not
implementing them. Right. So
looking at MFA, like what were
the stats, something like, it's
like less than 15% of users are
actually using MFA every month.
Everyone in every tenant has the
ability to enable MFA. But not
everyone is doing it.
Francisco Donoso: That's why
included.
Chris Goosen: Yeah, exactly. And
so that's why I like Emma's we
should start every every episode
with like, interface.
Nicolas Blank: So let's try this
one over to Fran for for some
common ci, basic security stuff.
Warren du Toit: Is that such a
thing?
Francisco Donoso: There really,
there really is. I think what
you'll find is that almost every
compromised, larger small if
it's a small community bank or a
large multinational happens,
because of some small basic kind
of misconfigure ation of
technology, things that you've
already mentioned. Maybe
organization that doesn't have
any multi factor authentication,
or even enabled multi factor
authentication, but forgot about
legacy protocols that don't
support multi factor
authentication, which then gives
you access to email which you
can use to pivot as an attacker
to another, another, you know,
method of compromise, I could
trick Chris to do something on
my behalf if I have access to
Kudelski Security email as an
example. So I think that a lot
of what you see is really the
cause of this, in my mind is two
things. One, it teams are moving
really fast. And they're
constantly under immense
pressure to deliver value to an
organization, right? Because
they need to that's they're
there to enable an organization
to conduct their business.
Nobody runs an IT team just
because they love it. They're
there to enable an organization
and they're moving very fast,
and they don't have the time to
take a second and think about,
okay, well how does this change
my exposure? I'm about To go and
put this thing on the internet,
or I've just migrated to Office
365? How does that change the
way that someone could interact
with my environment? And that's
where a red team comes in,
right? Because a lot of the
defensive guys or even just it
guys, they don't know what they
don't know. They don't know how
a system can be misused. And the
reason that hackers or attackers
are so successful is because
they're, honestly all the time
just being creative. How could I
use this thing for what it
exactly was not intended to do
on my behalf to be able to break
into an organization? So I think
that a lot of it is the IT team
just doesn't have the time, but
they also don't have the kind of
concept of how do I misuse this
thing to gain an advantage or
break into this organization.
And the second half, I think, is
security teams kind of all over
the place, have built this
culture where they're just the
know people. They're the people
That nobody wants to talk to,
because they're gonna cause a
project to grind to a halt.
Right? They're not there to
enable the business. They're
there to just say no, and tell
the IT team too bad, you got to
go do this all again. So I think
that, that what's really
important for any organization
is to build a culture where the
security team is an enabler to
the ITT, right? An example of
this is actually Facebook and
some of the big like Silicon
Valley companies. The security
teams are working directly with
the DevOps teams or the IT teams
to help enable security and make
their lives easier. A perfect
example from Facebook is that
Facebook security team wrote a
piece of code, a library that
enabled secure checking of
passwords, and they literally
went to the development teams
and said, Hey, you guys don't
have to worry about this
anymore. Just use this thing
that we wrote. And you don't
have to worry about it. There's
not a lot of teams that are
doing that. A lot of teams take
up backseat and they're there to
like I said, say no rather than
collaborate with a technology
team and say how do we make this
project success? successful? But
securely? So I think, really it
is a lot of companies don't have
the basics, right? Because it
administrators too busy. They
put something up, they forget
about it. Nobody does inventory.
Well, nobody, literally any
company I've ever worked for.
None of them do true inventory.
Correct. Nobody knows what they
own. But at the same time, even
if they know what they own, they
don't know how they potentially
have misconfigured it and how
that could be advantageous to an
attacker. So yeah.
Chris Goosen: So do you think
that slops just changing gears
just a little bit here, but
thinking about sort of moved on
the management side? Do you
think that there's a
misunderstanding between
organizations using a managed
service versus it with an
expectation and this happens in
the cloud to write this have
certainly ever been discussions
that I've had with folks go,
Well, I want permissive
environments a mess, but we
might, we're going to AWS or
we're going to Azure, so it's
gonna be perfect and was like,
Well, no, that's not quite how
this works. Like, you don't just
throw stuff up into the cloud.
And then now it works. Right. So
do you think there's a there's
also a bit of a misconception
that people go well, we're
moving to Microsoft, to the
Microsoft, you know, in 365,
platform, Mexican to deal with a
security now? move on? Yeah,
yeah. What are you seeing?
Right?
Francisco Donoso: I think so. I
think absolutely. I think a lot
of organizations are based at
the very beginning of cloud, if
you will, right, like
Infrastructure as a Service.
They didn't consider the shared
responsibility model, right?
They just saw, hey, I'm putting
my data in AWS now it's their
job, or I'm putting my
infrastructure in Azure. Now
Microsoft has to deal with it.
That's not the case. And I think
what you've seen is all of these
companies Microsoft and Google
and AWS have started to enable
their their customers to build
some really secure software in
some very secure environments,
essentially included right for
free and their plans are there.
They're doing a lot to enable
their clients, Microsoft with
MFA for free and all of the
security features they built
into even base enterprise plans
for office 365. But
organizations aren't taking
advantage of them. Because one
they either don't know or two,
they think it's Microsoft's
problem. The Microsoft's problem
kind of aspect has changed. I
think what you've seen in the
security industry over the last
few years is a lot of education
that just because you put your
infrastructure in AWS doesn't
mean that you're now hands off
and you have kind of no longer
responsibility for securing it.
So hopefully that seems to be
changing slowly but surely. But
at the same time, what I've seen
that's unfortunate is a lot of
traditional IT security guys.
They don't know how AWS or Azure
works, right? They don't know
how office works. So they're put
in this position where they're
familiar with maybe the on
premise, legacy way to do
things. But they also need to
learn about these technologies
to be effective at securing
them. And a lot of a lot of
organizations are enabling their
security teams to go and learn
that stuff. So they can be
effective. hopefully that
answered your question. Yeah,
that's a definite. that's a
Chris Goosen: that's a
fascinating point. Do you think?
I mean, there is obviously a
very big difference between your
traditional managed services
type business, right. And Nick,
you know a lot about managed
services. It's something that
you're involved with every day.
And then the concept of managed
security services, right. I
mean, it's it with us just
unpacking the differences, Dave,
about what, what customers
should expect when they sign up
for one or both of those things.
Because Because many security
services is very different,
right? And that's a part of your
background too. So, I mean, you
know, should we should we go
into that just a little bit? I
think that'll be fascinating
topic.
Francisco Donoso: Sure. I just
want to start by saying that
it's really interesting to me
because some of the nation state
attackers that Nick mentioned
earlier, have found that the
soft underbelly of these large
mega corpse are actually their
managed service providers. There
was a report put out, if you
google the words cloud Hopper,
it was literally about how China
or Chinese nation state actors,
were breaking into companies
like IBM or other large managed
service providers, not managed
security service providers,
because this one single company
has access to a multitude of
different environments for some
very large organizations. So
they were actually compromising
their managed service providers.
So that is Pivot into other
larger organizations, because
that may have been easier. So I
think that what you're going to
see, and what we're going to
continue to see is these really
creative, truly nation state
actors who have unlimited
resources, they're going to
target the big guys that have
access to a lot of environments
as epileps. Because that's,
that's really valuable. And what
I've seen from a traditional
managed service provider,
someone who's maybe your
outsourced helpdesk, and who's
helping you manage Active
Directory and helping you, you
know, deploy new new servers or
what have you. They typically
see security as kind of like a
full time, right, something they
have to charge their customers
extra for. And that's where this
managed Security Service
Provider space came in. And, and
what I've seen, unfortunately,
I'm going to be totally
transparent here is that a lot
of managed service providers
that are specialized in
security, so many security
service providers, are actually
detrimental to their customer
security. I've worked for a lot
of msps. And what happens is
clients hire this mssp, they no
longer feel responsible for
their own cyber security. And
the mssp is not really built to
support them in that mission,
right? They're just like, Oh,
no, that's fine that mssp will
deal with it. I don't have to
worry about and these msps a lot
of them were built in really
interesting ways. I'll give you
an example. I used to work for
an mssp organization that was
built because the company used
to sell firewalls. And one day,
a sales guy sold a lot of
firewalls. And the customer was
like, Yeah, but what if I paid
you to manage them too? And the
sales guys like Yeah, that makes
sense. We can make this
profitable, and they built this
entire mssp that just kind of
got bolted on, right? That's
like, hey, okay, well, I'm gonna
go hire some fresh out of
college kids to manage these. I
don't know if that's In
firewalls for this customer, and
it just kind of snowballed. And
what happens is these managed
security vendors, they never
take the time to think about,
okay, well, how do I actually
provide value to my customer and
defend you perspective, rather
than just managing a firewall,
or managing a web proxy or
whatever other security
technology? So truly, if I'm
being transparent, spending my
career in managed services, a
lot of managed service providers
are a detriment to their
customers. And that's, that
makes me really sad personally,
right? Because we should be
helping our customers, but most
of them, unfortunately, don't.
But I know that that wasn't
exactly what's the difference
between an MSP and an SSP and
the real differences, one of
them should hopefully be focused
on security. But, but truly, I
think a lot of organizations
need to kind of take a step back
and understand what's the
additional risk that I'm
introducing to my business by
hiring a company that will
Absolutely be targeted by threat
actors.
Warren du Toit: It's not a one
size fits all thing as well. And
I think a lot of msps sort of
fall short on that too, because
I'd say they're vendor specific.
And so vendor specific, we only
use Palo Alto or we only use
fortigate. Whatever the case
would be is, it doesn't
encompass everything. It's not
taking this broader security.
Look at it. It's more like,
Okay, well, the people that I'm
hiring know this, so they will
use that. And then what happens
is, that's what we are going to
sell to the clients. And then at
least we know that we've got our
bases covered. But the way you
do one thing in one technology
and the way you do something in
another technology are
completely different. And it's
like you said it just a little
bit earlier and moving back to
this whole intrinsic versus it
thing. And I find that's the
biggest issue that I'm exploring
Ignore the moment personally is
yes. infosec say no, because
that's their job. Understood.
But also at the same token,
they're not very helpful.
They're not very, they're more
like, how that you redo that and
come back to me when it's done.
And then I will say yes or no,
it's not like, okay, maybe we
can do it this way. Or maybe we
can do it that way or, because
they're just like, nope, come
back. Try again. As opposed to
that, that helping that you were
talking about, and I think it's
very, very important, especially
in the times where we're like,
oh, AWS does this edge. It does
that. How about we just put an
NVA and then it's the same both?
How about No, you know, what I'm
saying? And so what happens is
you end up with two MBAs vendor
specific in two separate clouds,
because you're trying to make
them The same, but in actual
fact that should be okay. Well,
there are different
technologies, but you will apply
similar principles using their
technologies and you end up
gaining and i think that's
that's, that for me is is a is a
big issue at the moment. I don't
know about you.
Chris Goosen: I think my opinion
on this is that it's very much a
cultural evolution of cloud
computing. Right. So if you
think back to when we were
deploying Exchange servers on
premises, and Nick and I worked
the project probably 15 years
ago, where this was very
evident, right? The messaging
guys only looked after the
exchange environment. Then you
had, you know, guys looking
after SharePoint firewall team,
their endpoint team yet like you
had like 20 different teams
looking after all the various
aspects of the Productivity
Suite, with Office 365 coming
in, and these things becoming
more tightly connected. I think
one of the evolutions I've seen
and certainly the organizations
that I've worked with who have
made The best strides or at
least had the best adoption of
office 365 have been companies
who have looked at this and gone
well, that structure doesn't
work. We need to have a team of
productivity people that yes,
maybe some person's skill set is
more SharePoint or teams
focused. Another person might
be, you know, identity person,
but they need to work together
to make the platform successful.
Right. I think that the next
part of this evolution is
getting the infosec teams and it
traditional IT teams working
together as well. Because at the
end of the day, like all of this
stuff has to sort of Mount
together for it to become
successful and secure
deployment, like you can no
longer look at just security as
a theme. It has to it has to be
built into everything that you
do, right as a as a default. You
know, cloud first, but I almost
want to be like new security
first, plus second, but it's
really
Warren du Toit: Oh, nice.
Francisco Donoso: Fair enough.
Yeah, I totally agree with you
on the infosec teams that IT
teams need to work together. And
I think honestly, the biggest
thing that any security team
internal to an organization can
do is be more approachable and
be willing to help more. You're
not there to say no. And the
more you say, No, the more
people will bypass you, right?
Like this. If you're just the no
guy that's gonna take a critical
project, and just halt it,
nobody's gonna come to you, and
it's gonna make it to
production, and you won't even
know it exists. And a lot of a
lot of a lot of security guys
just make that mistake where
they're hired top of the tower,
and they're just the people who
get to say, we do it or no, go
do it this way. But at the same
time, a lot of what I've seen
personally, is some of the older
traditional security guys. Maybe
they're not familiar with AWS at
all, or maybe they've never even
written an application, right? A
lot of what we're transitioning
to is, hey, there's a lot of
custom development going around.
There's a lot of DevOps going
around. There's a lot of how do
I deploy things to cloud with
like something like terraform,
right. And the security teams
have never use these tools. So
they're in a position where
maybe they have, I don't know, a
vulnerability scanning tool, and
they get the report and they go
tell the developer, hey, go fix
this, but they don't even know
how to fix it themselves. And I
think that's the most important
part of being a security
practitioner, is sure, you
should be aware of how attackers
are breaking in and maybe you
should be aware of security best
practices. But maybe, just
maybe, you should be aware of
how to use the technology that
you're trying to protect.
Because unfortunately, I've seen
a lot of security guys who have
never deployed anything to AWS
or never deployed anything to
Azure. And I think Some of the
biggest value that I've ever
found, is putting myself in
operational positions where I
have to figure out, I'm an
operations guy now or I'm an IT
guy now, how do I deploy this?
And then how would I secure it?
So I really hope that what we
see as a transition, as we're,
as a security kind of community
that we begin transitioning to,
hey, I'm not just here to tell
people don't do this, or go redo
it. I need to learn about the
technologies, I need to test it
myself. I need to try it myself.
And then I need to collaborate
with the IT team based on what
I've learned to make them
successful and make the business
successful. Because no company
other than cybersecurity
companies is in the business of
security. Security is a business
enabler and a risk reducer.
Nobody does security because
they want to be secure. Truly,
nobody. They're all there to
enable the business
Warren du Toit: There's the
title of the episode.
Chris Goosen: That was just
thinking that actually, I. So I
think a couple of thoughts I
have on that which is, which is
kind of interesting. And he kind
of brought up here is one of the
things I've, I've learned in my
time and you know, the three of
us spend a lot of our time in
the community doing community
stuff writing vlogs, that vast
majority of the last 10 years,
for me, at least have been spent
doing that for Nick, it's, you
know, even longer than that. And
there's definitely a difference
in the community interactions
between, you know, infosec,
folks, and then just your
traditional IT pro people,
right. And you it's very evident
if you, if you go on Twitter,
and you look at and I think it's
changing, I think the younger
generation of infosec people are
becoming more community focused
at least about kind of sharing
things and being open to just
contributing to the community
and taking and give it's a give
and take relationship, right.
But I certainly have found that
there are there's a very guarded
approach. In the community in
the infosec community, in many
aspects, I think, you know,
we've we've been very welcoming
of inclusivity in the in the IT
pro community, I think it's and
dev community Sorry, I always
say it Pro, but I always include
the dev guys into that as well,
because, you know, it's very
much part of it. Microsoft did a
great job of that inclusivity
message. But I find that that's
still lacking a little bit
somewhat in, in infosec. And if
you look at, you know, I follow
a few female infosec pros on
Twitter, and if you look at the
abuse that they get from men in
particular, it's disgusting,
actually. And I'm actually proud
that that doesn't really happen
in the Microsoft community. But
that, you know, it saddens me
that that's still happening. And
I think as a community, these
things need to also be addressed
Because ultimately, we all have
the same goal here at the end of
the day, right, which would you
know, as Fran said, it's about
enabling productivity and
reducing risks. Right. And
collectively,
Warren du Toit: I just want to
jump in the creek and I want to
say like, are you guys not
stressed? lack? Because if a
hack happens, right, whose fault
is it? So we hired you guys to
fix this problem and we got
hacked. So why infosec so grumpy
is because they know that it's
their ass on the line if
something goes wrong, and I
don't know if I'd be able to
sleep at night, if that was, you
know, my thing.
Chris Goosen: I can tell you
from experience that I know Fran
doesn't sleep at night.
Francisco Donoso: Well, I think
that honestly. Yes and no. I
think that most of the really
good security people that I know
Have this in the back of their
minds with everything that they
do. Right, which, which drives
them to be successful, which
means they need to understand
the technologies that they're
scared. They need to have very
strong relationships with the
development teams and IT teams
and the infrastructure teams. So
I think yes or no, I think what
you'll find is that a lot of
traditional security people will
kind of sit back and say, I told
you, so I told you this was
going to happen. You didn't
listen to me. And and never take
a moment to reflect and say,
have I personally built a
culture where nobody wants to
talk to me? So maybe that's why
they didn't listen to me. Or
have I built a culture where if
a team comes to me, I'm going to
tell them no, so they're just
gonna bypass me and put it on
the internet anyway, is that not
my responsibility? It's not my
job, and I fall. So I think that
a lot of what you see from
traditional security folks,
unfortunately, is I told you
this was gonna happen. He just
didn't listen to me. So I, I
hope that there's a mixture of
that, but some of the best
security folks that I know
absolutely we, we stay up at
night thinking about oh my god.
Okay, so how do I make this
better? And a lot of how do I
make this better is not
technology, it's relationships
and it's building a community
and it's working closely with
teams outside of security. And a
lot of people don't do that
retrospection. Right. They don't
think about, well, why didn't
anybody tell me about this
project? Is it because maybe
I've just I'm not good to talk
to when I when I
Warren du Toit: say no, that's
Francisco Donoso: exactly,
exactly, exactly. So I think. I
hope that some of that is
changing in the community, but I
don't know. And then also
really, the reality is, a lot of
security vendors, unfortunately,
have started selling these snake
oil, easy solutions. Just buy
this thing. It has machine
learning. It has AI it uses The
cloud, it'll just solve all your
problems. Security is super
hard. And you need to be
methodical, and you need to be
detail oriented. And I've never
until now, where we had the
opportunity to build a managed
service practice that I'm proud
of, truly, I've never worked for
a security company that
literally sat our customers down
and said, Okay, this is going to
be really hard. But we're here
to work with you. It's going to
take six months to really make
sure we understand your business
and make sure we methodically
approach how we're going to
secure your environment. Every
other security vendor, every
other security guys like rapid
time to value, buy this product,
it solves every problem. That's
never the answer. That never
works. And some of the most
disillusionment that I've had
personally as a cyber security
person who truly loves like the
security, world and technology
and I love learning about things
is that There's so many security
vendors that are just selling
snake oil, and they're just
peddling stuff that they know it
doesn't work, but they're giving
their customers a false sense of
security. And it's just so
disillusioning, like honestly, I
don't know if this is the same
for other parts of the IT world
because I've been in security so
long. But I just constantly feel
that if I go to like some of the
business conventions within
cybersecurity like RSA, I just
walk around this space, where
vendors are just selling stuff
that they know doesn't work. And
I don't know how those people
sleep at night, right? Like, I
don't know that and I don't know
if this is a systemic problem in
technology, or if cyber security
companies are just like pretty
scummy, in general, most of them
Chris Goosen: i think i've seen
we've definitely seen our fair
share of that type of stuff in
the migration space right
wherewhat you know, the
expectations beingset by By
migration vendors and or and or
consultant consultancy companies
who who do migrations don't
always meet their own match the
reality of the of it right? All
of this is seamless, your users
won't even know. Like, yeah, I
mean, is that really true? Like
it, you know, there's always
going to be some, when you
undertake a migration project of
any sort, there's always going
to be some pain and hassle with
users. Right. And I think that's
also why the whole
organizational change management
movement is has accelerated as
much as it has. And you know,
we've had some great ocm guests
on the show previously, but so I
think that exists everywhere.
But you know, it's a good point.
And I think just, again, just
honest, honesty and transparency
is just, it's important in every
part of, you know, the way we do
business, how we interact with
our customers. And it's an
important thing, we can't lose
sight of that, right.
Nicolas Blank: I hate to be that
guy, but I've got to be that
guy.
Warren du Toit: So I think we
could have gone on for hours dud
, but thought it has to happe
Nicolas Blank: But before we go,
I'd like for him to leave our
listeners with. Okay, I've heard
the stuff and I'm really worried
I'm not gonna sleep tonight.
Yeah.
Warren du Toit: Always please.
Nicolas Blank: What if if I am
a, this is valid right back
down. I'm a I'm an overall
system. I could be a developer
could be an IT pro could be a
business person, I could be a C.
So I've heard all the stuff.
I've heard the show. I'm
thinking I'll quit my job.
Instead of quitting my job. What
are the one two or three or
something tangible? What can I
do? Now? What could I do
tomorrow? What can I do to be
safer?
Francisco Donoso: Yeah, I'll
start with the one thing that
nobody does correctly.
inventory, the most unsexy We
think in security, but the most
valuable. So please, whatever
you're doing, try to figure out
a way to automate inventory, you
need to know what you have to
know what you need to protect.
The other things that I'll say,
are all of these vendors,
Microsoft, AWS, Google, they've
spent a significant amount of
effort and time and money,
building security best
practices, and enabling your
business and your developers and
your teams to do things in their
environments and their cloud
securely. So just take a moment
and just go through and read
some of the fantastic
documentation that all of these
vendors have around security
best practices. Maybe before you
go and roll out office 365 or
you go to Azure. Just take a
moment and read what those best
practices are, and familiarize
yourself with how attackers are
attacking. And then finally, I
would say, help build security
teams or hire consultants who
are familiar with the technology
that you're trying to protect.
That's, that's really important.
As you look to transition to the
cloud or to these environments,
you need to have security
professionals who have actually
used the technologies that
you're trying to protect. Either
in their personal time in the
lab, it doesn't matter. But
whoever you're hiring, either
internally or externally, make
sure they've used it, make sure
they've deployed a, you know, an
easy to instance or Azure VM or
whatever. So that they can help
you understand how your team can
secure some of those
environments. Hopefully, that
helps. But really, those are the
three things that I would
inventory. Nobody doesn't,
right. Please try to do that. If
you're going to the cloud fresh,
figure out how to do automated
inventory, all of these, all of
these cloud platforms have a way
Do inventory in one way or
another across subscriptions or
accounts, try to use that as
much as possible
Warren du Toit: Taggling, man
just tag everything stay for a
reason.
Chris Goosen: That's very,
that's very insightful. I think,
you know, in many instances,
the, the attacker knows the
platform better than you do.
Right? So you really need to
spend the time making sure that
you actually understand what
what you what we're working with
here. So that's, that's awesome.
Fran, it's been awesome talking
to you as always. And before we
go, is there anything that we
can would that you would want to
plug? I'm not sure how active
you are on social media, things
like that. But if there's any
way you know if you want to put
that out there now feel free to
do that now. Guys, any closing
thoughts from you?
Francisco Donoso: Yeah, I'll
just say, hey, nothing really to
plug my Twitter handle is
@Francisckrs. ridiculous to
find. Don't worry about it. Make
sure that Chris has a link to
it. But it's been a pleasure,
guys. It's been a blast. I
really enjoyed talking to you
and I hope to be able to do it
again.
Warren du Toit: Oh, yes, yeah.
Everyone, before you go, we just
wanted to say thank you for
listening. We really enjoy
putting this podcast together
for you every two weeks, please
visit us at thearchitects.cloud.
Alternatively, drop us a tweet.
We'd love to hear what you have
to say at @thecloudarch.