Chris Goosen: Welcome to the
cloud architects podcast, a
podcast about cloud technology,
and the people using it.
Nicolas Blank: The cloud
architects podcast is sponsored
by Kemp technologies. Choose
Kemp to optimize your multi
cloud application deployments
and simplify multi cloud
application management. A single
pane of glass for application
delivery, Kemp provides a 360
degree view of your entire
application environment, and
even third party ADCs. Download
Kemp 360 for free today at
Kemptechnologies.com
Warren du Toit: Hello,
everybody, and welcome to the
post apocalyptic version of the
cloud architects podcast. And we
have a new co host today. Anna
Chu! Welcome back.
Anna Chu: Hey.
Warren du Toit: And again, we
have the amazing little
wonderful the stupendous, Mr.
Nicolas Blank: Nicholas blank.
I was I was waiting. I waited
too long. I think I ruined the
theatrical effect, but I gotta
say that new Chris is a lot
better looking than the old
Chris. Ah,
Warren du Toit: that's for sure.
That's what you're gonna
say, Maxie. Same accent story.
Anna Chu: Is it? I don't know.
I've been told it sounds a bit
strange that people ask me if
I'm British people.And people
ask me.Yeah, but
Nicolas Blank: it's a South
African if I was from Spain.
True Story.
Anna Chu: Oh la la
Nicolas Blank: la compadre.
settled there differences in the
accent between that one and this
one. But now we got to roll with
it.
Anna Chu: Well, I am very proud
to be your fit like her horse
today. I'm not sure how this is
gonna go or it might turn to
crap. But Oh, well. Let's roll
with it.
Warren du Toit: Let's go with
it.
Cool. So what are we going to
talk about today, I think I
think something really important
is we can talk about I'm not
going to say post apocalyptic
again, because and it's just
going to mess things up. But
let's let's go post Ignite. And
we look at the technology that
Microsoft has brought to the
fold for CES. And so using
innovations that Microsoft I
consider what react is and has
done with inspire ignite ready,
bold. And I'm going to be using
proceeds. That's a big deal.
Anna Chu: That's a huge deal.
Yeah, yeah, the event team has
done a lot of work and they're
really, you know, bullish and
proving themselves. So I'm,
yeah, I'm really interested in
those down. Of course, us as
Microsoft were a little bit more
forgiving of our own technology.
We drink our own Kool Aid.
trigger on champagne. Is that
was that the time? Um, so yeah,
I wonder if, how if What if
we're really ready for primetime
with CES, I have high hopes, I
definitely think that the team
will do pull out all the stops
to make see is an awesome event
and what a great way to like
actually be a partner for
events, right? Like CES is a is
a was already. I think there was
a year that Microsoft decided
not to be part of CES for
whatever reason. But I think
it's a lot better to actually be
the one pairing the event
instead of just being Hey, we're
gonna be like a major partner
and showcasing our product. But
we're actually living it through
through the event itself, which
is really cool.
Warren du Toit: That's super
cool. And when it comes to I
mean, just just your personal
question is, are you looking
forward to anything at CES?
Anna Chu: I havenever really
been involved because CES is
typically consumer thing. I've
always worked in the
commercials. Yes.
So I if I ever, like the only
time I ever look at CES is just
as an observer, just as someone
who's interested in, you know,
what's happening in the Xbox
world or Surface devices or any
other, you know, mobile mobile
devices, right. Um, for me, like
I've been spending a lot of time
with online events. And I went
to Adobe max last week. I've
been going to see to Montreal
for the last two years and this
is the first time that they've
done a completely online event.
For those of you who don't know
what C to Montreal is, it's a
collaboration between the month
Getting agency for Cirque du
Soleil called Sibley and another
company I can't remember. But
it's all about the collaboration
between creativity and commerce.
And so they always do a great
job of getting amazing speakers.
And really great immersive
experiences. So I was really
curious how they would do that
with everything being online. I
mean, how immersive Can you be
when you're at the same desk
that you read email and do teams
calls, you know, but they got
had some workshops, and one even
involve me walking out of my
house, and observing like, like
noticing what really stood out
for me. And I think in this age
of, you know, we're still in
pandemic work mode. More, and I
know that, when we were talking
earlier, you were saying that
you will starting to feel a bit
fatigued from working from home
for a while. So like, you do
need to get outside and sick get
exposed to a completely
different environment in order
for you to, you know, not only
like stay sane and preserve your
mental health, but just, you
know, just for a little bit of
relief, right?
Warren du Toit: Yeah, hundred
percent Look, I mean, I guess,
we've tried to replicate the
stuff that it is that we do on a
daily basis, but from home, so,
you know, got a gym, or you have
a spinning machine or I don't
know, you know, just those
little things that you try to
replicate. I mean, the kids, you
know, joining meetings and sort
of virtual, virtual and Roblox
games and things like that. But
you're right. I mean, there's,
there's only so much that you
can mean, there's some sort of
interaction that sort of has to
happen, but it's not, you can't
necessarily get
Nicolas Blank: away actually,
you get such digital fatigue,
that you don't care, you don't
care about how amazing the
content is, you get to the point
where I just want to be in the
same room as another human
being, and talk to them and see
them and see the the pale blue
blue light of another screen.
Anna Chu: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, it's really it's, it's
really, really tough. And I
think we've said it many times
that COVID-19 is kind of like
everyone's digital
transformation officer, I
everyone's had to like, be
pushed into digital, kicking and
screaming and set. The same
applies for online events. And
one thing I've been thinking
about is, have the objectives of
events changed. Because now that
we move to online, let's think
about this, right? As I look at
the metrics for ignite 2020. And
compare that to our metrics for
2019. We, in person event, we
looked at things like how many
people turn up? How many
registrations do we get? We
looked at things like that, now,
Warren du Toit: we're completely
blown up.
Anna Chu: Yeah, totally blown
out. Like, like, like, a lot.
I'm, like, 10 times just a
little under 10. x, you know,
just crazy. But there's a couple
of things behind that we might
be event free. And typically
ignite, you have to pay like two
grand also, to for the price of
admission. We've also looked at,
you know, session scans to get a
sense of like, how many people
actually attended sessions?
Well, when you are logging in
to, to a session, right? Is that
person really there is not a
captive audience a distracted
by, like, they could have three
other tabs open on their
browser, that, yeah, it'd be a
source of distraction, let alone
what's happening in their home.
Now, you could also argue that,
you know, we weren't able to
capture people walking out of
those rooms. But as someone who
used to stand by that door,
didn't really I mean, you just
have like, maybe 10 1215
depending on the room, like
really point 01 percent of the
people in the room. But
attention spans really
difficult. And the other thing
too, is something that is been
really on my mind is these
events have always been
technical training events,
right? So how do we do this
online when people's attention
spans are so limited? And I
mean, you you've seen this at
Ignite, like, we've always done
like 45 minutes, 75 minutes
session breakouts. We didn't do
that for our online event. Like
we did 20 minutes, 30 minute
things. So is that going to help
people get the technical depth
that they need to be successful
in their jobs? I'm really
interested in how technical
training organizations pivoting
like have you guys seen
anything? Have you guys seen
major changes? They're
Warren du Toit: not really not
not remind me look Hi. For me
it's also an there's an
excitement factor. I'm going to
the the person who led the
session afterwards, and having a
chat to them saying that was
amazing or seeing what sort of
shirt they were wearing, because
I suppose he gave you some sort
of indication of what the kind
of person what that person was
like. Whereas now, let's say
it's pre recorded. They're
wearing a shirt that Microsoft
told them to it, or how
rehearsed wasn't actually. Um,
so it was, I think leading to my
next question is when it comes
to the virtual table sessions
and the social virtual sessions
that you tried to have it
ignited at work?
Anna Chu: Yeah, I'll tell you
what Hawks. Um, yeah. Last time,
when we spoke, I was talking
about how it was a bit of an
experiment. I thought it went
really well. The feedback that
we got from the table talks was
like, Oh, my gosh, I could have
sat in these table talks all
day, we had repeat customers, we
had people coming back, like
Table to Table Talk, I had my
coffee, I woke up early stayed
up late in order to be part of
as many of them as I could. And
people really love the free
flowing conversation. They've
really loved that, you know,
they had a place where they
could have that hallway
conversation, that you typically
have big conferences. And while
they was an agenda, it was super
loose. It was more like, hey,
like, this is going to be a
table talk about application
development. Got a couple of
people here, like, let's find
out in the room, like what
people are interested in
building what you're building
right now. You know, just have a
chat, though. The main complaint
I had was that 30 minutes is too
short. And I agree with that.
I'm sorry, I'm hoping we can
expand that. I'm very interested
in like, any advice or any tips
that people might have. So any
listeners to this podcast, just,
you know, message me on on
Twitter, at underscore HQ, if
you've got any ideas of how
you've seen networking done
well, especially a really big
events, right, like, like, the
Ignite reached like hundreds of
thousands of people. So trying
to do intimate networking can be
very difficult. But I'm very
excited about Microsoft Teams
and the breakout room
functionalities. And maybe we
can do it that way. Yeah, yeah,
that would be really fun. I see
online events to and they have
used the breakout room
functionality. I think the
difference the challenge with
that from from that event is
that not everyone went into the
breakout rooms like me included
guilty, because I was planning
on just passively listening. And
so if you were pushing l had
allocated, he would go into
breakout rooms, some would be
more full than others. So I
don't know, it's just one of
those things that we need to
take into consideration.
Nicolas Blank: You realize you
celebrating something that was
successful there? And it was
because it had interaction? And
we weren't just being statically
presented at? And yeah, that's
sweet. We love interacting. And
we had a conference and we
weren't just watching slide off
the slide off the slide deck by
Anna Chu: Yeah, yeah. Yeah, it
was a, I think it was the best
solution for Yes, what you said
there, like driving interaction
and connections. I have no idea
whether people like started
connecting with other people in
that check table talk one on one
afterwards. I don't have a way
of measuring that. Nor do I want
to, like be so you know, big
brother about it. Right? Like,
we kind of have to leave things
to be organic. So yeah, um, but
we shall say, Oh, I also did one
in Japanese Actually, I didn't
personally but I was like, you
know, what, like, the people
community is also very local.
Right? And with the Japanese,
they need to connect with people
who speak their language.
English is not their mother
tongue, right? Or something that
they feel super comfortable
speaking in, and so interact
like, so they won't feel 100%
comfortable interacting in, in a
in a format like that, where the
predominant language is English.
And so I sat in on the the
Japanese one. I don't understand
a lick of Japanese, but I just
observed and people will, like,
turn the cameras on. They turn
the cameras on. They unmuted
themselves. It was awesome. You
know, like, I think, like, if
you look at all the sessions, we
did, we did breakouts, We did
them in in teams live events,
you had the interaction in the
chat, you didn't see anyone's
faces. Like, one thing I did,
and I kept doing it was I turned
on together mode for myself,
took a screenshot of that, paste
it in the chat window. And but
and of course, if people don't
know, or you don't turn on
together mode for everybody, you
do it for yourself. So you can
see everyone in that beautiful
format. And so it was a little
bit, it was two things. One, I
was showcasing a feature of
teams through Table Table, as a
good corporate citizen and a fan
of Microsoft Teams. And
secondly, I was really
motivating people to actually
turn on the cameras unmute their
microphone, so they can see
themselves in together mode, and
start and stop just giving them
a little signal, say, Hey, this
is the permissible thing to do,
you don't have to, but if you
want to be involved in this way,
you know, join in. So I think
you have to like Softly, softly
let people feel comfortable.
With an interactive mode, like I
learned a lot from doing
unconferences in the in person
event 2019. Certainly some
people gave us feedback that
there were some dominant voices
and dominant personalities,
which is fine. But you have to
make sure that as a facilitator,
you acknowledge that and play a
role in pivoting and making sure
that everybody has a chance to
speak if they want the
opportunity, you know, so I
think we did a really good job
of using technology to to
advantage to facilitate who
Warren du Toit: at least it
other than us, you know, how you
get these common meeting
mistakes, or the common things
that happened inside of meetings
or like you're on mute. Or you
know, your cameras or whatever
the case may be is which leads
me to the next thing is who runs
Microsoft Instagram, because
that's, that is hilarious.
Instagram, it's really funny.
It's like, something you haven't
heard in three hours, or
whatever the case is, and it's
always like this, this random
meme about something bad you do.
What's the funniest thing you've
done on a meeting? Like in the
last month?
Anna Chu: Ah, I've been using
the snap snap camera filters are
using playing with that. I
actually have and I could put a
cat on my head on it. Let me see
if I could do I could miss a cat
one as a whole bunch of them. I
could I haven't done anything. I
have Oh, this one's gonna be
interesting. Oh my gosh, I can
be a on this is going away. Oh,
look, I'm a Halloween bride.
This better make the blooper
reel.
Nicolas Blank: I'm not so sure
about the blooper reel. I think
this is gonna make mainstream.
Warren du Toit: mainstream.
Anna Chu: Yes. I mean, look at
this. Look at these cheekbones.
It looks amazing. I haven't know
I feel like I'm pretty good at
teams etiquette. And I think I
don't know why it's just been
drilled into me to, you know,
oh, one thing I will say I don't
think it's so much mistakes. I
think using teams to have
meetings is just has really
helped introverts because if
that like this couple of things.
One, the raise hand feature is
excellent. Because, yes. You
know, Nicole with 2050 people,
and you just can't get a word in
edgewise. So the right hand
features is great for that.
Also, you can see through too
intense as someone is trying to
say something because you can
see that little avatar profile
picture like flash purple. So
hey, like there's audio being
detected on their microphone. So
maybe they're trying to say
something. And so if you
visually you see that you like,
hey, Nate, do you want to do it
looks like you have something?
Nicolas Blank: I'm sorry. Thank
you. Yes.
Anna Chu: quesion All right.
There we go.
Um, so yeah, I think it's been
really good in driving people
to, you know, be more inclusive
of all the different voices in
the room. Yeah, yeah. Um,
Warren du Toit: You want to say
something?
Nicolas Blank: Well, you know,
for the fact that you're looking
so blue today, wine, I don't
know what you've done with your
camera. But don't do it again.
It's fine. You know what we can
talk and calibrated afterwards?
Magic?
So yeah, we keep on talking
about COVID and the success of
Ignite. And what is the next one
gonna look like was ignite never
going to end because we used to
have a show called ignited
chirp. So what do we have not we
have an everlasting ignite
Anna Chu: FCM never ending story
No, um,
Nicolas Blank: do we even one?
Is ignite still special if it
never ends?
Anna Chu: Yeah, I well okay
this.is it's coming, there is
gonna be another ignite
happening in March. That's all I
can communicate in terms of time
frame right now. So
Warren du Toit: you heard it
here, folks all much.
Anna Chu: I think where what the
future of digital events will be
interesting. I don't really nor
we one thing that is very clear
from the conversations we've
been having the planning team is
we want to do more to drive
local engagement. I mentioned
the experiment we did with a
Japanese Table Talk. And we
certainly want to do more to
reach out to our Asia Pacific
audiences, because I think they
felt a little left out with the
English centric content just
fine. We just need to do a
better job of reaching people in
different languages, right. And
that's inclusive of Spanish,
French, German, Brazilian
Portuguese, whatever it may be,
right. So we want to do more of
that. And perhaps we need and
but it's just not, it's not just
the language thing, like
localization is about translated
the tire experience. And like, I
website, the Register button,
like the clothes cache,
everything, it's a lot more than
just the content. So and also
culturally, for some coaches,
like they need that. I haven't
delved deep into this. But we
need to consider cultural
differences as well. It's not
just a straight up AI language
translation. chozo isn't
perfect, either. So we're
thinking about that. Um, but I
think something I was alluding
to earlier, in terms of, you
know, the content now being
shorter. And technical
readiness, we also have to think
about on demand event strategy,
too, because going back to what
you were saying, around fatigue.
And this, there's a lot of
content and to expect people to
tune in for like eight hours
straight, 12 hours straight,
2448 hours straight is not
really healthy. So we want to
motivate people to go at their
own pace, especially when the
content gets very technically
deep, like level 300 400 level,
right? I've been thinking about
that. So there's an on demand
piece of that. But how many
times like would you also be
motivated to go if that was pre
recorded, and there was no one
there to like guide you. So I'm
thinking about interaction
styles to there's a lot to think
about. Um, I know that in the
last podcast we did together
talking about ignite, we were I
was using the analogy of
television for our content,
which is very true, like we had
to operate like this clockwork.
But is that at compromising? The
longer form content that people
need to help them be better
developers? Better IT
professionals? Right. So yeah,
curious on your on your thoughts
about, you know, how we could,
you know, still help people get
hands on with technology in this
work from home setting, you
know? Yeah. But on that, on
that, I will say we launched a
new feature, and I was I
couldn't talk about it. Now,
last episode. In the tech
community, it's the video hub.
So we've got hundreds of videos
and interactive demos. So click
through demos. So that kind of
talks to a little bit of
technical readiness. If you go
to the tech community tech
community.microsoft.com, and
garter the top navigation cord
community hubs, we have a new
video and you'll see lots of
video content. And also if you
you know love SharePoint love
Azure and you go to the actual
as you can community hub
SharePoint community hub, you'll
see the latest videos that have
come in from the video have
served up to you on that landing
page. So you don't have to like
go specifically to the video hub
to find it, we will recommend
content view based on the
community hub you're in. So
that's a new feature that we
pushed out to hopefully help
people with getting familiar
with with, you know, the new
announcements and the new
products and new features
coming. So yeah, yeah. So we're
always ever expanding the
features that we have on the
tech community.
Nicolas Blank: And it's a double
edged sword, though, because the
content is fantastic, not taking
away from that, I think we've
gone from, because in physical
events, we had the constraints
of what we could do physically
in terms of walking from one
session to another. And I could
only physically talk to so many
presenters and look at the T
shirts per day. And I feel like
from a content point of view,
we've gone from ignite, which
was the fire hose to a digital
only format, which is now
several sets of tidal waves. And
I don't think we need to
navigate there, we don't have
the guidance that says, in your
role in your job in your
persona. This is how much or how
little you need to do what you
need to do.
Anna Chu: Yeah, like, Are you
saying you don't know what the
minimum you know, table stakes
are to be a certain level of
certain expertise.
Nicolas Blank: I'm saying this
so much content that I could if
I just look at the the folks
that are followed from the the
Azure group, the Azure AD group
and office 365 group. And I
could do nothing but consume
content, eight hours a day,
excluding the stuff that has
been added to community. And
then there's the video content,
which I play at normal speed,
and I don't fast forward, plus
some of the most amazing
podcasts that are out at the
moment. Like, I don't have
enough hours in my day to
consume content and work.
Anna Chu: Hmm, yes. Yes, that's
very true.
Warren du Toit: hasn't been
hasn't always been like that,
though. Like, because now you
just
Nicolas Blank: multiply Oh,
Warren du Toit: yeah, but you're
forced to consume it that way.
Now, because if we had to have
sort of a said, we have to think
back a little bit you'd ignore
could be your week of lateness
from work. But now what happens
is you've got that sort of
context switching that has to
happen sort of, in between, so I
completely understand what
you're saying. But also at the
same token, we, like we were
forced to take those days and
dedicate them to something,
whereas now you don't. And
maybe, maybe that's our issue is
I mean, like, I know, you know,
as if he, they, they say quite a
bit is make time for your, your
personal learning and your
growth and, you know, you know,
like, sort of take time out of
the day, because they understand
exactly how many meetings
somebody will put in your
calendar if they could. So maybe
that's something that we, we
suppose need to say, Okay, well,
can we just break out like a two
hour? I mean, is it possible,
you break out two hours in your
day and say, Okay, well, this is
exactly what I'm gonna look at.
Um, so the fire hose becomes
just a little bit smaller. We
have to adapt to, I suppose. But
it's like you say, you, you are
limited to physically, you
walked into the room, and that
was where you were for that
hour. So maybe that's what you
sort of need to do, I guess?
Nicolas Blank: Yeah, I'd like
some, some guidance on this so
that we could share with like,
we've had to teach digital
netiquette. Right. So don't
Yeah, don't schedule an
appointment for an hour and a
half or an hour. Because you
know, people need space to be
human. So make it 45 minutes.
Yeah, those are skills that we
we don't naturally have, because
the calendars and an hour block.
It'd be good if we could give
some guidance in terms of how
did you laugh in digital age
where there's so much content,
but at the same time, I still
need to do my day job. But the
content is really very relevant
to my job. But I can't spend 12
hours a day consuming content
and I can't spend 12 hours a day
doing my job because neither one
is actually healthy. And then I
work from home. My life is a
mess. COVID Yeah. 2020 about
Anna Chu: Yeah, yeah. So taking
the an out the fire hose
analogy. You got to lay it
pipes. Right and evaluate it.
You got to figure out like hey,
like how, where am I going to
divide my time, your time is
like a pie chart. And you figure
out how much time you want to
spend with your family, how much
time you want to spend with
work, and then you and how much
time you want to spend on
learning. And figure out, you
know, what that looks like in
your day. Like exercise as well.
And that's us. Like I, I feel
one thing I've I'm trying to do,
and I fall off the wagon, every
so often is prioritize workouts
in the morning. So this morning,
I did my workout I, I'm using an
app, and it makes me do a bunch
of, you know, things today on
Monday was like, but you know, I
did it, and I feel so much
better for it. I worked out, I
took my shower, I got ready, I
turned on my camera did this
podcast. And you have to when
you when I say lay your pots, it
also is another way of saying
define your boundaries. So if
you are wanting to work nine to
five, it is strictly nine to
five, you do not take a meeting
at eight, you do not take a
meeting at six. That is like
that is when you work. And I
think Don does this really well
don't asaka a lot of people, I
encourage everyone to like be
very clear on your boundaries
and do not do not make
exceptions unless it really is
an exception. Exceptional
situation. But then like, then
you've got things in lieu. So if
you are going to take that 8am
meeting then you finished up at
four. Right? You've got you are
in control of your and your
calendar. So stick to it.
Nicolas Blank: That's good.
Scrap brass. Yeah.
Anna Chu: Yeah. And also, like
go back to like, your, your New
Year's resolutions. I know, it
was very weird back, like, you
know, pre COVID. But, um, like I
had a mission to read more books
to see. And I know, it's very
vague. And I'm definitely
reading more books than I did
the previous year. But I have
like, I'm actually refinishing
them. Can you believe I never
used to finish books. But if you
have goals for yourself, set
aside time to achieve them.
Whether it is like to be
healthier or to like ferociously
read more. allocate time to do
it. Because if you don't
prioritize time and actually
plan to do it, you will never
get it done. Something else will
always steal your time. It's
usually work.
Nicolas Blank: Yeah.
Anna Chu: Still still more of a
time than any email? Yeah,
email,
Warren du Toit: emails, terrible
emails thing for me. Yeah, email
is one thing I'm always behind.
I know what
Anna Chu: I turned off my email
notifications. And I've done
that for the last five years,
and I've never looked back.
Like, it doesn't make a
difference. You don't? Like,
what's the point? What's the,
like, you're also setting bad
examples if you are responding
immediately. Right.
Warren du Toit: Like for sure.
It's a very good point.
Anna Chu: Yeah, yeah, like 4am
in the morning. 1am in the
morning, what are some
ridiculous out like you also
causing anxiety, other personnel
around who thinks Oh, shit,
like, I shouldn't be doing this?
I should be responding. I should
be working. No, no. I think we
all have a responsibility to
drive better work life balance
to everybody. And sadly, you
know, if you're causing work for
someone, you are causing someone
else's anxiety, too. So
Nicolas Blank: Wow. I think this
has been the deepest show that
we've done for a while.
Anna Chu: Hey, why don't we
Warren du Toit: take away a
whole bunch of things? Yes.
Like, do not email me tweet it.
Anna Chu: And I will respond to
when I want to when I wake up
set notifications on my Twitter
either because it was a point
where I'm like, I'm getting
inundated. I do not want to like
be like a squirrel and just
like, just Sure. Attention to
like the latest thing someone
tweeted at me. I don't need
that. I'm, like away.
Warren du Toit: Which I guess is
another question that we could
we could probably pose since
we're on this subject is the
subject of social media. Oh,
yeah. And has has the social
media effect changed? Because,
and obviously, in some ways,
it's the only way that you can
communicate with those peers or
those people that you would see,
but have people become more
liberal now. And Is it like,
every single morning somebody
wakes up and they post a photo
of something that they would
have never had done post? I
mean, previous before code. So
like, you know, they would get
to the office and then they tell
somebody about it. But now that
they're not going to the office,
they're telling the whole world
about it. And then it says, Have
you noticed there's been like a
slight shift in who's posting
what and why they're posting it.
And I posted this, I think, to
be perfectly honest with you and
become a bit of a sort of like a
social media hermit moment. And
I don't like a completely. I'm
not sure why. Yeah, social media
butterfly in the family, not me.
But um, have you noticed a
change in what you want? I
guess,
Anna Chu: I, I've noticed the
chain, I there's, I've noticed a
lot of different things a lot.
I've noticed people take and
delete Facebook. One, I've
noticed people just completely
like, go on that end of the
spectrum. And that may be
because of, you know, that
recent documentary on Netflix.
This dilemma, I'll highly
recommend people watch. It. I've
also seen Yes, on the other end
people post more. I go in waves
between posting a lot or posting
less. I, I've noticed that, you
know, people just miss people
and interactions. And yes,
you're right. It's a little,
like hanging out in the in the
office, like cafeteria or in the
kitchen. You know, like, there's
like, that's just completely
pure randomness as someone else
walks in while you're making a
cup of tea. And then you have a
chance to do them, right. Um,
but I've also been like, you
know what, I'm just going to,
like, post a selfie of myself
with my morning cup of coffee.
And hopefully that, you know,
and I'm trying to send some
positive vibes out there. So
people have a great morning, you
know, like, and I have no idea.
But I'm glad you do. Someone
might roll their eyes and Gosh,
like, geez, but that's fine.
That's fine. I couldn't meet me.
I want like, I'm not doing it
incessantly. I'm just like, Hey,
I just want to stay alert to
people and see how everyone's
doing because I miss everyone
you know? So yeah, I like it's
really hard. I definitely feel
like there's a bit of there's
there are people who are opting
out and there are people who are
like all in I'm going to be all
social and I'm going to share
all my like, you know, thoughts
onto the internet which can be
dangerous.
Warren du Toit: Dangerous, so
dangerous. Let's delete that.
But the damage is done, right?
Yeah, yeah. damages. I mean,
there are some people that
cannot show their faces. Like
around anyway. We've had the
kind of no it happens
everywhere. I guess really. But
we've had like, a couple of
social media influencers stars
or TV personalities that just
some problems they get some
somebody posts something bad on
tik tok. They are gone. Oh,
yeah.
Anna Chu: Oh, gosh. Yeah.
There's been so many warnings
from 2020. Oh, like it has been
the volumes in turn up to 13. I
tell you what, like, there's
been a lot of things that I've
learned Personally, I feel like
this, which has been a reckoning
on many, many things. And yes,
it was probably the, the
medicine we all needed to take.
But you know, I have like I'm
Look, I'm hopeful that we're
going to come out the other end
is all more enlightened
individuals, enlightened humans
who have a better appreciation
of community, have a have
exercise deeper empathy is one
thing that I have spent the last
two weeks doing is a lot of
introspection. I was watching a
session delivered by Malcolm
Gladwell is a journalist. He's
Canadian, American, many things.
And he had a very, very
interesting take on deep
empathy. In terms of, you know,
you don't really like when I was
taught in school, what empathy
was. They translated that as
being able to walk a mile in
someone's shoes. But the problem
with that is that I'm imagining
what it's like to walk in worn
shoes on Nicholas's shoe. If I
haven't actually sat down to
speak to you individually
understand your points of view,
your perspectives, your
experiences, your influences. I
do not really understand you
deeply. Right. And I think
Especially given the current
climate and what's going to
happen next week with the US
election, it is even more
important to exercise that and
put your biases aside, right?
And so next time you see that
what you perceive as a crazy
Facebook post or social media
post, have a think about that
person and you may not have a
full understanding as to why
they did that, that they may be
having a mental breakdown. We're
all under massive amounts of
stress. And we're not very good
at expressing it or maybe too
good at expressing. You know, I
think if we have all exercise
that well and being a bit more
perceptive, I think we're all
going to come out of this the
other end that a human being so
you're right Nicholas's has been
the most deep episode you'll
ever have on the cloud pockets,
fix it
Nicolas Blank: book. Yeah, yeah.
But I think it's, it's necessary
because I shows not just about
technology, it's about the
people in it. And we, we
desperately need each other. And
I've been looking at my Facebook
feed, and especially my American
friends. And I've seen things
that I've, as a non American
I've looked at, and I see such
depth of emotion on so many
topics, and especially the
politically charged ones and
direct challenges to unfriend me
if you don't like this and and I
just think that is, there's so
much space available that we
need to give, in terms of this
empathy topic, we need to figure
out how, how do I how do I
support a person? Or how do I
just let them be when things are
difficult, and other expressing
things on a political topic, and
they've got left to deal with
and family and, and work? And
it's, it's not an easy world at
the moment in COVID?
Anna Chu: It's not Yeah. It's
brought a lot of things to the
fore. I mean, like, while
learning, I feel like I've
learned a lot about people's
challenges, like some people,
I've learned about people's
health issues, physical health
issues, people have come out and
talked about, you know, that
they have bipolar, or ADHD. And
I'm also learning that, you
know, for some people, they
really don't want to be fully
transparent about their
sexuality, or, you know, the
gender that they most associate
themselves with. That is totally
their call. It's just, it's,
it's really opened my eyes this
year. And maybe I knew about
this stuff, I just didn't delve
deeper into it. But this year,
I'm definitely much more in
sharing with people and not like
me, and nor should they be. And
I should seek, like, seek to be
super curious about it. But only
with that mission to write.
Like, I don't want to look at
people like as museum artifacts,
I want to look at people as
human beings, and just so I can
have better relationships with
them, you know? So, yeah,
Nicolas Blank: so let me try and
condense that and ask you to
summarize that into and it
doesn't matter how many there
are, it's a top 1235 skills.
What do you think, as people in
the professions that we are in
being technology focused, being
people focused? What are the
skills that we need right now?
And if we don't have those
skills, how do we build those
skills?
Anna Chu: I think a skill that
everyone needs to work on is
self awareness. I think that
underpins a lot of things, self
awareness, because it is you are
in control of of yourself.
Right? But are you aware of how
you're, what you're doing
affects other people? Like, even
the whole, you know, responding
to email at midnight, is, is
that you need to be aware of how
that action is impacting the
person on the other end of the
email, right? Same goes for your
posts on social media. It might
be just you venting the how's it
making other people feel? It's
also like how do you spend your
time if your family or your
colleagues see burning the
midnight oil? Is that is that a
good example you're setting for
your kids or for you colleagues
and that kind of goes back to
empathy a little bit too,
because people need to like it.
It's a self awareness in terms
of how your, your actions and
your words impacting others, but
but also deeply understanding
the other end, like who is this
person and how my actions
impacting them. So, yeah,
Nicolas Blank: that's stunning.
The speaking of empathy, we want
to respect your time. Getting to
the Thai LAO,
Warren du Toit: look at that.
Hey, geez. Yeah, really quickly.
A really good Yes. Yeah. I
really missed you guys. For
ages. Oh, we missed you, too.
Oh,
Anna Chu: it's just hard right
now, sir. I hope you're all
staying well and staying
healthy. And, you know, drawing
your boundaries, if he goes to
take one piece of homework away
from this is to, you know, line
your boundary so that you can
better respect your time and in
turn respect thistime
Warren du Toit: reject the
meetings man, Chelsea? No. No,
no, no meetings are allowed to
recruit more than three times.
Yeah.
Anna Chu: That's tough when way
in planning parties or events.
But I think I should take that
principle put a little Asterix
on it. Like some exceptions
apply. Yeah, no, you're right.
You're right.
Nicolas Blank: We have loved
this format. And we'd love to
have you on again, as a co host.
And you you are part of the
furniture now. So we're going to
have to have you on as host and
get you to grill someone with us
and, and and be proud of the
show.
Anna Chu: What I always love
talking to you guys, and I hope
everyone who listens to podcasts
got something out of today. So
thank you.
Warren du Toit: I think they
definitely did. Thanks,
everyone. Before you go, we just
wanted to say thank you for
listening. We really enjoyed
putting this podcast together
for you every two weeks, please
visit us at the architects
cloud. Alternatively, drop us a
tweet. We'd love to hear what
you have to say @TheCloudArch.