Chris Goosen: Welcome to the
cloud architects podcast, a
podcast about cloud technology
and the people using it.
Nicolas Blank: The cloud
architects podcast is sponsored
by Kemp Technologies. Choose
Kemp to optimize your multi
cloud application deployments
and simplify multi cloud
application management. A single
pane of glass for application
delivery, Kemp provides a 360
degree view of your entire
application environment, and
even third party ADCs. Download
Kemp360 for free today at
kemptechnologies.com.
Welcome to another episode of
the cloud pockets podcast.
You're here with myself Nicholas
blank. And my co host Warren du
Toit and Chris Goosen.
Warren du Toit: Hello,
everybody. Good to be back. I
missed I missed the last
recording and I'm really upset.
But it's good to be here.
Chris Goosen: It is it's, you
know, another Corona addition, I
guess. Yes recording or episode
of the show. But we're super
excited today because we have
someone who I've been personally
wanting to get on the show for a
long time and someone whose work
I've really enjoyed kind of
watching over the last little
bit, and I've used a lot of it
myself. So we have Lee Ford on
the show Lee, you wanna say hi.
Lee Ford: Hello. Hello,
everyone.
Chris Goosen: Well, thank you
for joining us really appreciate
it. It's a afternoon time for
you guys in the three of you in
in Europe and South Africa and
morning here in Texas. Lee, do
you want to tell the folks at
home those who don't know you
kind of who you are what you do?
Lee Ford: Absolutely. Yes. So my
name is Lee Ford. I'm based in
Birmingham in the UK. I'm
solution architect for a company
called Symity who predominantly
on Microsoft 365 house. And I
mainly work in the teams part of
Microsoft 365. And that's around
migrating people from Skype for
Business to teams, maybe helping
with the bits around the edges
around automation and scripting
and application development. So
it's kind of a as you know,
teams is such a wide net these
days pet something like Skype
for Business where it was just
sort of meetings telephony and,
and I am now it's, yeah, it's,
it's pretty much the centerpiece
of, of Microsoft 365. So yeah,
that's pretty much where I spend
most my time working.
Chris Goosen: Awesome. Yeah,
that's, um, you're right, it is.
And it's getting wider, right?
It's not just where it was like
six months ago or a year ago and
it just continues to improve and
increase and get wider and I
noticed this week there was an
announcement about some advanced
licensing which seems to be
ruffling some feathers Which we
could probably get into Warren
might have some some opinion on
that. But so did you come from a
traditional like from the Skype
or Lync world? Or is teams kind
of your kind of where you got
into working with, I guess the
that productivity stack?
Lee Ford: Yeah, so
traditionally, I came from when
I first started I did PBX So,
things like Mitel and Avaya PBX
is Mitel Well yeah, what a while
ago now but that's kind of where
a scary Phone Guy Yeah, I'm very
funny. Yeah, you either come
from Windows Server or you come
from like telephones and I came
from the telephones side. And
and this new product Lync or
OCS, I guess came in and we will
Oh, well Cisco anything's and we
want to have a have a bit of a
poke around and see what it is
if it's any good or, and that
was kind of it really, from that
point on, you know, I've just
sort of that's where I want it
to be. You know, that's many,
many years ago now and yeah, so
it's kind of been through the
evolution of ACS link of the
Skype for Business server and
Skype for Business Online. And
then obviously teams is where we
are now. So yeah, it's kind of
been there a little while now
been doing it. But
traditionally, it was a PBX,
which does come in handy when
you're doing PBX migrations, and
you know, they've got PBX that
you're familiar with you. Oh,
great. Yeah, I can, I can help
out here.
Chris Goosen: It's to me that is
so so your background is very,
very similar to Greg Sheridan,
who I think you know, and he's a
close friend of mine. We worked
together for many years. Back in
Australia, very similar, but I
think what makes that awesome is
that people coming from that
voice background. When you look
at an SBC or like a telephony
gateway, you just go Yeah, this
makes perfect sense to me.
Whereas for me coming from you
know, messaging background and
and the way like SMTP routing
works, I log into an order codes
and like the stuff does not make
any sense whatsoever to be
right. So it's always
interesting when I kind of need
help on you know on a sonar or
something or whatever they call
themselves this week. I call I
call Greg for for help, but it
works the other way as well.
Right he you know if he if he
has some DNS or some weird Yeah,
it's always DNS, but if you have
some weird, some weird thing
that he likes troubleshoot, then
you know, he'll ping me and so
we've had that kind of
collaborative relationship for a
long time. But you know,
especially because I've never
met anyone else who's come that
far along out of that kind of
PBX moto world.
Lee Ford: Yeah, no, absolutely.
Like, you know, I remember when
I first started many, many years
ago, over 20 years now, it was
Yeah, running cables for
telephones, you know, where I
sort of first started you know,
and you know, that just is
unheard of now, it's just seems
such a such a far away thing,
really. Whereas now everything's
virtual. You can work from home,
you can work anywhere and with
Coronavirus. It's Yeah, it's
more than welcome isn't it
really
Warren du Toit: and those big
cabling cabinets with those
piers and you know they're like
100 pair cable or 400 pair cable
and there was like literally it
was like this bare
Lee Ford: bones set Yeah,
absolutely yeah that's a number
that I think I've probably stole
but the tool somewhere but every
so often someone I go You know,
I've got an old telephone line
that needs moving or something
like that and yeah, I'm still
still always keep the tools just
in case you need them.
Chris Goosen: It's a separate
track the skill set that's
that's where I started right my
my old man still does do data
data networks and now it's he's
moved away from like, PBX stuff
and phone cabling, right but
it's still data networking,
because obviously all of this
stuff runs off a data backbone
now and fiber and I mean, I was
you know, I was in like primary
school. Boot every every school
Holliday, that's what I was
doing. I was pulling cables and
terminating cabinets and stuff,
right. And I think starting at
that sort of very, very, very
ground level gives you a real
appreciation of where we've
gotten to now. So yeah, that's,
that's super fascinating. And I
forget how I was gonna say it's
a super handy skill set. Because
now when I need a cat six drop
in a room somewhere, I'm like, I
just do that. It's good.
Warren du Toit: Yeah, so lately,
Chris Goosen: I'm getting really
good at fixing drywall holes now
too, because every time I need
to do this, I need to cut a hole
in my wall. And so
Nicolas Blank: just
Warren du Toit: so you saw Well,
we've we've got bricks here.
Yeah, mate.
Chris Goosen: So moving, moving
back to teams, I guess. So we're
in this place now where
obviously team's adoption has
skyrocketed over the last you
know, well, since March is right
in like every time I look at the
numbers, they just astounding. I
mean, last time I saw it was
like 75 million, I think but
it's probably gone up since
then. What about the PBX side of
teams? Are you seeing your
experience are customers using
it? Is it something that people
are actively getting rid of
their, whatever is left for
Avaya Mitel type stuff in using
teams.
Lee Ford: apps? Absolutely.
That's the case.
Not and but pre COVID. That was
also the case that, you know,
people are looking to move away
from your fixed phone on a desk,
you know, they want to be, you
know, to the ability to, you
know, have that, you know, their
desk or their landline number.
That'd be a transact call on a
mobile, if they're working from
home or, you know, wherever they
are in the world. And they can
sort of take those calls. And
especially now with COVID,
where, you know, offices are
either closed or running at a
reduced capacity. There's a lot
of desk phones sitting there
idle, and people aren't able to
use their telephones. So yeah,
absolutely. We're seeing a
massive increase of people
wanting to move away from
traditional PBX is and move over
to teams where it just gives
them the flexibility that they
can just use the number or ever
and yeah, we are seeing sizeable
uptake in in telephony, and not
only is it people wanting it,
but they're wanting it
yesterday, you know that they
want it now. You know, with
COVID It's, it's, it's gone from
being Yeah. Or we will do that
in 12 months, 18 months. Well,
we'll, we'll write out our PBX
as long as we, you know, as long
as we can. So we need it now we
need, you know, we've got key
numbers that need to be, you
know, terminating on users work
from home PBX can't do it. How
can you help? So absolutely.
Fair enough.
Chris Goosen: Yeah. So I think
that's, I mean, that is that is
interesting, right? Because if
you think about all of the
logistics that go into a company
just closing its premises,
right? I mean, you know, it's
easy to go Okay, well, guys,
like us, we've been lightly
working or working remotely. And
I should say folks like us have
been working remotely for a
while. And so we're used to
being able to just carry a
number around with us, whatever.
But if you think about the
situation where You know, you
have some sort of inbound
calling number or reception
number or something like that,
like the logistical and I had to
think about this just the other
day cuz someone asked me a
question about, like, Oh, we, we
have to shut up our office. And
so like, someone has to look
after that phone number, like
what do we do with that? Right?
It's interesting. I mean, if
it's just a line sitting, you
know, a prep terminating in your
premises, that's gonna be a lot
harder to do. I guess call
forwarding is always an option,
right, but still makes it much
more convenient when you can do
something like that. Bring it
into into teams.
Lee Ford: Absolutely. Yeah,
there's, yeah, we're having
customers at the moment,
literally just forwarding calls
to to Microsoft Teams number
just as a quick win, you know,
with with the with the prospect
of moving those numbers properly
and importing those numbers at a
later date, but just with time
is of the essence they need to
need to move across quickly.
Yeah, so absolutely. That that
you say there's a lot of
logistics involved with Closing
in office and telephony is
absolutely one of those ones.
Especially when you've got
things that you know, emergency
hotlines and things like that,
that you know, you can't have
downtime. You can't have people
not answering the phone. It is
it is a key service really.
Chris Goosen: Okay. So sorry,
Nick, you go Go ahead.
Nicolas Blank: Yeah, I wanted to
ask you since you have the the
scary Phone Guy background and
we say scary Phone Guy, because
as Windows people, we look at
like all the standards that you
guys just find so easy and
codecs and everything else. And
it's like, no, that's scary. So
excuse me Phone Guy. So if you
look at the the commercial side
of the house, if you look at the
cost of a traditional PBX and
those folks now moving over to
teams, do you find that there's
a massive upside from a moving
my voice over to teams point of
view that those folks are
getting that they couldn't get
on the traditional PBX is of the
world
Lee Ford: From a from a cost
perspective, there probably is
some say. I mean, there's
obviously two types, two left
teams, you've got calling plans
and then you've also got the the
direct routing. Certainly with
direct routing, that there is a
cost there can be a cost saving
by moving to that rather than
sticking with the PBX, you know,
coming up for renewal. And a lot
of the times you know that they
might be on E five, in which
case they've already got phone
system built in and I think
recently has been out so that in
some regions, there's also
minutes bundled into the five
that all of a sudden is like,
well, we're already paying for
it. Why are we not using it? So
yeah, we see that people are Oh,
yeah, it's it's a win win.
Really, we've already got the
licenses we need to replace our
PBX teams is the natural choice.
When it comes to teams from a
functional level filling the
need of the PBX. It's ever
improving things like call
queues and auto attendance are
getting better their features
are being added almost All the
time. There is obviously going
to be cases where, well, my old
PBX did this in a particular
way, we need the same. And you
can't always offer that. But you
might be better off or
something, you know that the old
PBX couldn't do that maybe
better. So it's always a balance
between managing what you can do
and what they should probably
do. With regards to PBX
replacement, but yeah, I think a
lot of people are like, we've
got licenses, let's use it,
let's go.
Warren du Toit: What are the
people that don't have licenses?
I mean, like, I'm finding it
sometimes the teams actually
works at a more expensive number
one, and I use that that's sort
of like easy to my next question
is, like, so in South Africa,
we've got no choice, right? We
have to use direct routing.
Yeah. Because routing apparently
is a bad word in some parts of
the world. In Australia. Anyway,
so like, we've got a choice
right? So that's, that's fine. I
mean, but like If you have to
consider what phone system costs
on an E three, it's actually
pretty expensive. I mean, you
can get a hosted PBX number,
like through a little portal,
you can click a click, and it's
really not that however, like,
if you have to look at Call
Quality Dashboard.
And the improvements that have
been done there. Your article,
which was released a month ago
was yesterday, now a month ago.
June. Yeah, yeah. Yeah, that's a
great article, man. And you
can't do that sort of like with
a hosted PBX or something like
that, and you wouldn't be able
to get these sorts of
statistics. And I guess, having
an all in one box. So my
questions would be like, Are
there any features that you
think Microsoft's forgotten
about? Or, I mean, like, I find
that they're really, really like
that teams, admin centers
getting packed full of stuff
every day. And I think it's, I
think it's going well, but I
mean, do you think anything's
missing? Do you think anything's
like, do you think that direct
routing should have been
configured with the admin By
now.
Lee Ford: Yeah, I mean, yeah,
absolutely. So I think
previously, certainly when it
first launched, it was pretty
much PowerShell is the way you
need to do a lot of it only
Yeah, yeah, a PowerShell only.
And now they've added things
like normalization rules and
voice routes. And I mean, I'm a
PowerShell. Guy. So I always
generally still do it via
PowerShell. But I'm pretty sure
you configure the whole thing
for direct routing, maybe not
all of it, but let's say 95% of
it via the admin center now, and
I think that's intentional,
because they want to get people
that maybe on PowerShell experts
to want to be able to just
quickly click, you know, you
will even just make changes, I
want to be able to click a
couple of tweaks, something like
a normalization or, you know,
regular expression. Not
everyone's gonna know what
regular expressions are. They've
made that easier where it builds
the regular expression for you a
bit like they did with Skype for
Business server.
Warren du Toit: So it was a
reason I failed my 333 exam.
Those damn regular expressions,
man. Yeah. is different.
Lee Ford: Yeah, absolutely. I
mean, I'm not an expert on
regular expressions. I do kind
of get enough. But yeah, even
even, I think everyone still has
to use some sort of online tool,
just because I need this
particular pattern. And it's
Yeah, when you break it down, it
makes sense. But then when you
put it all together, it's and
just look at string. It's Oh,
hang on what'shappening here? so
much.
So So yeah, I think I think it's
getting there. I've been sent. I
think with direct routing,
they're adding pretty cool
features like LMS, a local media
optimization, where the media
from the team's client doesn't
have to go up to Office 365. It
can get media bypass. Yeah,
yeah. Media bypass via the local
SBC while and having to go out
and back in. So there are
improvements. I think there
probably could be improvements
in the voice applications,
things like cool pickup, so
there's They have a term I think
it's called group pickup, which
is kind of I wouldn't call it
pickup group personally, like
you would on traditional PBX.
It's more, it rings the, if you
divert your call to another user
and their phone doesn't ring,
but it audibly flashes that's
classed as a pickup call pick up
that's not really a pick up
group in my eyes, but the things
that I think they could
potentially improve on. But I
think on the whole it's Yeah, I
think it's, it's, it's if
someone was going, we want to
move off, move away from our
PBX, we want to get your teams,
I really would never have any
hesitation in going Yep, sure.
Let's go. I don't think they'd
be like, Oh, hang on a minute.
Are you doing this? Are you
doing that without routing,
which makes it kind of answers
all those edge case questions
around things like dect phones
or Analog Devices or anything
like that, that you have to
keep.
And you couldn't do that we call
them fans and all of a sudden
direct routing gives you that
extra option.
Chris Goosen: So I think both
the both of you guys have
actually kind of queued up for
segwayed the question I was
gonna, I was gonna ask earlier,
which is, how is teams differing
in the regions, though, right?
And this was actually gonna be a
question to both Warren and you,
Lee, because I know like, here
in the US, we just take things
for granted that like, because
when the feature comes out, we
just have it. But But there are
other regions. I know, Australia
is one of those regions as well,
it's sometimes lags a little
behind what's possible, what's
not possible. So, I mean, are we
getting to a point where things
are being released across
everywhere, like all the regions
now or, Warren, you alluded to
the fact that that may in South
Africa right now you can only do
direct routing, so there's no
Copeland stuff available?
Warren du Toit: No, so he said,
it's, it's, it's a complicated
thing, because you see, in order
to become a teller in order to
become a telco, you need like a
telco license, right. And like,
apparently, it costs doesn't
want to use Microsoft Word, or
whatever the case would be, so
they can't like sort of legally
be a calling plan provider. At
least that's sort of what
they've said when I when when
when Microsoft gives you an
answer about where the calling
plans are available or not. So
it costs
Chris Goosen: a governing body
for
Warren du Toit: the governing
body for communications in South
Africa. So you know, like, yeah,
so, but again, you know, the
strange thing is, is obviously,
and Lee you can, you could
probably attest to this is that
even though calling plans are
available in the States, I mean,
when I was working at the team's
booth at Ignite last year, I got
so many questions about direct
routing purely because guys
wanted to use their existing
Cisco call manager or they had
this massive investment in an
existing PBX that they couldn't
just get rid of right now. And
and they wanted to connect the
two together and direct routing
is the way I mean calling plan
sort of that so so direct
routing is like sort of a more
like, like a multi tier approach
when it comes to that sort of
integration because these guys
like they don't I mean, you'd be
surprised how many people like
all over the world I mean, like
jabber jabber is such a thing,
man. I don't know how why but
jabber is a thing.
Lee Ford: Yeah. I've never
touched it. But yeah. It's,
it's,
Warren du Toit: it's under, it's
an on prem investment. Like,
like, they use.
Yeah. And you know, like I don't
even know if they have a proper
hybrid model. As far as if you
want to move from let's say
jabber to WebEx, which is, you
know, hosted. And then you get
your calling plan from WebEx. I
don't even know if there's,
there's a hybrid model.
Lee Ford: Like Yeah, so I don't
know. Yeah, so so on the calling
plans versus direct routing. So
calling plans available and I
think eight countries that
didn't any been added for at
least a couple of years and I
think Japan or maybe Australia
with the last couple to be added
and in those last They think
they had to partner with Sony in
Australia that depart with I
think Telstra. So, Telstra don't
actually provide the service
Telstra do. And there's like a
specific skew you have to have.
It's not your traditional
license. It's like a Telstra
based license. So that way
they've kind of got around
having to be a provider in that
location. I think that I think
there's some of seeing somewhere
that that they're planning
schildt they are so planning to
roll out to other countries. But
that's not to say there hasn't
been for a couple of years. But
even in the UK, with finding
that most people go direct
routing, and that's because like
you say you have a PBX and you
want to do a gradual migration
or you've got an existing
agreement with a provider.
That's, you know, yeah, too cost
prohibitive to actually want to
move away from it when you add
on the calling plan cost. And
typically, like say calling
plans we're finding that people
are rather put that money into
an SBC and and stick with their
current provider of money. Gives
them extra flexibility to switch
providers down the road and
whatnot. So what we're finding
Warren du Toit: which leads me
to my next question is why audio
codes? Like I'm also like, I
mean really like the great
products and stuff. However,
they're not cheap. You have to
look at like a like a any node
SBC. I mean that things like
literally attend to the brass.
Lee Ford: There's really I've
never actually so I know ran
out, you know, Randy Chairman,
he's he's talked about any node
before he works, where I do. And
he's saying, Oh, you know, you
should have a look one day and
you know, he's got a blog post
about it, but
Warren du Toit: I don't really
is pretty. I mean, the console
looks like AWS. Okay. Yeah.
Lee Ford: Yeah. Yeah, no, it's
it's um, yeah, I mean, to be
fair, the audiocodes ui used to
look horrendous.
Warren du Toit: Back load was
better.
Lee Ford: So when people go it's
really bad about hard to use.
Now. Thinking You want to use it
like five years ago? It was
something else. So, yeah, I've
never touched a ribbon. What I
think where I work, there's a
kind of a 5050 split between
audiocodes and ribbon. Its
expertise. And I'm sure ribbon
is just as good as audiocodes
it's just Yeah, I've always been
the audiocodes that will the
code side of the, of the camera.
Yeah, it's difficult to sort
Warren du Toit: of transition
from one sort of tiller, like
sort of provided to the next
because they are very different.
And like, if you look at
interfaces and commands and what
has to be run on a and the way,
like the flows work and what one
thing's called on the one side,
and one thing's called on the
other side, you can get
incredibly confused. I mean,
sometimes they don't I mean,
like, on an any node, it's
called a trunk. Right? But
audiocodes doesn't really use
the word trunk ever.
Lee Ford: Unless it's ISDN I
think Yeah. Which technically
isn't But yeah, it means Yeah.
They were like sardines and sip
interfaces and all those direct
good things. Yeah,
Chris Goosen: this is this I've
always wondered this and it's
always fascinated me right? I
wonder if this is also a little
bit of a regional thing because
I know like ever since I've I've
lived here in the US it's always
been audiocodes, right? Like
where I've worked in the past
that the guys don't even people
don't even look at anything
else. But when I was when I was
working in Australia, every
partner I've ever worked for it
was always so not open ribbon.
Yeah, as an alkaloid. So I
wonder how much of that is
regional versus just
Lee Ford: I think it is. It's
interesting. Yeah. Okay. Yeah,
Warren du Toit: South Africa
they use Asterix because it's
free.
Chris Goosen: So, shifting gears
just a little bit here. I so at
least one of the things I think
and so Bobby, the reason we got
to know each other was I was I
was working on a project a
couple. This would have been
probably about a year ago now.
And I was trying to do some
funky stuff with like, exporting
conversation history out of
teams conversations. And, and I
was at the time, the way I tried
I was trying to do this was I
had done a discovery search of
the mailbox of the team mailbox,
dump that to PST, and then I was
interrogating the PST through
PowerShell to try and pull the
messages out, which actually did
kind of work except the problem
was, I couldn't figure out how
to link the threads together,
right. So I could pull out the
individual messages, but they
would just be individual
messages. They weren't threaded
in any way. They just have funky
gooeys. And this doesn't seem to
be any key that links them
together. So I reached out to to
Greg Sheridan, I was like, hey,
Greg, here's what I'm trying to
do. I realized this is really
weird, but I have a specific use
case that I need to work on. And
this is what I need to do. And
he was like, Oh, I'm Lee has a
script for that. I was like,
what really? He's like, yeah,
check this out. And he sent me
your backup teams backup team
script, which then just blew my
mind because it basically did
everything that I needed to do.
And so I guess one of the one of
the things that I wanted to kind
of ask you was, you have a ton
of stuff on your on your blog,
and to me Still, it's the go to
resource for anyone who wants to
do any PowerShell stuff with
teams, I always send them to
your blog comverse, the virtual
conference that was on a couple
weeks ago, I actually presented
a team's PowerShell. So
PowerShell session at the
conference, and I demoed a bunch
of stuff. And I had like a whole
block snippet of your scripted,
which was great. It was great.
Yes. But, but I was and I kind
of sent everyone to your blogs,
like, Look, if you need stuff
that involves PowerShell in
teams, you got to go to Lee's
blog, right. Did you do you have
some sort of developer
background? I mean, we talked
about you coming out of the PBX
world, but the way I think you
approach a lot of the coding I
mean, it's it's it's it's
actually pretty Incredible and
and you look at the stuff and
you go this stuff was written by
someone who is, you know, a full
time developer. But that's not
the case with you though,
Lee Ford: right? No, it's
absolutely not afford, you know,
there's bits that I would need
to do for paid work where, you
know, we just need to script
something or write rapport or
something like that. But
typically now it has been, I'm
doing other How do I do
something? Or I, I'm doing this
thing. It's taken me a really
long, long amount of time to do
manually. How can I script? How
can I automate it? And it is
purely just a hobby is probably
not the right word. But it is
just something I enjoy doing. I
like writing a bit of code. But
certainly I'm not a formal
developer. I haven't been on any
training courses or, you know,
my job title isn't developer. So
it's purely just a passion for
wanting to do it really. And
yeah, I quite enjoy buying a bit
of code.
Chris Goosen: And so we fought I
think because I wanted to I want
to I want But to kind of get
your thoughts on the, the graph
PowerShell SDK, but before we
jump into that, do you mind just
running down or running through
a couple of the the scripts that
you actually do have a new blog?
Just for folks, for folks who
haven't come across your work
yet and are sitting there going,
how am I going to solve this
problem? Because so you have the
backup team script, right, which
is essentially just goes and
interrogates the the org and I
haven't used it in in a little
while now. But it goes
interrogate all the teams in the
org and basically dumps all of
the content into an archive.
Lee Ford: Right? Correct. Yes.
So what it will do is it will
you log in to bonds, run the
PowerShell script, you log into
it, and then it will list all
the teams within your tenant.
And then you choose like I want
to backup this team or you want
go actually I want to backup all
the teams. And then it will go
through and it will grab the
team. It will download all the
files within that team or the
chat history. And any settings
that were set against the team
is basically anything within
that team. And puts in a zip
file like saying, including all
the attachments. And what it
allows you to do then is
actually, if you wanted to, you
could recreate that team on the
same tenant or a different
tenant. And it will try and put
the file upload the files back
into the team. And if it's the
same tenant without the members
back in on the owners back end
of that original team so it's
it's a way
Warren du Toit: Why do I need to
go by F point then? Well,
Lee Ford: no, no actually doing
any SLA. Your own risk, but
yeah, I mean, it was kind of
just a, it's a, I was just
thought this should be something
that's just built into the
Amazon alphabet to just go on,
kind of capture this team
download as a file as a backup.
And then you know, I've got that
for for charity. And if that
team goes by, by by accident or
whatever, then then you've got a
copy of it a set point. So
that's kind of the need really
there. And yeah, it was it was
great fun writing it to be able
to do it's written in
PowerShell. With I think it's
just graph. I don't think
there's any, any teams your
show, purely just graph.
But not the SDK is impressive.
Nicolas Blank: Yes. That's
awesome.
Chris Goosen: And so in here's
why I think it's so cool. Right
is because and again, I, you
know, my my history or knowledge
on this is probably about six
months out of date now, because
I haven't been doing migrations
for a little bit now with my new
role. But historically, this
there's a challenge. There's
been a challenge in getting
conversation history out of
teams, right. There's no real
like, API that you can query, at
least they never there wasn't, I
guess, at the time when you can
query to get that data out or to
replay it. And so what I've seen
certain vendors doing is their
approaches that they they use,
there's a slack migration thing
that they use to replay the
cart, the Conversations back.
But you lose all the metadata.
So you end up having the the
author of the conversation have
a very chat is whatever the
migration service account is.
Right. And, and what's what's,
what was what's super sneaky
about that is, is that when I
saw this demo, they had named a
migration service account like a
person's name like john smith.
That was every conversation
authored by john smith. john
smith is our service account.
But that's, that's even worse.
Lee Ford: Migration told us a
bit more obvious to know that
Oh, yeah, this isn't actually
Chris Goosen: exactly I just
feel like it's so sneaky because
they they were trying to like,
I'm not accusing anyone of
anything. I just feel like it
was kind of a way for them to
not pay draw attention to the
fact that that and I picked up
on a straightaway and so the
other approach obviously, she
dumped everything into a file
archive like you like you do
with an HTML file. That thing
can just be viewed later. Right.
Which, which I think is is
pretty
Lee Ford: sorry. That's That's
why Yeah. So it's just an HTML
file and it almost looks like a
conversation, you've got sort of
the, the chat bubbles, if you
want to think of it like that.
And then you can kind of when
you look, okay, let's have a
conversation history, you can
either open an HTML file or if
you restore that team or
recreate that team, I guess,
into into the tenant, it will
then be available. Yeah, within
that team as an HTML file that
you can just open within teams
and look at the previous
conversation history. So you're
not gonna lying to anyone that
you know, that conversation took
place naturally, you know, that
the previous conversations were
in this fight if you do need to
get back and view them. So. But
the main reason for that is more
just want to look at a team or
look at the whole conversation
from a backup purposes rather
than a recreation.
Chris Goosen: Right? Yeah,
absolutely. And it makes a lot
of sense, but I think there's
definitely sort of an
application for it in backup
slash migration places as well,
right? If you need to move
between tenants or whatever,
this is a really handy way to
say where Here's what we can do,
here's what we can't do. And we
can't give you an archive of all
of that stuff. Because sometimes
the conversations in within the
team are not super valuable to
anyone, like from a longevity
perspective, right? Like
everyone's talking about their
lunch order doesn't isn't
something that the business
needs to keep. But there may be
some other conversations within
a that are really handy. And so
be able to get them in that
archive is, is pretty cool. So
yeah, thank you for that. There
was another one, you have a just
a backup team's config one as
well.
Lee Ford: Right there. Yeah.
backuptrans config. Yeah. So
that that effectively does a, it
uses the Skype online
PowerShell. But you can also do
the team's on my power show now,
but it basically connects via
PowerShell and downloads, all
the configs and all the policies
and all pretty much any
configurable option within teams
from a PowerShell point of view.
And then you can download that
and it puts into another archive
file. And then each type of
let's say, you know, there's a
client policy or something about
you can open the HTML file. for
that client policy and view it
kind of in in table format so
it's a bit easier to view than
than looking through a
PowerShell export. And what I've
also done is included the
PowerShell exports the the CLA
XML files, which means that you
can then go back and compare a
backup to a live service and it
will go through line by line and
compare any differences so if
you make someone's made a change
you can go well let's see what
it was compared to this back
watch it two weeks ago Hang on a
minute this is this this policy
has changed and now this value
is set to true is now set to
false
Warren du Toit: son of he's
gonna get fired that going chiz
yeah salaries salaries are you
right at right
Lee Ford: now? No, no, no. It's
all just my for my Yeah, just
just just just keep it should be
changing. Yeah. So
Nicolas Blank: anyway, you How
difficult was it for you to get
going with graphs and moving
away from What PowerShell
couldn't do is to dig around in
graph figuring out what you
wanted to solve in terms of
problems, and then figuring out
how to put that all together.
Lee Ford: Yeah, it was a little
bit of a challenge to begin
with, just because at the time,
there was no PowerShell SDK and
not being a former developer,
now having to work out things
like auth, and, you know,
authorization codes and tokens
and all that sort of stuff to to
be able to log into graph. And,
yeah, that took a little bit of
time, but it was worth it in the
end. And it is certainly
something that I do find useful
or almost on a daily basis to
know about so. But yeah, that
that was the biggest challenge
was kind of getting into graph.
Once you in graph. It's kind of
just like any other API really,
you're sending requests to an
API with with a token saying,
you know, I'm allowed to ask
this question and then you're
getting data back or you know,
your push your or you're placing
data or putting To in, in graph
and, you know, you get response
back to, to that. So, yeah, that
that was a bit of a, from going
from, you know, dedicated
commandlets that, you know,
would have been pre built almost
having to create your own
commandlets or your own custom
connections and things like
that. Yeah, that that took a
little bit more time. Not coming
from that, you know, background
Warren du Toit: very cool. I
mean, I said, I'm gonna, like,
go away completely off on a
tangent. Tell me about the
spider man in the background.
I'm a huge Spider Man fan.
Yeah.
Lee Ford: I'm not actually. So
my Mike. Mike. My kids. I'm not
really into sleep.
Warren du Toit: Oh, he's a good
guy is gonna grow up to be a
champ.
Lee Ford: Yeah. Yeah, I'm not
really. Yeah, I'm not into
super. Yeah, I'm probably
shouldn't be saying things like
that. But I'll probably get
kicked off podcasts and things.
But yeah, I'm not really into
superhero film. Or I've never
seen Star Wars things.
Warren du Toit: Yeah, no, it's
okay. Okay within them. There
must be something that you're
into right like a conscious be
graph.
Lee Ford: Yeah Now watch graph
movies. Yeah, yeah.
I
Warren du Toit: see your
YouTube.
Lee Ford: Yeah, I just watched
YouTube tutorials every day, but
it's not quite like
documentaries and
yeah, science fiction I think.
So I probably should watch Star
Wars but yeah, things like that.
You know, I'm happy to watch
that but yeah, superhero movies
I've tried I have tried but it
just didn't do it for me.
Chris Goosen: So again, getting
back to slight tangent screw.
Well, let's get back, get back
to graph. I think what you've
said is kind of exactly been my
experience right because I like
you I don't really have any
formal development background
but I I'm a mentor As a fan of
automation in PowerShell, and I
literally like if, if I could
find a job where all I did was
just PowerShell to it like all
day long, I'd be super happy. It
was quite funny I was. This is
just a little little story.
Yeah, Nick and I were at Ignite
one year, and we were talking to
a mutual friend of ours, dog.
And I and I just met him. And I
didn't really know what he did.
And we started talking, he was
like, Oh, I like PowerShell. I
said, Yeah, I said, Why I wish I
wish I could find a job, or I
just did PowerShell all day
long. And he was like, that's my
job. That's what I do. And he
actually ends up, you know,
running a whole bunch, you know,
he had a company that he did,
started to build some apps and
stuff. And it was all PowerShell
based, which is very cool. But I
also find it really hard and
really difficult to when you
start working with JSON and
having to kind of parse and
construct those queries, it
becomes really difficult or can
be interesting, right to learn.
But then I, you know, with the,
the the, the graph PowerShell
SDK, that's come out In the last
six months or so, that's made
that significantly easier
because now, I feel like you
have all of the graph magic
without any of the, you know,
having to construct, you know,
invoke web request. Right. Have
you found that? I mean, I've
seen you've been doing some some
work with it and on it and I
think you actually have some
tutorial videos on Yeah, as
well.
Lee Ford: Yeah, I think I have a
getting started video and and
just, yeah, an accompanying blog
post. And it's pretty good.
Actually, it takes away a lot of
the playing Previously, we had
to work out how to authenticate
with graph using PowerShell. And
you don't have to do any of that
you used to be type Connect pipe
and graph and say what I'm doing
graph you have these things
called scopes, which kind of
permissions what what do I want
to have access to in graph you
specify those, and then you log
in with the device code like you
do on other PowerShell modules.
You connect it and that's it.
And then you can just run, you
know, get typhon mg user or
something like that. So it's I
was always mg prefix, but bit
like there is a CS prefix with
Skype and teams. And
effectively, yeah, takes away a
lot of the guesswork and kind of
how to construct like, say, JSON
objects to post. And when you're
requesting data is literally
just writing that it feels much
more natural as from a
PowerShell point of view while
they're doing to kind of create
your own wrapper, but photograph
now i think it's it's very, very
useful. Really cool. I do
probably need to put it into
some of my scripts actually,
because I need to go back and
update them to use the module.
But no, it's super cool. I don't
think it's 1.0 just yet, but
they are working on it and yeah,
it's improving all the time. And
it's super cool.
Chris Goosen: Yeah, I definitely
the I really like it and what i
what i love about it is that I,
because I'm a Mac user, I can do
everything on my Mac now. Right?
Like I don't I mean, I still do.
But I technically I don't need a
VM to be able to do things
anymore because I can take, I
can access all of graph through
this module that runs great in
PowerShell Core, and I can do it
straight up my Mac. And that was
part of the demo that I did on
the converse was taking, I took
a script that another MVP,
Nathan O'Brien had written. And
I ported it to use what I bought
it as much of it as I could to
use the the SDK, and then I ran
the one in Windows, and then I
ran the other one on on my Mac.
And it's for one, it's
significantly quicker, right to
run and versus the module. But
it's fantastic stuff. I'm super
excited by that. I'm struggling
a little bit with the lack of
documentation on some things,
because it's not, you know, it's
not as easy to find. If you
know, if you want to interrogate
a particular property somewhere
to go and find exactly how you
do that, you kind of have to dig
through the the API reference
and then try and work it out. At
least that's how I've been Been
doing it but
Lee Ford: grass was only a
module of the SDK for the SDK?
Yes. So the the SDK isn't sort
of hand built. It's it's, it's
kind of auto generated, right? I
can't I think it might be called
Open API or something like that,
where they they use a method
where it's kind of looking at a
graph and working at all right,
there's a, there's a graph
endpoint for user. Okay, based
on that I can create a list of
commandlets to wrap around that
that API call. So they're not
having to write each command
line manually. I think there are
literally are thousands of them.
So so you're probably going to
struggle to get documentation
like you would, let's say, with
a traditional PowerShell module
has been written by someone.
It's It's so that's Yeah, where
you're going to struggle. I
think you kind of almost looking
to look at the graph API
reference to work out what the
object is going to be when you
when you run your request. And
kind of work backwards from
there really, so yeah,
Chris Goosen: yeah, that's,
that's, I guess that's been my
approach of trying to kind of
figure it out. And eventually
we'll kind of get to that way of
thinking, I think it's just a,
it's a familiarity thing, right?
You know, if you're looking to
find anything related to a user
be, you know, in the in the
Azure module, it'd be, you know,
get Azure AD user, and it's
going to be a property in there
somewhere. But it doesn't, it
doesn't translate like that to
the SDK, you can't do get mg
user and see all of us and
properties. Sometimes you have
to query a different command I
found but I think once we start
wrapping our head around that,
it's, it's just gonna be super
because now it really becomes
cross platform. And that's
really good for me. So I want to
kind of move any future scripts
I write all the same here to to
do that. Yes, it just seems to
make a lot more sense. So
Warren du Toit: XML as long as
XML is out of the picture Life
is good. I'll take JSON or XML
Lee Ford: Yeah, I think it's
moving that way, isn't it? It's
It's It's all JSON and open
standards and annex one is an
open standard, but it's, yeah,
everything's everything's
heading that way. And Things
like what you say have been not
fixed. I've got to use Windows
PowerShell. For this module, you
know, I think slowly but surely
that's moving away. Like in the
team's preview PowerShell
module, they've added the
bilytica Skype for Business. So
you can use in Skype for
Business PowerShell using core
by then empties Windows
PowerShell. So they are moving
slowly, which is common.
Nicolas Blank: So we're coming
up to the top of the show. And
before we let you go, I would
like to ask you, what is it that
you'd like to plug either in
terms of Twitter handles, blogs?
Anything else that you'd like to
call out? Absolutely. Nothing
goes as long as we get a cut of
it.
Lee Ford: Yeah, of course. And
so yeah, you can you can follow
me on Twitter. My Twitter handle
is @lee_ford. And my blog is
lee-ford.co.uk. I'm not sure how
so I've got it has to blow to
play. As my blog capacity and
Twitter on my blog, you'll
probably find everything that
I'm working on really. So yeah,
that's, that's it for me.
Chris Goosen: Awesome. We really
appreciate having you on the
show. And, you know, maybe we'll
do a follow up sometime. kind of
see how things are going and
what you what else you busy
with, but yeah, really
appreciate you coming on and
taking the time.
Lee Ford: No worries. Yeah,
thanks. Yeah, geez, we got to
talk about Yo, we got to talk
about Yo,
Warren du Toit: yeah, we got to
talk about adaptive cards, and
we got to talk about all that
stuff. So yes, thank you so much
for the time.
I know. Everyone, before you go,
we just wanted to say thank you
for listening. We really enjoy
putting this podcast together
for you every two weeks, please
visit us at the architects
cloud. Alternatively, drop us a
tweet. We'd love to hear what
you have to say @thecloudarch