Chris Goosen: Welcome to the
cloud architects podcast, a
podcast about cloud technology
and the people using it.
Nicolas Blank: The cloud
architects podcast is sponsored
by Kemp technologies. Choose
Kemp to optimize your multi
cloud application deployments
and simplify multi cloud
application management. A single
pane of glass for application
delivery, Kemp provides a 360
degree view of your entire
application environment, and
even third party ADCs. Download
Kemp 360 for free today at
Kemptechnologies.com
Hi, and welcome to another
episode of the cloud architects
podcast my name is Nicolas Blank
and I'm here with my co host.
Christopher Goosen.
Chris Goosen: Hello.
Nicolas Blank: Today we have a
guest which we featured on the
show before Michael Van
Horenbeeck
Michael Van Horenbeeck: Hi,
everyone.
Nicolas Blank: Welcome to the
show. And thank you so much for
appearing again. We are excited
that there's something that you
are launching fairly soon, and
it's a book. So without wanting
to spoil too much, why don't you
tell us what your book is about
and why you've decided to write
it?
Michael Van Horenbeeck: Sure. So
the book is called Microsoft 365
security for IT professionals.
And some of you might recognize
that the title kind of resembles
the office 365 for IT
professionals book, um, which is
done on purpose. A couple of
years back Tony Paul Cunningham
and I we started a venture
Adventure I should say of
writing a book which is kept up
to date on a monthly basis, the
office 365 for IT professionals
book. The reason why we started
that journey a couple years back
is because the cloud is moving
at lightning speed updating you
almost on a daily basis. So
trying to create a book which
isn't outdated from the day that
you publish. It was an
interesting challenge. And I
believe I wrote for the Book
Three, four years after original
work life got in the way so I
kind of dropped off as a as an
author and an entire team took
over from Paul me. And, you
know, there's a whole author
team out, but still you I like
to write. In the meantime, I
also switched over to the
security side of things where
over the past couple of years,
all I've done is security,
security, security. And I
noticed there wasn't really a
security book in the same space
or following the same model kind
of keeping up to date on a
monthly basis. And you know,
With the focus from Microsoft on
everything, you know, security
and compliance, there's a ton of
stuff that's changing really
like a lot of that. So I
figured, you know, let's bring
on that challenge. Let's try and
write a book and keep it up to
date at the same pace. But
rather than focusing on the
productivity side of things,
just focus on the entry 65. and,
by extension, a little bit of
Azure Security as well. And
that's how we got to the book,
which, by the way, we should be
releasing very shortly.
Chris Goosen: That's, that's
super exciting, I think, for a
number of reasons. Right? I
think, one, I think that most
people or at least a large part
of the audience will understand
or know of the office 365 for IT
pros venture and the work that
you and Tony and everyone have
done on that because it really
is the standard as far as you
know, a book of knowledge around
office 365 goes right and I it's
something that I've given to
customers in the past when when
I've worked with customers, and
they've said hey, where do I go
for free? Knowledge, where do I
go to learn more about office
365? What training courses can I
go on? I've given them a copy of
the book. And on here you go,
actually hijacked Tony once at
Ignite and made him sign a whole
bunch of USB keys for me. He
wasn't he wasn't pleased. So I
think that that same kind of
methodology is is fantastic.
Because I think one of the
things I've found over the last
little while since I've started
doing a lot more security
focused work as well is
sometimes the documentation is
not quite where the where the
product is. And so all I can say
is, you know, hats off, and
congratulations, but it seems
like a mammoth challenge to me
to be kind of taking that on
keeping that publishing kind of
cycle going on something that is
that bleeding edge.
Michael Van Horenbeeck: Yeah.
So, I mean, you have no idea how
much effort it goes into the
book. We started writing last
year. And you know, the initial
effort of writing a chapter is
massive, right? But as you're
writing the chapter, they keep
changing stuff, and you're like
finding yourself writing a bit
of bits and pieces and then
rewriting it and then writing
new bits and pieces and
rewriting older stuff that
you've written a couple of weeks
back. So to get to the point
where we're, you know, ready to
release has been a massive
undertaking, but the real
challenge starts now, updating
the book on a monthly basis. If
there's one thing that I've
learned is, don't underestimate
it. I did in the past a little
bit where, you know, sometimes I
didn't account for the time to
write the chapters, right, which
meant that I had to know doing
last minute, which added a lot
of burden. So I learned a lot
from the earlier process. My
respect for Tony for, you know,
keeping the book up to date for
keeping everyone in line and for
doing the copy editing is just
grown tremendously. Because now
I'm taking on that role and I'm
like, Oh, god, what do you do,
you can start with, right? But
at the same time role, so you
know, trying to get to the point
where we want to be that book of
knowledge, right, where we want
to centralize everything, get
that practical guidance. But
it's a journey, right? Even
version one that we're
releasing, we know their stuff
that we should get in there over
time. Like, I'll give you a
practical example Office ATP,
right due to some author
challenges, you know, people
dropping off halfway, because
they, they figured out, hey,
this is too much of a word for
us. We had to cut that chapter
on version one. So we're going
to add that word as part of the
release, you know, in a couple
of months time. But that's a
massive chapter, right? Like our
Defender ATP chapter, even
without practical deployment
guide information is 120 pages
on that one, I'm not gonna call
it a little thing. It's just
it's quickly becoming this huge
mess of stuff. And I think we'll
learn as we go, but it is it is
it is interesting to see at the
very least.
Chris Goosen: Yeah, and I think
the thing is, and we've said it
on the show before it may even
have been on the last episode
where we you know, we call
Microsoft, the security vendor,
right? Because At the end of the
day, that's kind of where they
are right now. And, and a lot of
folks, and I'm seeing this
firsthand with my recent role
change, people don't take
Microsoft seriously in the
security space yet, or at least
a lot of folks don't. But when
you're able to look at something
like this and go, Well, this is
how it all ties together. And
the small thing that's just a,
just a tiny little endpoint
thing is 100 and something pages
worth of documentation. It's
really stunning to say something
and I think it's gonna be a very
easy way to quantify the value
that the platform brings. Right
when you when you when you tie
all these services together.
Michael Van Horenbeeck: Yeah, I
mean, and there is another
interesting tidbit, which you're
just kind of you mentioned
Microsoft cybersecurity vendor,
I'm entirely with you. There's
things they don't do, right.
They don't build firewall. They
do build Azure firewalls, but
don't build physical firewalls
and stuff. But they have a whole
plethora of options and
solutions that somehow tie in
together. They have a vast
ecosystem and it's uncovering
value. system, which is the
interesting part and also the
hard part. But at the same time,
you know, putting everything
together as an author team, we
were already facing the, you
know, where do we put this in
which chapter with this belong?
Or like this feature, it belongs
to product x, but he really
belongs more to this new
paradigm. So where do we put it
into the book? So why expect
that will happen is over the
course of the next couple of
months when, you know, feedback
trickles in when Microsoft, you
know, releases new stuff, and
God knows what they've got
planned for this year. You know,
we'll be modifying and updating
the book and that's the beauty
of dating monthly, right? If
something doesn't belong in one
chapter, or we can take it off
next month and put it somewhere
else where it belongs better or
where it feels more natural. But
we see that today, like,
honestly, we've had discussions
about you know, Windows
Information Protection. Well,
you know, do we create a chapter
on Windows 10 security and if
so, well, what about Defender
ATP or attack surface reduction
resource protection? Do we keep
it in Defender ATP? Or do we put
it into Windows? 10 per day?
Yeah, it's kind of like, you
know, ongoing discussions the
entire time.
Chris Goosen: Yeah. And I think
this is probably this probably
is a really good insight into
how meetings within the
Microsoft marketing department
go, right? Because they're
constantly, they're constantly
like they changing the product
names, but also the product name
doesn't always align 100% with
the rest of that, the platform,
so I could definitely see how
that would be a slight, you
know, slight challenge.
Michael Van Horenbeeck: Well,
and you know, it's not just that
Microsoft 365 security for IT
professionals. So you know,
obviously even looks at the 65
side of things. But what we've
already committed to and we
started writing is an Azure
Sentinel chapter now. Better
Sentinel? No, it is and it isn't
entry 65 because it's Azure
workload, but yet we put it
there in the book. So you know,
you can see the cross the bleed
between the two worlds, your
productivity and Azure, which is
typically infrastructure, kind
of converging in becoming one so
you know, maybe we should rename
The book from the get go to
Microsoft Security for IT
professionals editor.
Chris Goosen: Now that makes
sense. I mean, I think where
you're at now, I think it, it's
definitely gonna resonate with
the way that it's named. And I
think immediately, when I saw
news about the book it
immediately I was able to put it
together and tie it to, you
know, the other author team and
the work that Tony is doing. And
I think that's really valuable,
because I think not only are is
it going to be a natural
progression for folks who are in
the IT pro space, who are now
possibly becoming more
comfortable with Office 365, and
with the 365 workloads, and now
starting to think a little bit
more security focused. So this
is a natural progression for
them. But this is also a really
good entry point for just pure
infosec folks who have not
played in the micro space
before, right. And there are a
lot of people like that there
are a lot of people who come out
out of the Palo Alto, Cisco,
etc. World CrowdStrike world who
have never really dipped their
toe into the Microsoft
ecosystem. I think this is going
to be a really, really good
entry point for them too. Gotta
get involved and see what's
what's actually going on.
Michael Van Horenbeeck: Yeah, so
and that's, that's really
important what you mentioned,
because, as you said, there's a
whole audience that's familiar
with Tony's book, The Office 365
book. And obviously, they, you
know, after having read the
book, you understand the product
really well, the product
platform, I should say, really
well, I have certain insights.
So the jump into the entry 65
security is more natural, but
there is a whole, you know, a
whole army of people out there
that you know, are less familiar
with Microsoft products as a
whole, but they're now you know,
faced with new implementations,
new features, you know,
Microsoft everywhere these days.
So what we try and do is, you
know, to keep it accessible,
right, not start up there, but
you start slowly and then build
up gradually to the book, which
is also one of the reasons why
the first chapter is not a
really a technical chapter. It's
more you know, okay. So how to
approach it security, because
people come from a security
background, they have this
person in mind if this you know,
thinking like their security It
and someone who's coming from
the productivity side doesn't
necessarily have, you kind of
have to blend them together to
kind of mix and match the both
worlds which, in itself, we
didn't want to create a 300 page
book about process because
that's though, everyone, you
know, understands why it's
necessary, but it's still dull.
So we kind of slimmed it down to
about 1520 pages to kind of get
everyone in that same mindset,
and then take them on a journey
with identity, Device Management
and support and so on. Okay,
yeah,
Chris Goosen: that makes sense.
I think that's a pretty, pretty
important way to kind of
approach it right. And you kind
of have to have a mix of those
various components. You can't
just be all technical or process
because you end up losing out on
a bunch of, you know, folks lose
out on a bunch of things that
they're looking to learn. But
also, you're not hold at that
point. You're not you know, you
can't be completing a job if you
don't understand, you know, a
little bit of all of those
pieces.
Michael Van Horenbeeck: Mm hmm.
I agree. Yep.
Chris Goosen: Okay, well, look,
Nick, I think Nick might have a
question here.
Nicolas Blank: Yeah. I wanted to
ask Michael, who is the primary
audience for this book is Is
this an operations person who
needs to add security to the
landscape? Or is this for a
hardcore security person who
needs to add Microsoft to their
landscape?
Michael Van Horenbeeck: That's a
good question, Nick. I think
there's value for both right?
This is for the none. Well, tech
savvy but non security savvy, IT
professional that needs to do
something with with something
and security in Microsoft 365. I
mean, we all know how to sale
cycle work, right? Then the
Microsoft sales sales guys there
and tell them hey, it was a
great discount on, you know, the
interesting divide the five
security bundle, and the company
says, Yeah, great, let's do
this. And then, you know, it
rolls downhill to the security
teams or the operational teams
or like lowers first time that
we touch X, Y, or Z. You know,
what can we do with it? How do
we do it? What's the best
practice? What are the caveats,
right? So some of them may have
the actual office 365 experience
and some of them may be coming
from a purely security
perspective, like looking In our
company, and the projects that
we do is we've got exactly that
happening. Like I've got one
project for customers migrating
from McAfee to Defender ATP. And
we're dealing with people that
have dealt with McAfee for
years, they know the product
inside out, they have no
knowledge whatsoever of Defender
ATP. But you know, just looking
at defender by itself, you can't
because it's part of the holder,
your bigger ecosystem. So it
kind of ties in together with
that whole entry. 65 steps are
prevented, super valuable to
have secure resource. But the
same is true. If you're coming
from the other side where, you
know, we've come from exchange
like all of us, all three of us
were hardcore old coal exchange,
guys, we turn a link to
security, you know, a couple of
years back if a book like that
would have existed, I would have
surely appreciate it that rather
than going out and having to
figure out everything on my own,
Nicolas Blank: completely right,
but just like so many other
things in the IT landscape, is
there a process that I can
follow in so Yeah, I'm kind of
picking on from an IT
professional point of view. I
could be ITIL aligned from a
security professional, I could
be mature aligned. How do I
align myself against the
knowledge in the book?
Michael Van Horenbeeck: Yeah,
yeah, I agree. So I understand
what you mean, I'm so this is
where the first chapter clinic
comes in. I mean, there's so
many frameworks out there that
you could use to actually, you
know, build a build a strategy
on what you're going to do.
Personally, I am a NIST
cybersecurity framework fan,
right? With the different
phases, but there's
organizations that adhere to
whole other standards that have
built their own standards, in my
opinion, and you know, maybe
some people will be printed in
what I'm going to say, but, you
know, I don't care which
framework you use, as long as
you use a framework, you have a
plan that works for you. I'm
happy, right? So that's also
what we try to explain that
first chapter. I do mention
meter. And you mentioned ISO, or
you mentioned a PCI DSS or you
mentioned Mississauga security
framework. I explained to the
people in here, these are the
frameworks look at these are the
highlights of these frameworks
now go out and figure out what,
what's important to you.
Obviously, if you're a financial
institution, PCI DSS will come
up really quickly. And even
there, we try and give some
practical examples. Like there's
this huge mapping sheet between
all the different frameworks
that tells you you have the
controls in this framework equal
the controls in that framework.
So we refer to that to that
sheet to tell them you know, if
you're already compliant with
this, but you want to look at
the other one, just use that
cheat, do the mapping so that
you don't do the work twice. But
at the same time, we don't want
this to become a book on how to
use the frameworks. There's
plenty of books out there that
explain these frameworks into
details. You could go on
certification on once one
framework itself. So we wanted
to explain why they're there and
where it's important, but we
didn't want to go into the
detail of, you know, this is how
each of them work.
Chris Goosen: I think that seems
that sounds like a really,
really good approach. Honestly,
and I, I, for one can't actually
wait to get my hands on this so
that I could actually have a
have a look at that, because I
think that's definitely
something that I've found
particularly challenging kind of
entering into this this world is
is the fact that everyone has a
framework that they look up to,
and that is super important to
them. But the relationship
between them, and then I think
it's that's a super important
kind of introductory step for
sure.
Michael Van Horenbeeck: I agree.
Yeah. facing the same
challenges, right for moving
into ISO certification 28 27,001
for our own company. Oh, my
gosh, it's like there's a whole
avalanche of stuff coming to
you. And you're like, Really? So
yeah, no, it's getting trying to
be practical. I think there's,
we could write 100 pages about
one of the things but we
deliberately kept it, you know,
short and sweet, I'd say.
Chris Goosen: Yeah, I think that
it sounds like it. Right. And so
the question I had for you was,
I mean, this so much as far as
security functionality goes
within within the service,
right? But I think there's a lot
of organizations that still have
this mentality that we've given
out, we give Microsoft up
monthly subscription money, and
we've put our data in their
service. Why do we have to worry
about the security functionality
of this? Right? Shouldn't
Microsoft be taking care of all
of the security functionality
for us? Why are we having to
care about this? I mean, are you
coming across that in Europe as
well? Is that something that
you've seen?
Michael Van Horenbeeck: Yeah, I
mean, less than less, to be
honest, because people are
getting more and more used to
the cloud model where, you know,
there was a segregation of
duties, where, you know,
infrastructure, sure, that's
Microsoft Word, like physical
security. Sure, let them take
care of that. But you know, the
layer that you build on top of
that solutions that you build on
top of that, you know, people
are starting to understand that
that's your responsibility. Now,
there's still a whole long way
to go. There are still a lot of
companies that try and get
around why do we need x y, z.
But you know, the reality is is
that whenever you see today,
These days in the news, there is
breaches you're far and few in
between. Every day there is a
breach. There's a leak or
something. I think, you know,
gradually people will
understand. Alright, we need to
do this. Like, you need to lock
your door a couple of hundred
years back, no one locked your
doors. There were no locks.
Right? The doors are open. Well,
today go out and find a house
where there's no lock. Hmm.
Yeah, I think it's pretty much
the same.
Chris Goosen: Yeah, I think that
that makes sense. I think enable
multi factor everyone if you
haven't done it MFA. It's just
my, my, my PSA for the day. I
you know, we got to make sure to
pull that out in every episode,
just because it's such an
important thing. You know, we
see, I although I think the last
couple of weeks have been very
much taken up by f5. And their
vulnerability that everyone
seems to be bypassing or
whatever, but definitely a lot
of the things that we're seeing
could easily be have been
mitigated by just MFA, right?
But companies I think are just
folks are not being educated and
and they're not kind of taking
that active decision to, to go,
hey, let's see how we can
continually improve this. This
is not the cloud is not set and
forget, right? It doesn't matter
what any vendor tells you, you
can't just go and throw your
data at a service, pay them and
forget about it. Like there has
to be a continuous improvement
model that, you know, you're
going to be looking at where the
threats can come from, because
at the end of the day, the bad
actors continue to evolve as
well. Right? And you can't, you
can't just go Okay, well, this
is the assumed knowledge
everyone has, and we're gonna
we're safe. Yeah, you might be
safe today. That doesn't mean
you're safe tomorrow. Right? So
I think that this whole thing
with f5 is really kind of shown.
A lot of folks that are, you
know, a lot of organizations
that are slower to move to the
cloud and stay or staying on
prem, because security right are
now the ones that are targeted
by this, you know, this thing in
their security, like their,
their legacy infrastructure, if
you will, right. So this is a
very, very interesting thing to
be kind of paying attention to
Michael Van Horenbeeck: We
mentioned it in the book, a
little spoiler there, but it's
about 68% of all breaches in the
cloud originate on premises like
68%. Yes, that's, that's a large
number. And again, you know,
attackers are people with
intent. They'll always take the
path of least resistance. If
it's easier to get into your
cloud through your on prem
environment, they'll do that,
right? And this is just true. I
mean, when a pen test happens,
you should know, right? kudelski
does these tests, right?
Whenever a pen test happens, I
rarely seen them go after Azure.
At first, they're like, Okay,
let's try and get into the
device. And we're into Active
Directory, then some letter
Academy movement, and bam, we've
got your domain. And then from
there, it's easy to get back
back up into the cloud. You
know, that's where the
challenges lie. So the people
that are full traditionally on
premises, they have a lot of
work to be done there a lot more
than, you know, lowering your
attack surface in the cloud, but
at the same time, it's very
different, right, the things
that you have to deal with on
premises No, they're not the
same as in the cloud, which is
also one of the messages that
we're trying to get across is
like, it is changing sure
devices device, that doesn't
change. But you know, Cloud
Platform cloud applications,
they operate in a very different
way. The your security is a very
different way and therefore have
different security measures or
how to approach that.
Chris Goosen: Yeah, and I mean,
even getting down to managing
those that infrastructure,
right, the way that you
typically would do that on
premises versus the way that
you're possibly doing it today,
it's very different in the way
you approach it. So it's kind of
like I think the message really
is that you have to be able to
adapt to the way that you know,
the new modern way of doing
things and you can't be stuck in
the old world for too long,
right. Otherwise, you're gonna
you're gonna lag behind. So
yeah, that's so. So we've
talked, we've talked a lot about
the book and honestly, I
personally can't wait to get my
hands on a copy here. Can you
give us some information about
where when how all of that?
Michael Van Horenbeeck: Sure. So
not sure when the podcast is
going to be released. But our
target is to release July 13.
I've got a full weekend of copy
editing, building the book and
you're getting the PDF ready.
We've got the website up. So the
entry 65 security book comm
where you can get to the book
files are actually to the
government platform through
which we're selling the book,
which is the same platform as
the office 365 for IT pros book.
So money 13th the book will be
available, obviously, it will
make a big splash on LinkedIn,
Twitter, the website itself,
we'll make it known and then
hopefully people will find their
way to the book itself as well.
Chris Goosen: Okay, and would
you are you gonna be releasing
on Amazon as well? Oh,
Michael Van Horenbeeck: no,
that's a deliberate choice we
we've made and actually I'm
leaning on Tony's experience of
building the book for Amazon.
There's a couple of things like
the the amount of effort going
into building that book or the E
pub and making sure that In
Amazon, that's one thing.
Secondly, Amazon doesn't support
monthly updates. gumroad is
easy, because it's just changing
the PDF like first one to
version two and off you go.
Right, nothing else changes. And
because of that, I didn't want
to take on more work. Plus, you
know, supporting the authors
supporting the marketing, the
hosting everything for the book
cost money. Amazon, you know,
takes a 70% cut on the book.
Wow. Which, you know, it's great
because you reach a bigger
audience. But at the end of the
day, I just think that the
effort you put into it, and the
gains that you get from it, and
the gains that people get from
it, are too liberal to justify
using Amazon as a platform.
Chris Goosen: I think that makes
sense. I mean, personally, I've,
I've always used the, the
gumroad platform because I
prefer just having the PDF copy
of the book, right. It's more
portable for me. I know others
disagree with that, because I
want to use Kindle and whatnot.
I you know, it's not my
preferred method of reading. So,
you know, it is what it is. But
yeah, mix. I think that makes
sense. And I think it's good
Good to get the message out
there to folks like this one
platform. That's where you can
go and get it. And that's also
where you get your your updates,
right? Because that reminds me
how the subscription model works
again. So you, you buy an
edition of the book and you get
all updates that are part of
that edition, correct?
Michael Van Horenbeeck: Yes,
Yes, correct. So there is a
yearly cycle. We're starting
July of this year, which is
coincidentally called the 2026
or 20 2006 edition. But anyway,
so the 2020 edition runs up
until June of next year, you buy
the book, you get all the
updates that year and you know,
we are committing not just to
updates of the chapters, but
this year we'll also committed
to a practical guidance chapter
on the ATP on an Azure Sentinel
chapter and Office ATP chapter.
So with the book, you know,
you'll be getting that. And then
up until June, you'll get
updates sometime next year,
March ish timeframe, will start
thinking or building the new
book, which means new edition
2021 edition. We may you know,
do completely overhaul we may
add more chapters into that
really depends on Oh, ever
everything, you know, moves
along. I mean, we all know that
Microsoft is doing shifting in
that space as well with the
acquisition of cyber x in the OT
space. So we're closely
monitoring that. And then based
on that, we'll build a new book,
new edition, and from there on,
people who have bought the first
book and can get the new one at
a discount, you know, kind of
your appreciate their, your,
their loyalty to the book, and
then they get updates for a year
as well. So there is no monthly
fee, it's just a one off and
then you'll get the updates per
year.
Chris Goosen: Yeah, fantastic.
And I think what's what's great
about that, and certainly, you
know, the way that I've
approached this with with the
the other book is that the book
is so large now, it's gotten so
big that it's it's a fantastic
reference. And realistically, I
you know, I don't read through
the whole thing every time I get
it. Now, I just like I read the
new chapters when I get the new
chapters, but I know I have this
In a referenceable thing in my
in my tool bag, if you will,
right where I can rip it out.
And, you know, remember back in
the day when we had the exchange
administrators pocket to get to
guide it's something like that.
Michael Van Horenbeeck: Yeah,
well at the same time though I'm
really keen on making sure we
don't bloat the book because
it's so easy to go over, you
know a certain amount of pages.
Right now we're not it's five
600 pages, which is sizable by
itself. But once you go over
that, like it becomes that huge
chunk and people start not
reading certain chapters or they
start being selective which is
which is fine, right, but I
really want to keep it you know,
concise so that it is
digestible. You know, obviously
some things just take like the
unwritten so many pages, we have
them Defender ATP, it's just
because we need that much,
right. We honestly we couldn't
have done it with less maybe we
could have done 90 pages and you
know, cut some redundancy here
and there but at the end of the
day, you need what you need. My
goal is to keep it sizable, but
you will see, you know, talk to
me in a year and maybe I'll be
six 700 pages.
Chris Goosen: Yeah, no. I mean,
look, I fair enough. And I think
the thing is, given your
experience in the industry, and
given your experience learning
things, I think you have a
fairly good idea of what it
takes to be able to get that
message out there in a way that
is going to be useful to someone
without it being too bloated or
to kind of, you know, too wordy,
but also, you know, where it's
sometimes where it's just not
enough, right? Unfortunately,
the internet is full of blog
posts that tackle a particular
topic, but really just scratch
not even scratch the surface.
Basically, they just kind of
give you a little bit of
interest. You know, and you need
to like to everyone who has
blogs credit, that's great. But
but sometimes sometimes you need
to dig one level deeper. Right?
And I think the what's great
about that your history with
with the other book, also you
Your history as a, you know,
blog author and speaker and
stuff is I think that you have
that balance, you know how to
find that balance. And so yeah,
really looking forward to what
you and the team have kind of
come up with here. I can't wait
to get get my hands on a copy,
Michael Van Horenbeeck: you'll
get a copy from me, but only as
you get feedback, because this
is, you know, one of the
messages that we're going to
push really hard. Um, that to
me, that book is a collaborative
effort, right? Yes, the author
team has written something, but
we can only improve, make it
better and make it you know,
more suitable if people use the
feedback, right? If they email
us and tell us we like it, or
Hey, you know, we're missing
this piece, so that we know
maybe we haven't thought about
it. Or maybe we didn't
prioritize it in the same way
that people are asking for. Call
it a user voice. If 100 people
email us and tell us we really
need this piece of information.
And we as authors, we didn't
prioritize it as high, we might
just shift it up in priority and
just add it into the book
because there was too long for
it, right? So I'm really keen to
see how that's gonna work. I
know that too. He's getting tons
of feedback through his feedback
channels on the book, you know,
even to correct things as wrong
because you never want to make
mistakes. Because I'm like our
tech tech reviewer, he's done an
amazing job. But you know, he's
going haywire through all the
chapters, all the events that
we're firing at him all the
things that he needs to test. I
mean, we're doing our best to
make sure that it's you know,
without any spelling errors,
grammar spelling, even me as a
copy editor. I'm not even native
English speaker. So, you know,
things will slip but we'll,
we're counting on that.
Chris Goosen: And I was actually
just going to touch on that
point, right is I'm always
amazed by the fact that and I've
read some of your works before
where I've, you know, we've done
I've done you know, we've done
work for the same vendor writing
vendor or whatever, and we've
kind of reviewed each other's
stuff and I I'm always amazed
that as someone who's not even
an English first language
speaker, the level at which you
managed to crank out this this
awesome work, right so you know,
Kudos to that. And I think this
is something that everyone needs
to also understand is that the
team and correct me if I'm
wrong, and I actually like you
to introduce the team that you
know, that you're working with,
because I actually don't know
everyone personally, like, I
know you. But you guys are all
based in Europe, right?
Michael Van Horenbeeck: No, no,
not really. So we've got a mic
on it, or both also, in VPS, do
a lot of work in the security
space. They're based out of the
United United Arab Emirates.
There are actually I think I'm
our move to Dubai right now. So
they're based out of there. I've
got a couple of folks in the
Netherlands. I've got as you can
see, lovely works for me, as
well. And, you know, it just so
happened that when I started
reaching out to folks that they
were the first to respond and
said, Yeah, sure. We want to do
that. But yeah, it's been it's
been helpful because, you know,
less timezone issues. It's only
a couple of hours apart. But
we'll we'll see. I mean,
reaching out to the For the
Office ATP chapter, I think we
might actually cross jump over
to to the US to onboard someone
else. But as far as the team
goes, so we've got alarm on a
tour doing the NBA TV chapter,
we've got Peter who's doing
Intune and identity. We've got
Thomas was focusing on
information protection, which,
you know, coincidentally you
could say it is more compliance
feature rather than security
feature, but as you said, to
kind of blogs to it. Next to
building the book in the the
copy editing, I'm doing em Kaz
during the introduction, and
also doing some work here and
there and the other chapters,
and then task is doing the all
all up review.
Chris Goosen: Okay. And I think
what's great about having, like
an international team like that
is everyone has their
potentially slightly different
market. So there's going to be
slightly different point of view
and slightly different
experience coming into it and
blending it all together. I
think that's really powerful
too.
Michael Van Horenbeeck: It's
incredibly useful, like in the
talks that we've had, that is
questions that we've had. I've
learned so much like, insights
from from Amar in certain things
and how to approach it even you
marketing the book, but also
structuring the book. We've had
another meeting last week, where
we were just talking, like
brainstorming, all of a sudden
everyone was like, Yeah, wow,
that's a great idea, just by
having that interaction. And
that's, you know, it's a
learning process for each and
every one of us. And, you know,
it's fun. So, yeah,
Chris Goosen: well, that's super
exciting. Honestly, I think I
can't I can't wait. Like I said,
and it's really the timing on
this is absolutely perfect. Like
you couldn't have picked a
better you know, a better time
for it. So I think with that, I
mean, just kind of keeping
keeping an eye on the on the
clock here. I know. We've all
got other things to get to.
Nick. I just wanted to just to
check in that. You're still
breathing, buddy. I I'm sorry.
I've taken over.
Nicolas Blank: If the questions
weren't so good. I throw in some
more but you're doing great.
Chris Goosen: Michael before we
let you go As we always kind of
do when we when we kind of, you
know, tie off the end of the
show. How do you want to be
found can obviously be great if
you want to develop the URL for
the book again, how do people
find you on social media if you
want to be found, but I know you
have a fairly fairly active
social profile so go ahead,
Michael Van Horenbeeck: not as
active as I used to be just
because I'm writing the book. So
but you know, on Twitter I am
and then hybrid, I think that's
the easiest way to get a hold of
me because my last name, you
don't even try to pronounce it
in English. So advanta hybrid.
From there, you've got the URL,
you'll have the book title,
you'll see my blog post.
Obviously, I'm on LinkedIn as
well but has my full back name
and Vanderbeek. But through
Twitter, you'll easily find me
I've got my own blog at the vet
hybrid calm so you can get to
there or the book of website
m365securitybook.com as well,
but I'll share it with you so
that you can post it with the
recording as well.
Chris Goosen: Yeah, thank you. I
think we'll We'll definitely
make sure to put all of these in
the in the show notes for the
for the episode as well so that
we can kind of get that out
there. But thanks again for for
taking the time to speak to us.
This is super exciting sort of
announcement, I guess. And we're
really pleased that you came on
to talk to us about that. And I
know it's afternoon time for you
in Europe, but I'm sure you
still got a few things to get on
with for the day. So
Michael Van Horenbeeck: unfortunately,
yes. Like, you know, you've got
a whole day and so I'm halfway
my well actually done with my
day, two more hours a year I can
sign off. But yeah, anyway,
guys, I really appreciate you
having me on the call inviting
me and talk about the book.
Really appreciate that as well.
Chris Goosen: Hey, no problem.
Thank you. We're always happy to
have you. So thanks for coming
back.
Michael Van Horenbeeck: My
pleasure. Cheers.
Chris Goosen: Go. Okay, guys.
Bye!,
Warren du Toit: everyone. Before
you go, we just wanted to say
thank you for listening. We
really enjoyed putting this
podcast together for you every
two weeks, please visit us at
thearchitects.cloud.
Alternatively, drop us a tweet.
We'd love to hear what you have
to say @thecloudarch.