Chris Goosen: Welcome to the
cloud architects podcast, a
podcast about cloud technology
and the people using it.
Nicolas Blank: The cloud
architects podcast is sponsored
by Kemp Technologies. Choose
Kemp to optimize your multi
cloud application deployments
and simplify multi cloud
application management. A single
pane of glass for application
delivery, Kemp provides a 360
degree view of your entire
application environment, and
even third party ADCs. Download
Kemp360 for free today at
Kemptechnologies.com
Hello and welcome to another
episode of the cloud architects
podcast. I'm here today with my
co host Chris Goosen. Hello. And
we have a very special guest
today is going to talk about
something that's wonderfully
contentious. And I'm going to
ask Chris to introduce our guest
twice today.
Chris Goosen: Yeah, absolutely.
I'm excited about this topic
actually. And I'm super excited
about the person we speaking to.
So we are joined by Ashwin pal,
who is the director of cyber
security for the APAC region at
unisys. And Ashwin, I actually
go back really long time he was
the really the the reason I got
interested in cyber security in
the first place. And so super
excited to have you actually
welcome.
Ashwin Pal: Thank you, Chris.
Great to be on this and great to
reconnect man. It's it's been
it's been too long.
Chris Goosen: It has it's been,
it's been a really long time. I
think we could probably trace
back the last time we saw each
other at some pub somewhere in
the rocks. But we won't go into
that on this episode. So as a
means of introduction, do you
want to tell the folks listening
a little bit about yourself and
what it is you do?
Ashwin Pal: Yeah, definitely. So
obviously, actually, Paul, and I
run the cybersecurity business
for unisys across Asia back.
Been in Australia now for 13
years. But I'm a kiwi and been
doing this for 20 years now. So,
you know. Yeah, there isn't much
that I haven't touched around
the Sophos cybersecurity space.
Chris Goosen: Right. And, and
the the contentious subject that
I think Nick was referring to is
a zero trust. Right. I think we
hear that. We hear the phrase,
I'm soaking in zero trust a lot,
lately. Yeah. Right. And I think
maybe, probably the best place
to start is to probably unpack
exactly what that means. Because
I think what I've found is in
talking to folks in talking to
customers is there's a real
misconception around zero trust,
you know, some folks think it's
a product. Okay, can I get me
some of that zero trust? You
know, I think there's a real
misunderstanding in the sort of
in the industry as to what it
means and what it is who many
people have takes on it? So can
you help us kind of unpack a
little bit about you know, at
its core, what it is?
Ashwin Pal: Yeah, totally man.
And, you know, you are pressing
my buttons again, as as you used
to when you were a cleaner
Australia. So, unfortunately,
you talk to anyone, right now,
any other vendors, they've got
their own definition, right. And
zero trust came out of
Forrester. So I get along really
well with the APAC head of
security at Forrester. And, you
know, she, she's running a
server right now. And one of the
key points that if let's
actually come out from the
survey with silos, it's just a
frustration around the multiple
definitions of zero trust. So
zero trust, it's a philosophy,
it is not a tool, okay? It's
it's not a particular
technology, it's really a way of
actually implementing
cybersecurity in an
organization. It was actually
founded by john can divide. It's
for us to go in 2010. And,
really, the principle
effectively states never trust,
always verify. That's the key
thing thing. Now, what that
effectively means is that any
user or application, any device
that is actually coming into
your organization, any one of
those needs to be authenticated
properly, needs to be
authorized, you need to
implement very, very limited
role based access controls on a
need to know basis only. And
you're consistently
authenticating, authorizing
them. And at the same time,
you're using a myriad of other
technologies to make sure that
you are watching the behavior.
You're watching their security
posture, you're looking at other
contexts and other data sets,
things like threat intelligence
information, you know, through
things like security, log
monitoring, etc. To make sure if
anything actually goes bump, you
actually kick them off in order
grammatically that should
actually happen by itself. Now,
interestingly enough, about two
weeks ago now, this has actually
released its paper on zero trust
architecture. And they have
discussed a lot of these
concepts. Now one of the
concepts that actually they have
talked about in there is one of
control plane and data plane.
Right. So data plane is
basically so you segregate both
areas. data plane is actually
where the data travels control
planes effectively, we actually
implement access controls or
authorization controls. And
that's how you actually control
access to the underlying data.
And you're basically segregating
both of those. So when you talk
about zero trust, there are
multiple ways of implementing
it. The segregation that is that
I'm talking about, micro
segmentation is one of those
that I'm most familiar with, to
be honest. But at the end of the
day, so long as there is a
separation between the control
plane and the data plane, and
you are consistently authorizing
authenticating your users, your
applications, your devices,
establishing the trust,
maintaining that trust, through
constant posture, checking,
behavior, monitoring, and
encrypting the data on the wire,
that's quite important as well.
That's what zero trust will give
you. And as I say, you can hear
it in what I'm saying. It is not
a tool of technology, it is a
philosophy. And it really
depends on how you implement
that in your implement that in
your own environment.
Nicolas Blank: As well, Ashlyn,
I have to ask, I think it's
really easy for us who have been
around for a long time to hear
authentication and assume
identity, right? So you approach
my application or my service,
and we're going to constantly
ask you to verify who you are
through whatever methodology
that we have. However, what is
zero trust mean, when we get to
the the actual wire of data on
the wire? And how do we do zero
trust in a physical environment
like a layer two, layer three,
all the way up to layer seven,
where I'm talking zero trust
across clouds, zero trust
towards my data center? How do I
do that in a practical manner?
Without vendor locking?
Impossible?
Ashwin Pal: No, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, it is absolutely
possible. In fact, you should
abstract yourself from the
vendors. So what you should
actually be doing is coming up
with a strategy, which is, you
know, not technology focus. So
the key components that actually
just spoke about, you know, you
start off by thinking about what
those key components are, and
how you would actually address
those key components, the core
aspect here, and I like the fact
that you actually talked about
the OSI model, because I would
actually walk away from that and
actually talk about identity
itself. Identity is the new
permanent, okay, because what is
a network? Where is your? Any
answer? You can't, it doesn't
exist, you know, even with Cloud
is anybody using one cloud, no
people multi cloud. So if you
abstract yourself from the
network layer, or any technology
for that matter, and focus on
the core principles of zero
trust, which actually just
mentioned, at a strategic level,
and then drill down, try and
achieve those outcomes, that's
how you would actually achieve
zero trust. So if you took that
identity piece, right, and anti
role based access control, just
to those identities at an
abstract layer, it doesn't
matter where the identity goes,
whether it's in your network,
whether it's in your home, and
that's very, very relevant now.
Particularly with respect to
working from home remote access,
and all that stuff, or whether
it's actually in the cloud. And
again, that is very important
now, as well, because a big part
of this COVID working from home
shift, his people are working
from home now. And a lot of the
data is actually now in the
cloud, so you can access them
easily. Now, if you take the
concept of their identity, which
stays the same, doesn't matter
if it's on prem, whether it's in
the cloud, whether it's in your
home, you tie your access to
that identity, and then enforce
quite strict role based vennela
access controls. That's how you
establish that based on the
identity, and that's how you
restrict the access.
Nicolas Blank: Okay, so what I'm
hearing you say, is, forget
about the new trick. Just don't
trust it, and put something else
on top, which is completely not
network related in any
semblance. And what we're going
to pivot off on everything is
identity.
Ashwin Pal: Hundred percent,
because at the end of the day,
how far does your network
extend? Can you extend it into
Azure Cloud getting extended
into Google's cloud? Can you
extend it into AWS? You can't
Can you extend it into people's
homes? Not really, right? I
mean, we've got a situation now
where there are multiple users
coming in from their home using
the BYOD machines because not
everybody had a laptop. So when
they actually went home, that
could not procure laptops. I
know for a fact Dell, Lenovo,
all of these guys literally ran
out of laptops, you couldn't buy
one. Okay? The option was, okay,
cool. We'll set your home laptop
up to actually come in. So now
all of a sudden, you're using
BYOD machines coming in over an
insecure wireless connection
straight into your network.
Yeah, you trust that connection?
Are you going to trust that
endpoint? You see what you see
where I'm going with this
Nicolas Blank: is a
Ashwin Pal: challenge that you
are trying to address. And
frankly, zero trust is the
answer. I love, you know, making
predictions and just being
controversial with neuro
cruces Easter, which is always
loving.
One of the things that I've
actually been saying is,
you know, zero trust, frankly,
last year was a pie in the sky
concept. With the whole COVID
thing, it's basically giving it
a shot in the arm. I can't I
guarantee you, within three
years, a lot of organizations
would either be working towards
zero trust, or would seriously
have it on the roadmap, zero
trusted if you're not easy to
put into place. Because there
are a number of challenges with
regards to compatibility with
legacy environments, change
resistance, except, you know,
time and cost all of that stuff.
So you'll need to eat the
elephant. Hopefully, there
aren't any alpha blockers on
this call. In bite sized chunks,
right. And that's, that's what
you've got to do. But at the end
of the day, people simply have
no choice now with the work from
home stuff with the move to
cloud. And trust me, not
everybody's honey, anyone's
going to come back into the
office full time anymore. The
whole working from home stuff is
here to stay. So you've got to
have, you've got to have a
response to that business
challenge. And zero trust gives
you a pretty solid answer.
Chris Goosen: So so. So what I
what I like about what you've
said is because for the longest
time, I've been preaching that
the identity is the foundational
component of any move to the
cloud, right? Whenever we talk
to customers, I spoke to add a
late customer call yesterday,
where they tend to get so
fixated on the fact that they
need to move data from on prem
to, you know, on premises
servers into a cloud
environment, or they need to
enable this feature in in teams.
And then you take the wind out
of the sails when you say, well,
hang on, have you thought about
your identity? Oh, well, what do
you mean? Well, people need to
be able to log into stuff. And
that really is like, if it's
like building the house, right?
You can't do it. Without doing
that foundational step. I kind
of experienced the same thing,
because during COVID, I was
trying to get a new laptop
myself. And I ended up having to
use a use a Windows machine for
a little while because my Mac
was an order, and it just took
forever for me to get it. Right.
And it's the same situation like
vendors everywhere we're having
having issues with this. And
unfortunately, you know, I was
able to continue working with
without problem but you know,
you're right. I think this this
new norm, this new shift, this
is interesting. So I what I
wanted to pick on, or at least
what I wanted to ask, I had a
couple of questions. Now the
first one's gonna be a little
bit more controversial, right?
You're up for? I've heard a lot
of talk about something that
Google calls beyond cope. Yeah.
And and and it comes up a lot in
these kind of zero trust type
conversations is just is this
just Google's branding on some
of the same concept, though, is
this something that they're
trying to turn into? Okay,
Ashwin Pal: so that's in TNA.
Here we go. Now I'm going to
start throwing four three letter
acronyms at you. That's zero
trust, zero trust network
access, it is a it's a piece of
the puzzle. It is absolutely not
completely zero trust on its
own. Right. So effectively, what
beyond Corp does, and you've got
z scalar, that have got a
similar technology as well. And,
you know, effectively allow
secure remote access to certain
applications. And the access is
tightly controlled, and the
applications are not exposed
until such time that you
actually need access to it.
That's effectively it in
summary, right. So that's what
beyond Corp is, as I said
earlier, if you go back to my
initial definition, zero trust
needs to be holistic, it needs
to cover any device anywhere,
any access methodology anytime,
right? So zip DNA is a piece of
the pie. It is not the entire
pie. Okay. Very interesting. And
the other, obviously, just add
to that, Chris. The other thing
you've got to be very careful
about is vendor locking.
Alright, so we spoke about that
earlier. And there was actually
one of the questions, what
you've got to think about is
that if you go with a particular
vendor, in this case, Google,
you know, what are your
limitations? What can you do
with them what you cannot do
without them? And is it going to
lock you in and actually prevent
you from, you know, implementing
the access from, you know, a
place where there might not
actually exist or something like
that. So, again, you've got to
be very careful about vendor
lock in. And as I say, don't
start with a technology. Start
with what you want to achieve
your and then go from there.
That's key.
Chris Goosen: Yeah, definitely.
Sounds like it's so the second
sort of, I guess, tack on
question to that. We're talking
about the identity. It's the key
part of that. And you're you're
essentially wanting to
authenticate based on all of the
data points that you have,
right. And so when we, when we
look at something like
conditional access, I mean, is
it okay, just, you know, a
common a common situation, when
you when you use conditional
access is to say, Well, if we
can identify that we have a
known device, and we know the
user user credentials, we trust
the user credentials, that we
can be a little bit more relaxed
around how we, you know, sort of
know two factor, for example,
right? And maybe we allow that
person because it's a trusted
identity, it's a trusted device,
we can allow them access to some
really sensitive data. Whereas
that same user identity coming
from grandma's device, or, you
know, a McDonald's network that
we've never seen, maybe we want
to do a few more things, right.
So would you say that something
like conditional access kind of
plays into this? Or is a key
kind of building block for it?
Ashwin Pal: Now, you've
absolutely hit the nail on the
head there, right? So one of the
key issues around implementing
zero trust is change resistance.
Because, you know, let me take
it a step back as humans, as
organizations, we've always
worked on the principle of
trust, right? For example, I'm
sure you guys have all heard,
why would you hire someone if
you don't actually trust them?
Right, their trust is
effectively going completely
against that. Now, just to be
clear, we're not saying that we
don't trust our employees, what
we're actually saying is that
depending on their risk profile,
and it is related to everything
you just said, you know, we want
to be able to make sure that we
can verify before we can
actually trust, it actually
makes sense. It's a bit like,
you know, someone's actually
knocking on your front door.
They've got a helmet on. Yeah.
What do you mean, do open the
front door? Because at the
moment, the way network access
actually works is that you know,
you come in and Chris, you know,
this, you know, you either get a
wired or wireless connection
onto your network. By the time
the login prompt comes up,
you're already on the network,
correct? Yeah. What you've just
done is you've actually let this
person with a helmet on into the
house, you've opened the front
door, they walked into the
house, and then you go, Oh, are
you? Okay? Right, what we're
saying is basically keep the
door shot, make sure this person
pulls the helmet off. And if you
know him, let him in it, don't
keep them out there goes back to
what you just said, right? It's
all risk based. So if the person
has an issue wearing a helmet,
you can see their face happy
days, the risk is lower, you
will actually have lower
controls in place. And you'll
let them in because you've got
to be very, very careful and
Cognizant, off, balancing user
experience with enhanced
security. And that's always the
friction when it comes to cyber
security. And that's where risk
based decision is very, very
important. And then if the IRS,
you put further controls in
place, and then once they're
actually in a key aspect of this
is user and entity behavior
analysis. So you know,
constantly monitoring, you know,
what this user is doing, what
this device is doing, and
whether it actually matches what
you would actually expect. And
if it doesn't, then hopefully
you've got an automatic control
to either kill their access or
limit their access, because that
could potentially mean that
something's changed. You know,
we've got a man in the middle
attack or something like that,
that has actually happened,
obviously, with men in the
middle is, you know, it's a case
of a valid user session has just
been hijacked by somebody who is
nefarious. So you know, it is
risk based. But having said
that, you still need to make
sure you actually have controls
in place that you can constantly
monitor and control that very
session until the end.
Nicolas Blank: I want to just
ask them continuous question
asked another contentious
question. And we spoke about
identity, which is wonderful,
and I'm completely on that
bandwagon. But then, both of you
very quickly, Chris, you started
off talking about Microsoft
Azure Active Directory,
conditional access and Ashwin,
you didn't bat an eyelid we just
go with the flow. There is only
one identity provider and for
four years for decades, in fact,
on premises, it made sense that
we would use Microsoft Active
Directory. And our users are
spoiled because we obfuscate
authorization and
authentication, one package and
particularly with Kerberos. Life
has just, you know, it's great
and it works. And but then we go
to cloud, right? When whose
identity model are we talking
about? We're still talking about
Microsoft identity. And so, let
me ask you, Ashwin, I want to
ask you a question that a
customer of mine asked me, he
said, I am concerned about
vendor locking. Okay. But what
have you literally for 20 years
been running in your data
centers as well, Microsoft
Active Directory, but now, now
that I'm going to cloud, I'm
concerned, because people have
told me about this thing called
vendor locking. Yeah. And how do
I not get locked into Microsoft
Azure Active Directory. However,
the other side of the coin is, I
don't see anyone else doing
conditional access, and doing
what Microsoft is doing, that
can at least from the outside,
in, do that thing of Who are you
and where you from? At the same
time before I'm going to let you
access my service? Right? So
Ashwin Pal: how do we answer
that question to the market?
Absolutely. And and so color
responses to that one?
Obviously, you recall, I talked
about control plane and data
plane, right, which is why we
started off and discussed the
concept of the control plane,
the control plane effectively
abstracts all the technologies,
right. So I have a control
plane, which actually enforces
authentication authorization, I
don't really care where the
identity store is where it's
coming from. And that's
literally, you know, what, what
we've actually what we've
actually done. So, you know, on
prem use ad, as an example, I
don't care in the cloud, where
you've got workloads, which
actually running and don't have
connection to your ad,
internally, stand up a simple
PKR infrastructure, basically
use certificate based
authentication and that privacy
identities for those workloads.
So as I said, you know, you've
got to be, whenever you start
with this, you've got to start
with the concepts, the building
blocks, and make sure you're
actually addressing the building
blocks, as opposed to coming in
from a technology angle. And
it's a very valid point, because
yes, you're right, Chris
actually did go down the
technology path. But you would
have noticed I keep pulling you
guys back away from technology.
This is not a technology
conversation. This is a concept
of philosophy called
conversation, whereby you'll
actually have building blocks
from multiple providers that you
would then pull together based
on the various components of
zero trust into a into a
cohesive architecture that is
then void. So makes sense. And
the example I've just given to
you mixes up your own Pico
infrastructure, which you would
have set up in the cloud as an
example. And on prem, I don't
care.
Nicolas Blank: I'm sure you guys
would have had the same
discussions with customers when
we asked them. So let's have the
security discussion. They say,
oh, mate, I'm secure because I
have been to whoever that is,
right? And you think But hang
on, that's a vendor, that's not
a framework. That's not a
strategy. A. And when I used to
work for a migration vendor, it
was also management vendor, I
used to talk to my customers and
say that software is not a
process. software enables a
process. And if you were talking
to a customer who's in cloud,
wants to go to cloud, because to
be fair, we still have customers
who are in cloud and immature,
right. And that's not from a
security posture that's not from
a mental point of view, or
customers who are still
evaluating about going to cloud
for the very first time. What
would you say to those folks?
Ashwin Pal: So I mean, in terms
of migrating to the cloud,
you've got to you've got to get
the basics, right first, right,
like and again, what is your
security posture? What is your
risk posture? You know, do you
have policies around your
minimum cybersecurity standards?
It's those things that come into
play. I mean, if you look at any
one of the cloud providers, they
provide security in the cloud,
some of it is pretty good. So
often, it's pretty average. But
at the end of the day, it's a
bit like going to a restaurant
and somebody gives you a menu,
right? You've got all these
things that you actually can put
in place or eat in this case,
it's up to you. It's like, what
do you want to eat and how
hungry you are? It's exactly the
same concept. It's actually not
about you can't and you
shouldn't start with With a
technology conversation, it's
going to be about your
requirements, etc, etc. And then
if you are specifically looking
at zero trust, zero trust is one
of those beautiful things, which
allows you to push your
security, you know, based on
what you've talked about, into
the cloud, that you can control
and is actually equivalent to on
prem security. It abstracts you
from the security that is
provided by the cloud provider.
I'm not saying you don't use it.
In fact, you should. But you
know, the concept of security
about multiple layers, right? So
if there is an issue with the
cloud provider, there was an
issue with Amazon's cloud
director, not long ago, right?
There was a vulnerability found
now if you actually have the top
issue. But if you actually have
a zero trust philosophy in
place, whereby you are
controlling some of the security
yourself, and you have allowed
minimum security based on strict
authentication, then you have a
degree of protection. So those
are the things you actually have
to think about. But it does come
down to, you know, what are your
minimum standards around
security? what is acceptable
from a risk perspective?
Chris Goosen: I think, I think
it's a very important point,
because I always pick on Nick,
because he has this phrase that
he uses a lot called
requirements. elicitation,
right, because you don't just
gather requirements up like
they're, you know, puppies. And,
and so I think that's important,
because I've had a lot of
conversations with customers,
specifically security
conversations, where they go,
Well, we need to secure this
thing. And you're like, Okay,
well, what is your risk profile?
What what are the what's
important to you, from a
security perspective? What are
your requirements? And they go,
Well, I don't know the product.
So I don't know what it can do.
I was like, Yeah, but that's,
that's not the question I asked.
Right. The question is, what are
your requirements? Because we
will tailor the product to do
you know, the platform to do
what? What? meet those
requirements. And so you get
into this sort of chicken and
egg situation where someone
standing there with their arms
crossed, going, Well, I need to
understand what the what
features it has and what it can
do. Well, that's not really the
discussion we're having. Yeah,
you need. Yeah, you know, we
need to talk about what and I
think the other part of this is
the concept of, you know, folks
tend to sometimes overthink this
as well, right? They go into
this sort of analysis paralysis,
where they want to end up
spending significantly more to
protect something than it's
worth, right. And that in itself
is a good idea, either. So it's
very important to understand,
like, if you if you have things
that are not that critical, or
our budget public, you know,
publicly categorize documents,
for example, right? Does it make
sense for you to go down this
like, super deep path of putting
all of these crazy security
controls in place? When if that
thing isn't all that important
to begin with? So understanding
that risk profile and
understanding your requirements
very, very important to this
whole discussion? That was my
long, roundabout way of getting
to that point.
Ashwin Pal: I completely agree.
Because that's really where the
conversation actually needs to
start. If you're starting a
security conversation with
technology, straightaway, the
red flag goes up for me, because
yeah, you're gonna end up in a
very wrong place.
Chris Goosen: Yeah, you're
almost ticking feature boxes at
that point, right, trying to
make Features Fit and go, Oh,
well, we bought this license.
Let's make sure we're using
every single one of those
checkboxes on the feature list.
Yeah,
Nicolas Blank: yeah. Yeah. And I
use the word elicitation.
Because, well, for one thing was
taught to me by a business
analyst who was fantastically
mature in this whole discussion.
And how he illustrated it to me
was just like Chris says, this
requirements online in the
ground, fast to pick up because,
you know, otherwise, it would be
easy. And I roll when we engage
with customers. And to me, our
customers is anyone who has this
kind of conversation and could
be an internal or an external
role. And for us as an external
role, we would go and wrestle
with our customers. And it's
kind of like standing with our
feet on the shoulders with a
pair of pliers trying to pull
these requirements out of their
mouth, because it's not an easy
discussion. It's a case of,
let's stop talking about this
feature. Let's go back to what
is our need, what is what are we
trying to defend? And very
often, when we talk to senior
folks in the business,
especially the C suite folks
who've been marketed to by
vendors, they will say, and I'll
take the conversation back 20
years, I want a Blackberry.
Well, why do you want a
blackberry? Well, it's cuz I
went down to the pub was living
in London at the stage. So I
went down to the pub, and Mata,
my friend who's a director works
for this other company showed me
his Blackberry, it's cool. Now
whatever is at the back end, can
you make that work? But that's
not a requirement. So if if we
didn't walk them forward to do
you need mobile collaboration?
Oh, yeah. Well, do you need
secure mobile collaboration, and
then we take them down that path
of let's articulate what it is
that we need that in your head
is aligned to a feature. But you
saw that feature, and you
thought, I need that. Because
that makes sense. But let's turn
it back into something that we
can then defend, from a
requirements point of view.
Yeah,
Ashwin Pal: yeah, absolutely.
And, and that's the critical
part, like every conversation
needs to start around, you know,
what is your risk appetite?
Where are you in relation to
your risk appetite? So what is
the current risk posture? And,
you know, how, if there's a gap,
then how do we actually get
there, and you know, you look at
the building blocks. Now,
obviously, a key part of that is
you need to understand where
your information assets are, and
how critical there because
that's what's going to drive the
security controls. But you've
also got to throw into the mix,
how the threat landscape is
actually changing. So for
instance, if you look at what I
just said, the massive the move
with working from home,
effectively changed the threat
landscape, you know, for the
worse, the whole environment
became a lot less controllable,
because people were in their
homes, BYOD machines, insecure
wireless, what I spoke about
earlier, then you've got to take
a step back and think about
Alright, so how do I actually
secure this? Like, what? What
access is required? What's the
criticality of the data being
accessed? Where is this data?
And you know, is zero trust a
good way to go? Those are the
questions you would actually ask
before even going down the zero
trust path. Going back to what
Chris actually said, and I know
this is an absurd example. But
just go with it. You know, if
you've actually got users that
are constantly coming in,
looking at publicly available
information and doing stuff with
it, they're who, you know, the
controls that you need to put in
place is going to be much less
However, if they're coming in.
And if they're actually playing
around with the formula for Coca
Cola. Yeah, you might want to
think about zero trust in that
case.
Chris Goosen: Yeah. That makes
sense. So, um, last question, I
guess, for me that I have is
resources, right? Let's say
someone's listening to this,
they're going, Okay, I
understand that zero trust is a
methodology or a, you know, a
mindset as opposed to a product
that I can go buy off the shelf,
right, no matter what vendors
are telling you, it is not a
product. But I want to learn
more, I want to I want to
understand how I can implement
this in my environment or for my
organization, or there's some,
like other good resources
available for folks to go and
skill up, or at least, you know,
get better acquainted with this.
And something that isn't
completely kind of marketing
skewed.
Ashwin Pal: I was gonna say, I
could give up my email address,
but I won't
Unknown: expect Dilbert.
Ashwin Pal: Jokes aside, two
things come to mind one. And
thank God, NIST actually has
written the zero trust
architecture paper, I would, I'm
in this to convert. And I go go
to NIST for all of my
references. First off, that's
probably the one that actually
referenced most, because it's
obviously vendor agnostic,
right. And, frankly, I've
written a white paper on this,
and you won't believe it. I
literally wrote it over
Christmas, because I was getting
so frustrated with seeing all
the different zero trust
definitions coming up, I will
start I'm going to write my own
paper and define this once and
for all
Chris Goosen: the different time
to rule definitions. How am I
going? How can I do know about
this? In all of my research for
this episode, I didn't even know
about this. So is that something
we can share in the shownotes?
It's publicly available paper?
Ashwin Pal: Yeah, hundred
percent. Man, I'll, I'll flick
it to you. After this and feel
free, feel free to distribute it
with this, go for your life. So
it'll cover a lot of the
concepts that I've actually
spoken about. And, you know,
these days, like I've discussed,
not just your trust, but what
are some of the challenges,
organizational challenges as
well as the suggested approach.
So, you know, zero trust is it's
hard to shoehorn or fit into a
legacy environment, but a lot of
people are going through digital
transformation. A lot of people
are actually going through cloud
migrations, as we discussed
earlier. Those are great places
to start, because they're
Greenfield opportunities and
projects. The thing is, you've
got to make sure that you're
building security and zero trust
is part of the entire process as
opposed to towards the end and
somebody goes, Oh, what about
security? Okay.
Yeah, yeah, that one before
Henry
Chris Goosen: I use that example
on a daily basis pretty much
because I've just discovered so
often
Ashwin Pal: start, and then it's
a nightmare in a disaster,
right? So you've got to make
sure you're actually putting
security in from the start. I
mean, this is applicable to
security as far as zero trust as
much as it is to broader
security. When you're actually
thinking off a project, oh, my
God, I don't understand why you
actually wouldn't have security
as a key requirement. So when
you're doing that requirement,
initial phase right up front,
before you're even going to like
project funding business
guessing stage, it should be in
there, you should be putting up
security against your
requirements. And then going
ahead with the project, yeah.
Mine to stick to your I trusted,
and effectively, it's almost a
case of land and expand, okay,
you land here a trust into your
your plan, migrations, your
digital transformation projects.
And then as your legacy
environments are getting
refreshed, you expand, you
expand, you expand, right, it's
a multi year, multi phase
journey. But you've got to start
somewhere. And as I said, a lot
of this discussed in my short,
sharp paper, which which I'll
share after the call, and feel
free to share that with the
audience.
Nicolas Blank: Yeah, absolutely.
I just Chris, before we end
this, this, just something I
want to draw an analogy to and
Ashwin, I'd like for you to, to
agree or to correct. So if I'm
putting my my Microsoft hat back
on, one of the things that I
gain from docs.microsoft.com is
the cloud adoption framework for
Azure. And one of the things I
enjoy about that is that it
actually is vendor agnostic. So
for all of those Microsoft
bashes out there, there's this
free framework called the cloud
adoption framework for Azure.
And it addresses multi cloud.
And one of the things that you
get from that is the concept of
building a minimally viable
product from day one. And after
we finish the envisioning phase
of we go to the business and
say, What are you willing to
spend money on? Right? So what
is this thing that cloud is
going to do for us in a
measurable way, we actually
start with a governance
framework. And governance starts
on day one with an MVP. Now I've
taken that methodology, and I've
applied it to our productivity
customers. So those folks going
to Office 365. And after we do
this envisioning thing of the
cloud, we get the folks in the
room. And then I look the
governance person, the eye and
say, you've just become the most
important person in the room.
Because without you, we can't
move a single bite to the cloud
without being compliant to
whatever is important in your
life. And this concept of going
to cloud in a secure manner,
including zero trust doesn't
have to be the thing that says,
Oh, it's going to take me 10
years to become secure, it means
I'm going to start somewhere.
And then I'm going to be
iteratively more mature, as I
take my minimally viable
product, and iterate through
that as I become more mature in
my security posture, and become
more mature in zero trust, so
that I build something that I as
an organization can sustain.
Ashwin Pal: Yep. Well said, and
I'm sure you guys know,
Microsoft's my Microsoft is an
absolute zero trust convert.
Yeah, they taught So actually,
they're on a multi year, zero
trust, migration journey.
Period, right? And then betting
in the cloud environment, just
just talking about Microsoft
itself. So yeah, they're
absolutely sold on the concept.
100%
Chris Goosen: and if you're
listening to this, and you want
to know, one thing you can do to
start today, turn on multi
factor auth. Yes, that's right.
That's where you start.
Unknown: Yeah, so I'll get off
Chris Goosen: my soapbox now.
ashran it's been it's been an
absolute pleasure catching up
again and having you having you
talk to us about this. If folks
on the call want to reach out to
you and and sort of get in touch
and talk about zero trust or
anything else security related,
how can they How can they find
you?
Ashwin Pal: easiest thing to do
is just drop me drop me a line.
And my email address is
ashwin.pal@unisys.com.
Chris Goosen: Okay. And on the
socials, you're on LinkedIn.
Right I'll while on LinkedIn, so
you can feel free to message me
on LinkedIn as well. Okay,
excellent. I'll put we don't
typically publish email
addresses but I'll publish a
link to your LinkedIn profile.
Just keep the spam out of your
inbox. You know, do Mike do
yeah. Yeah. Well, look, thank
you very much. And yeah, we'll
look forward to possibly having
you back again sometime in
future.
Ashwin Pal: Yeah, man. No
worries. Any any any topic I'll
give an opinion is you know.
Nicolas Blank: Awesome. Thank
you Ashwin. Thanks. Eyes.
Warren du Toit: Everyone. Before
you go, we just wanted to say
thank you for listening. We
really enjoyed putting this
podcast together for you every
two weeks, please visit us at
the architects cloud.
Alternatively, drop us a tweet.
We'd love to hear what you have
to say at the cloud Ark.